<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Becky Chambers on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/authors/becky-chambers/</link><description>Recent content in Becky Chambers on Strat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 02:30:40 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/authors/becky-chambers/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>To Be Taught, If Fortunate</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-22/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-22/</guid><description>Humm&amp;hellip;
It was OK.
Unlike The Galaxy and The Ground Within (also written by Becky Chambers), this novella doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of space (see what I did there?) to develop its characters and have you care about them.
There&amp;rsquo;s a little bit of tension as the crew navigates to each planet they&amp;rsquo;ve been tasked with scouring for life. Will they be ok? What will they find? Etc.
But it was hard for me to care.</description></item><item><title>The Galaxy, and the Ground Within</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-21/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-21/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Galaxy, and the Ground Within is a science fiction novel about a diverse cast of characters from all over the galaxy, stuck at an inter-planetary truck stop for an indeterminate span of time, getting to know one another and helping each other overcome (or make peace with) problems in their personal lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the characters learned about each other and gradually opened up about themselves, I started to see parts of myself reflected in them making me feel invested in the mostly low stakes interactions occurring between the characters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve seen complaints about the book not having a plot that propulses the characters forward. Although that&amp;rsquo;s mostly true, I don&amp;rsquo;t think this book needs one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a story about people, it focuses on them and their evolving relationships with one another, finding common ground despite their differences. That&amp;rsquo;s more than enough to keep someone enraptured for however long it takes them to read the book (I know I was).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a story about a ragtag group of underdogs overcoming stacked odds to save the universe, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to look elsewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for something a little bit out there, and are ok with reading something with less action, less sex (although there is some of that) and fewer universe ending apocalypses than you&amp;rsquo;re used to, then I can highly recommend this book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here be spoilers, you&amp;rsquo;ve been warned:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>