<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Strat&#39;s Projects on Strategineer</title>
    <link>http://strategineer.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Strat&#39;s Projects on Strategineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://strategineer.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lynchman</title>
      <link>http://strategineer.com/projects/2019-04-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://strategineer.com/projects/2019-04-15/</guid>
      <description>Lynchman was developed with python. It can be used to compute data based on Beat Saber (a Virtual Reality rhythm game where you&amp;rsquo;re tasked with using your arms to slice fast moving blocks in time with music) maps and using that data to generate maps automatically (using Markov Chains) for given song files.
NB: The name of the project is based on the character Lynchman from one of the best animated movies of all time, Redline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Framestore VR</title>
      <link>http://strategineer.com/projects/2019-02-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://strategineer.com/projects/2019-02-03/</guid>
      <description>Developed an Unreal Engine 4 Plugin (C++) for importing and iterating on art assets from Shotgun and Perforce into Unreal Engine projects with one click. Developed a data-driven system for automating the generation of new projects in Perforce and Jenkins based on a project-specific specification of Perforce hierarchies of depots, streams and source branching strategies. Developed a Python command line tool which acted as the glue connecting Perforce, Shotgun and Unreal Engine which was used primarily for detecting changed art assets, generating turntables automatically and uploading them to Shotgun for stakeholders to review if needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artifact Stat Tracker</title>
      <link>http://strategineer.com/projects/2018-12-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://strategineer.com/projects/2018-12-01/</guid>
      <description>Artifact Stat Tracker was developed using python and Google Sheets.
As I played the game, I entered data into the Google Sheets document using custom built UIs, the python script would then read the data within the Google Sheets document, manipulate it and inject it, with more contextual information, back into the Google Sheets document.
The Google Sheets document would then use the given data produce tables and charts with interesting insights to help improve my play on a competitive level such as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Head</title>
      <link>http://strategineer.com/projects/2018-06-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://strategineer.com/projects/2018-06-05/</guid>
      <description>Machine Head was developed using python and an instance of it is constantly running on a Raspberry Pi at my house. It was built for automating various manual processes tied to managing my Discord server that I was tired of doing over and over again.
I dove into Linux head first to optimize my programming workflow which, on this project, consisted of working in my development environment (a Windows PC using the Linux Subsystem for Windows with Ubuntu), testing the changes in this environment on a sandbox server on Discord, pushing the changes into the production environment (my Raspberry Pi).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pew Pew</title>
      <link>http://strategineer.com/projects/2017-08-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://strategineer.com/projects/2017-08-01/</guid>
      <description>Pew Pew was developed using pico8 (which is a fantasy console with substantial constraints tied to memory, graphics, sounds, etc.) while I was working at Borealys Games. I was inspired to work on this project by Dominique Morin who was truly a pleasure to work with and impressed me greatly with his portfolio of games he designed and built on his own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mages of Mystralia</title>
      <link>http://strategineer.com/projects/2017-05-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://strategineer.com/projects/2017-05-18/</guid>
      <description>I worked at Borealys Games, an independent video game studio, from May 2016 until November 2017. I mostly worked on Mages of Mystralia but I also worked on other unannounced/cancelled projects.
We were two/three programmers working on Mages of Mystralia (Anthony Demange as lead programmer and Vincent Bilodeau as graphics programmer).
On Mages of Mystralia, I touched almost everything given the small size of the team but I focused specifically on these parts of the game:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Out</title>
      <link>http://strategineer.com/projects/2016-05-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://strategineer.com/projects/2016-05-10/</guid>
      <description>Get Out was developed using Unreal Engine 4 for my team&amp;rsquo;s final project in the DDJV program at the University of Sherbrooke (Campus Longueuil).
We were a team of six programmers including Thomas Dobranowski (AI), Christian Nioré, Alexis Plet (Gameplay), Charles Santourian (UI), Frank Kongue Wankam (AI) and myself.
I pitched the initial idea which was based a video game prototype I had designed, playtested and built in the summer of 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Turtle Adventure IV</title>
      <link>http://strategineer.com/projects/2015-12-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://strategineer.com/projects/2015-12-16/</guid>
      <description>Great Turtle Adventure IV was developed using a custom game engine I designed and built (with DirectX 10 and PhysX) inspired by the game engine built by Gaspard Petit and the DirectX 10 knowledge provided by François Jean during my first semester in the DDJV program at the University of Sherbrooke (Campus Longueuil).
The project was completed mostly by myself with the help of Mathieu Langlois and Dominique Lacombe who helped me close the project in the last couple of days before the deadline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Box Bandit</title>
      <link>http://strategineer.com/projects/2014-08-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://strategineer.com/projects/2014-08-25/</guid>
      <description>Black Box Bandit was developed using Unity in 48h during Ludum Dare 30 (theme: Connected Worlds).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invasion Logistics Pro</title>
      <link>http://strategineer.com/projects/2014-04-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://strategineer.com/projects/2014-04-28/</guid>
      <description>Billguk the Invasion Logistics Professional was developed using Unity in 48h during Ludum Dare 29 (theme: Beneath the Surface).
Today, our Guk leaders have decided to lead their fellow Guks into battle against the hated Surfacers. Billguk, I&amp;rsquo;m calling upon you now to perform the duty you&amp;rsquo;ve trained for your entire life. I ask you to show your fellow Guks that the Invasion Logistics Professional diploma on your bedroom wall actually means something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Battleships</title>
      <link>http://strategineer.com/projects/2014-04-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://strategineer.com/projects/2014-04-10/</guid>
      <description>Battleships was developed using C++ and SDL in a team of three programmers composed of Benjamin Lewis, Franz-Philippe Garcia and myself in my second year at McGill University within the context of the Software Engineering course led by Jörg Kienzle.
I worked specifically on the game client, the graphics code and the art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graveyard Rush</title>
      <link>http://strategineer.com/projects/2014-04-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://strategineer.com/projects/2014-04-02/</guid>
      <description>I developed Graveyard Rush DURING my last exams of my fourth semester at McGill University right before my second internship at CAE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mega Super Epic Tankz</title>
      <link>http://strategineer.com/projects/2013-04-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://strategineer.com/projects/2013-04-24/</guid>
      <description>I developed Mega Super Epic Tankz after my last exams of my second semester at McGill University right before my first internship at CAE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writerator</title>
      <link>http://strategineer.com/projects/2013-02-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://strategineer.com/projects/2013-02-01/</guid>
      <description>A wise computer once told me, &amp;ldquo;Peremptory personal, Perpendiculars, Forestry spreadsheets zaniest.&amp;rdquo;
If you enjoy writing and/or programming then you should give Writerator a shot!
Oh&amp;hellip; You&amp;rsquo;re still here. OK.
Well, Writerator gives the curious user access to many tools to find specific information about their texts such as the number of times &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo; appears or the words in a text sorted by how many times &amp;ldquo;e&amp;rdquo; appears in them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>InfiniCube</title>
      <link>http://strategineer.com/projects/2012-12-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://strategineer.com/projects/2012-12-20/</guid>
      <description>InfiniCube is the first &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; video game that I developed. I made it during the winter break of my first semester of the Honours Software Engineering program at McGill University.
It features two campaigns with themed levels based on bad puns and an infinite mode with levels being created in a human readable data format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DnD Sidekick</title>
      <link>http://strategineer.com/projects/2011-12-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://strategineer.com/projects/2011-12-02/</guid>
      <description>I developed DnD Sidekick the end of 2012.
It was a personal milestone because it was the first fleshed out application that I built from the ground up, it was used extensively by other people and I was paid for my work.
DnD Sidekick &amp;hellip;
– Simplifies the process of character creation for the player. – Allows players to roll any number and any combination of dice. – Contains Spell and Feat dictionaries for quick searches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNA Toolkit</title>
      <link>http://strategineer.com/projects/2011-12-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://strategineer.com/projects/2011-12-01/</guid>
      <description>I developed DNA Toolkit at the end of 2011.
See my DnD Sidekick page for more information.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
