<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>non-fiction on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/tags/non-fiction/</link><description>Recent content in non-fiction on Strat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/books/tags/non-fiction/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On Being Awesome: A Unified Theory of How Not to Suck</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 07:19:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-19/</guid><description>Nick Riggle&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;On Being Awesome: A Unified Theory of How Not to Suck&amp;rdquo; is a philosophy book that discusses awesomeness and suckiness in detail. It defines language to accurately describe and reason about the awesomeness and suckiness that you perceive in yourself and in others.
According to Mr. Riggle, awesomeness and suckiness revolves all around social openings which are moments when we can choose to break out of our norm-governed roles by expressing ourselves.</description></item><item><title>The Greek Myths: The Complete and Definitive Edition</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-12-01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 07:36:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-12-01/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always been fascinated by Greek mythology but my understanding of it came from the sanitized stories I read in D&amp;rsquo;Aulaires Book Of Greek Myths and secondhand from the many modern interpretations of the myths I had seen throughout my life.
Prior to reading this book, I had never really taken the time to dive deep into Greek mythology.
I&amp;rsquo;m glad I did because now I cringe thinking about all the times I said that I prefer Greek mythology to Christianity because it&amp;rsquo;s: &amp;ldquo;way funner&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>The Joy of Mixology, Revised and Updated Edition: The Consummate Guide to the Bartender’s Craft</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-11-15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 07:39:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-11-15/</guid><description>Cocktails, Cocktails, Cocktails, Cocktails, Cocktails&amp;hellip; Cocktails, Everybody!
My buddy who&amp;rsquo;s a bartender recommended this to me when I expressed interest in learning how to mix cocktails. It&amp;rsquo;s got a bunch of good cocktail recipes and historical context for most of them (if you&amp;rsquo;re into that kind of thing).
Interestingly, in the first few pages, Gary describes bartenders as being &amp;ldquo;Ganymedes&amp;rdquo;, a young boy (remember this) who is the immortal cupbearer of Olympus in Greek mythology.</description></item><item><title>On Writing: A Memoir of the Craft</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-11-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 07:35:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-11-01/</guid><description>On Writing by Stephen King is half part autobiography and half part a guide to writing. You probably know Stephen King&amp;rsquo;s work and you&amp;rsquo;ve probably seen one of the thousands of movie adaptations of his books like It, Carrie or Shawshank Redemption). He is extremely prolific and he&amp;rsquo;s one of my favorite writers so when I heard that he wrote this book on writing, I picked it up right away.</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-10-01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 07:33:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-10-01/</guid><description>Infrastructure: A Field Guide to the Industrial Landscape is exactly what you think it is and it&amp;rsquo;s amazing. It&amp;rsquo;s a book that covers anything that you could consider to be &amp;ldquo;Infrastructure&amp;rdquo; (water treatment, electricity, farming, cargo ships, airplanes, mining, etc.) and gives you a broad yet deep understanding of how it all works through clear writing and beautiful photos taken by the author himself.
After reading Infrastructure, I now have a better understanding of all the infrastructure that surrounds me and this knowledge prevents me from taking anything for granted.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Power</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-09-01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 07:32:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-09-01/</guid><description>Understanding Power is the book that convinced me that I needed to start reading again. It&amp;rsquo;s just a bunch of transcripts taken from Noam Chomsky Q/A sessions, but man, I&amp;rsquo;m glad that I was convinced to sit down and read through it.
Noam Chomsky has eidetic memory (more commonly known as photographic memory) and so you can ask him about anything and he&amp;rsquo;ll be able to perfectly recall everything he&amp;rsquo;s read and written about the subject.</description></item></channel></rss>