<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Non-Fiction on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/tags/non-fiction/</link><description>Recent content in Non-Fiction on Strat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 09:34:06 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/books/tags/non-fiction/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Taoism: The Parting of the Way</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-21/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-21/</guid><description/></item><item><title>New Dark Age: Technology and the End of the Future</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-02/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-02/</guid><description>&lt;p>A bleak but compelling investigation on a variety of world ending issues we&amp;rsquo;re
facing currently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You have to be in the right mood for this text but if you are, you&amp;rsquo;re likely to
learn something.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Terry Pratchett: A Life with Footnotes</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-28/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-28/</guid><description>&lt;p>Terry Pratchett is an all-timer. The rare case of an author who is immensely
popular for the right reasons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a biography about him, and it&amp;rsquo;s the best one we&amp;rsquo;re going to get, written
by the best person for the job (other than Terry Pratchett himself of course),
his assistant Rob Wilkins.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is what it says it is, the story of Terry Pratchett from the beginning to the
very end.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Words Are My Matter</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-23/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-23/</guid><description>&lt;p>1/3 essays about life 1/3 book forewords 1/3 book reviews&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All written by Ursula K. Le Guin between 2000 and 2016.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ursula K. Le Guin is great, so to no one&amp;rsquo;s surprise there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to love about
this text.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Good Thinking: Why Flawed Logic Puts Us All at Risk and How Critical Thinking Can Save the World</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-08/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-08/</guid><description>&lt;p>A compelling and instructive book on the many logical fallacies we are guilty of
committing ourselves and exposed to through the media and internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A book that made me feel as though it was written specifically for me. A must
read book that very few people will read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Astounding: John W. Campbell, Isaac Asimov, Robert A. Heinlein, L. Ron Hubbard, and the Golden Age of Science Fiction</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-26/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-26/</guid><description>&lt;p>A compelling historical portrayal of the lives of the men involved in writing
for and/or editing the influential Astounding science-fiction magazine since it
was first published in the 1930s.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Priestdaddy</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-07/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-07/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Boulder: A Philosophy for Bouldering</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-10-20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-10-20/</guid><description>&lt;p>A collection of thoughts on the practice of bouldering, bringing it into
conversation with arts and sports as varied as architecture, dance,
skateboarding, painting, parkour, martial arts and gymnastics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Aesthetic Life and Why It Matters</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-10-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-10-03/</guid><description>&lt;p>We all enjoy (and love to comment on) our experiences with media, cuisine,
design, games and more. Clearly, aesthetic pursuits are an integral part of the
human experience, this book tries to tell us why from three different points of
view.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Performance Rock Climbing</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-17/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-17/</guid><description>&lt;p>Reference guide for experienced climbers who want to further hone their skills.
Has newspaper comic-style characters as well as photos to show off the various
techniques. Expresses a lot of information succinctly, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t waste your
time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>9 out of 10 Climbers Make the Same Mistakes</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-16/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-16/</guid><description>&lt;p>A bunch of mistakes climbers (apparently) make and how to avoid them. Not as
concrete and concise as I would like but if you&amp;rsquo;re willing to filter out the
fluff, there&amp;rsquo;s some interesting information here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Self Coached Climber</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-15/</guid><description>&lt;p>A climber&amp;rsquo;s guide to movement, training and performance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Games: Agency as Art</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-14/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-14/</guid><description>&lt;p>Games are a unique art form. They do not just tell stories, nor are they simply
conceptual art. They are the art form that works in the medium of agency. C. Thi
Nguyen&amp;rsquo;s Games: Agency as Art dives deep into these ideas and expands on them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Being Awesome: A Unified Theory of How Not to Suck</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-19/</guid><description>&lt;p>A philosophical exploration of what it means to be awesome and not suck, and a
plea for more awesomeness in our personal, social, and public lives.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Mindbody Prescription</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-01/</guid><description>&lt;p>As someone who&amp;rsquo;s been suffering with chronic pain issues for years now, I&amp;rsquo;m
always on the lookout for anything I can do to help myself feel less pain.
Underneath all the quackery contained in this book there seems to be a grain of
truth (for me, at least). It helped helped me reduce my chronic pain symptoms
considerably in just a short amount of time. If you (or someone you know)
suffers from chronic pain, I would highly recommend this book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Think</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-05-15/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-05-15/</guid><description>&lt;p>Think is a book about the big questions in life: knowledge, consciousness, fate,
God, truth, goodness, justice. It is for anyone who believes there are big
questions out there, but does not know how to approach them. Think sets out to
explain what they are and why they are important. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, and you
knew barely anything about philosophy before reading this, you&amp;rsquo;re in for a wild
ride.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Amusing Ourselves to Death</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-05-01/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-05-01/</guid><description>&lt;p>Amusing Ourselves to Death is a book about the corrosive effects of television
on our politics and public discourse. Now, with television joined by more
sophisticated electronic media—from the Internet to cell phones to DVDs— it&amp;rsquo;s
more relevant than ever.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Pig that Wants to be Eaten</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-15/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-15/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Pig That Wants to Be Eaten offers one hundred philosophical
thought-experiments. To get the most out of it, you might want to pull it out
and discuss a thought-experiment with some friends because the book doesn&amp;rsquo;t do
much more than present the thought-experiments one after the other.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Media Literacy</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-07/</guid><description>&lt;p>Media Literacy teaches you how to navigate through the overwhelming flood of
information found in today&amp;rsquo;s media-saturated world. Drawing from thousands of
media research studies, author W. James Potter explores key components to
understanding the fascinating world of mass media. Potter presents examples and
facts to help you understand how the media operate, how they attract attention,
and how they influence you and the public.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Man Who Mistook His Wife for a Hat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-01/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Man Who Mistook His Wife for a Hat tells the stories of individuals
afflicted with perceptual and intellectual disorders: patients who have lost
their memories and with them the greater part of their pasts; who are no longer
able to recognize people and common objects; whose limbs seem alien to them; who
lack some skills yet are gifted with uncanny artistic or mathematical talents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nine Lives</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-03-15/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-03-15/</guid><description>&lt;p>British guy goes to India and meets with nine different people, each one on a
different religious path and with an interesting story to share. William
Dalrymple acknowledges his white colonialist britishness and seems to mostly
stay out of the way and let the people he meets tell their stories.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Night</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-03-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-03-01/</guid><description>&lt;p>Elie Wiesel&amp;rsquo;s Night is a retelling of what happened to him during World War 2.
In a Nazi death camp, he witnesses the death of his family, the death of his
innocence and the death of his God. Night shows you evil at its peak and
convinces you that this horror must never be allowed to happen again.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Meditations: A New Translation</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-02-15/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-02-15/</guid><description>&lt;p>Marcus Aurelius Antoninus (a.d. 121–180) succeeded his adoptive father as
emperor of Rome in a.d. 161—and in his Meditations he provides insights, wisdom,
and practical guidance on everything from living in the world to coping with
adversity to interacting with others. It&amp;rsquo;s surprising how much of his advice has
aged well but given his position of supreme power and the changing times (eg.
slavery is bad), some of his meditations have not aged so well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Anthropocene Reviewed</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-02-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-02-01/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Anthropocene Reviewed is a book where author/youtuber John Green reviews a
random assortment of things and concepts that you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t expect to see
reviewed. This conceit gives him a lot of room to write about anything he feels
like. John Green is an expert at what he does, but I don&amp;rsquo;t find what he does to
be very compelling.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Because Internet</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-01-20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-01-20/</guid><description>&lt;p>Because Internet: Understanding the New Rules of Language discusses how we
express ourselves on the internet, how we got here and where we&amp;rsquo;re going from
the perspective of a linguist.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Joy of Mixology</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-11-15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-11-15/</guid><description>&lt;p>Everything you need to know about mixing cocktails.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Writing</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-11-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-11-01/</guid><description>&lt;p>Stephen King tells you about his life and his advice on how you can become
better at writing. This amounts to him basically saying &amp;quot;Just write a lot bro&amp;quot;
but despite this, this was quite a fun read. And&amp;hellip; He&amp;rsquo;s not wrong.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Infrastructure</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-10-01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-10-01/</guid><description>&lt;p>Infrastructure is a guide to all the major &amp;quot;ecosystems&amp;quot; of our modern
industrial world. In exploring railroad tracks, antenna towers, highway
overpasses, power lines, coal mines, nuclear power plants, grain elevators, oil
refineries, steel mills, and more, Brian Hayes reveals how our familiar and
often-overlooked industrial environment can be as dazzling as nature.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Understanding Power</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-09-01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-09-01/</guid><description>&lt;p>Understanding Power is the book that convinced me that I needed to start reading
again. It&amp;rsquo;s just a bunch of transcripts taken from Noam Chomsky Q/A sessions,
but man, I&amp;rsquo;m glad that I was convinced to sit down and read through it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>