<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>c_sharp on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/projects/tags/c_sharp/</link><description>Recent content in c_sharp on Strat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/projects/tags/c_sharp/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mages of Mystralia</title><link>https://strategineer.com/projects/2017-05-18/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/projects/2017-05-18/</guid><description>I worked at Borealys Games, an independent video game studio, from May 2016 until November 2017. I mostly worked on Mages of Mystralia but I also worked on other unannounced/cancelled projects.
We were two/three programmers working on Mages of Mystralia (Anthony Demange as lead programmer and Vincent Bilodeau as graphics programmer).
On Mages of Mystralia, I touched almost everything given the small size of the team but I focused specifically on these parts of the game:</description></item><item><title>Black Box Bandit</title><link>https://strategineer.com/projects/2014-08-25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/projects/2014-08-25/</guid><description>Black Box Bandit was developed using Unity in 48h during Ludum Dare 30 (theme: Connected Worlds).</description></item><item><title>Invasion Logistics Pro</title><link>https://strategineer.com/projects/2014-04-28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/projects/2014-04-28/</guid><description>Billguk the Invasion Logistics Professional was developed using Unity in 48h during Ludum Dare 29 (theme: Beneath the Surface).
Today, our Guk leaders have decided to lead their fellow Guks into battle against the hated Surfacers. Billguk, I&amp;rsquo;m calling upon you now to perform the duty you&amp;rsquo;ve trained for your entire life. I ask you to show your fellow Guks that the Invasion Logistics Professional diploma on your bedroom wall actually means something.</description></item><item><title>DnD Sidekick</title><link>https://strategineer.com/projects/2011-12-02/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/projects/2011-12-02/</guid><description>I developed DnD Sidekick the end of 2012.
It was a personal milestone because it was the first fleshed out application that I built from the ground up, it was used extensively by other people and I was paid for my work.
DnD Sidekick &amp;hellip;
– Simplifies the process of character creation for the player. – Allows players to roll any number and any combination of dice. – Contains Spell and Feat dictionaries for quick searches.</description></item><item><title>DNA Toolkit</title><link>https://strategineer.com/projects/2011-12-01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/projects/2011-12-01/</guid><description>I developed DNA Toolkit at the end of 2011.
See my DnD Sidekick page for more information.</description></item></channel></rss>