<rss>
  <channel>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 03:03:08 -0000</lastBuildDate>

    <item>
      <title>Blog - Reviewing code from a project I designed/coded 8 years ago</title>
      <link>https://btyros.com/journals/2019/06/12/writerator-code-review.html</link>
      <guid>https://btyros.com/journals/2019/06/12/writerator-code-review.html</guid>
      <description>One of the first projects I worked on after learning how to program, around 8 years ago, is called a href="https://github.com/KeikakuB/writerator/tree/legacy">writeratora>. It is a Python command line interface (or CLI for short) for analyzing English language text and generating randomized poetry such as haikus&gt;&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <category>tech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog - How to build your own website for 17$ or less</title>
      <link>https://btyros.com/journals/2019/06/08/how-to-build-your-website-for-17-bucks-or-less.html</link>
      <guid>https://btyros.com/journals/2019/06/08/how-to-build-your-website-for-17-bucks-or-less.html</guid>
      <description>The website you're reading this on was built by myself and it cost me a total of 17$ CDN (yearly). Without a custom domain it would have cost me nothing, zilch, nada.

My goal for this website was to create my own space on the internet to allow me to&gt;&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <category>tech</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog - Influencing the odds inside and outside of Blood Bowl 2</title>
      <link>https://btyros.com/journals/2019/05/07/blood-bowl-2-dice-and-rsi.html</link>
      <guid>https://btyros.com/journals/2019/05/07/blood-bowl-2-dice-and-rsi.html</guid>
      <description>"Blood Bowl 2 smashes Warhammer and American football together, in an explosive cocktail of turn-based strategy, humor and brutality, adapted from Games Workshop's famous boardgame."

I'd be hard pressed to come up with a better brief description of&gt;&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <category>gaming</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog - The website, Mortal Kombat 11 and microtransactions</title>
      <link>https://btyros.com/journals/2019/04/24/mortal-kombat-11.html</link>
      <guid>https://btyros.com/journals/2019/04/24/mortal-kombat-11.html</guid>
      <description>I'm currently working on my website (the one you're currently on, I should probably put a "work-in-progress" sign up…). Work has been going well so far. I had done most of the 'setting everything up' for the site a year and a half ago before I was employed&gt;&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
      <category>gaming</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
