<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AshtralFiend on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/mappers/ashtralfiend/</link><description>Recent content in AshtralFiend on Strat</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 19:18:29 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/mappers/ashtralfiend/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Otherworldly Ossuary</title><link>https://strategineer.com/wads/otherworldly_ossuary/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/wads/otherworldly_ossuary/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>looks good and plays amazing, this is a big gameplay levelup for AshtralFiend&lt;/li>
&lt;li>really short though&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>The Tower of Babel</title><link>https://strategineer.com/wads/tower_of_babel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/wads/tower_of_babel/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>inspired by Going Down (mouldy)? The first track is by him and the concept seems related. AshtralFiend&amp;rsquo;s participation in this collab would make sense if that&amp;rsquo;s the case because mouldy&amp;rsquo;s work seems related to his generally.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Going Up?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>tiny maps (1024x1024)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>these tiny maps really fit with most of what AshtralFiend has worked on so far, they seem fascinated by tiny tight maps&lt;/li>
&lt;li>flr07: tight wave-based arena fight, feels pretty good&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a lot of doomcute&lt;/li>
&lt;li>flr15: using single skull next to doors to show that following this path will give you the appropriate skull/key, something to do myself&lt;/li>
&lt;li>flr22: AshtralFiend feels like a main character in this community project, his maps stand out. This one is kind of wild, finally walking around the tower and being able to fall all the way down.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>some of these later maps are atrocious&lt;/li>
&lt;li>flr35: wild set piece&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Venom Vendetta</title><link>https://strategineer.com/wads/venom_vendetta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/wads/venom_vendetta/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Duality</title><link>https://strategineer.com/wads/duality/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/wads/duality/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>oozing style&lt;/li>
&lt;li>most of AshtralFiend&amp;rsquo;s work uses an altered color palette which makes sense, directors do colour grading, painters pick and mix their paint, the color palette is a part of the Doom mapping toolset, they use it effectively&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map01: take on first level of Doom or Doom II?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>these maps are just a little too easy but everything else about them is anything&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ya every level has a different color palette, very cool&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map03: mbf21 transparent textures?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>pistons! pistons everywhere, check these out in UDB&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Habitat Complex</title><link>https://strategineer.com/wads/habitat_complex/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/wads/habitat_complex/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>amazing detailing, Ashtral Fiend is an artist and their levels have impeccable vibes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>amazing doomcute&lt;/li>
&lt;li>OK combat but everything else is firing on all cylinders![alt text]&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Head Trauma</title><link>https://strategineer.com/wads/head_trauma/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/wads/head_trauma/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>doomcute!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>amazing use of textures and sectors, I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen Doom levels that look like this.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>great secrets, I never care about finding secrets in maps but here they&amp;rsquo;re just hidden enough to make you feel smart to find but not too secret that you won&amp;rsquo;t find them.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map01: jumping into the movie screen, feels like the whole premise of Ashtral Fiend coming from an arty/movie background (?) and creating Doom maps from that frame of reference&amp;hellip;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map02: amazing use of the Doom tools in creative ways to sell the fantasy of the space that&amp;rsquo;s being presented here, including extensive use of doomcute&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I need to take a look how these items are being put on conveyor belts (choosing between getting the rocket launcher or plasma gun and grabbing it off the conveyor is so cool)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>blue key on the belt&amp;hellip; wtf, how?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>very cool teleporter that teleports you into a different (hellish) version of the location you&amp;rsquo;re in, very cool.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>inspired by mouldy&amp;rsquo;s work (Going Down) or coming from a similar creative place&lt;/li>
&lt;li>enemy counts feel super low after playing &lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/wads/rush">Rush&lt;/a> (Slaughter for babies)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a runner up to the 2023 cacoawards, makes sense, this is amazing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map03:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>doomcute bathroom stall start, wild&lt;/li>
&lt;li>cooking with gas now boyz&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map04: &amp;ldquo;feeling sick feet under&amp;rdquo; direct reference to mouldy?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a lot of random chaingunners, gives off plutonia vibes (I think that&amp;rsquo;s the one?)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>great lighting, especially completely black sectors making enemies look like shadow puppets in front of animated blood / fireblu&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Nostalgic Entropy: Neo Retro</title><link>https://strategineer.com/wads/ne/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/wads/ne/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>jaw dropping visuals, custom textures, etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>amazing music&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>