<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>What's Strat reading? on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/</link><description>Recent content in What's Strat reading? on Strat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/books/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Stone Sky</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-10/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Left Hand of Darkness</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-02/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Oxford Companion to Food</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-17/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-17/</guid><description/></item><item><title>We</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-14/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-14/</guid><description>&lt;p>The much more interesting but lesser known dystopian novel that inspired George Orwell&amp;rsquo;s 1984.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not as prophetic as Aldous Huxley&amp;rsquo;s Brave New World but it&amp;rsquo;s more consistently well written and has mostly aged better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s more open to interpretation than I was expecting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Desolation Called Peace</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-11/</guid><description>&lt;p>In working through my thoughts after reading this trashfire of a novel book, I wrote five first drafts of a review. They&amp;rsquo;re incomplete but I&amp;rsquo;m posting them here mostly un-edited (just some typo fixes) for posterity. They&amp;rsquo;re either too incomplete, too snarky, too snooty or too mean-spirited to post on Goodreads.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lao Tzu: Tao Te Ching: A Book about the Way and the Power of the Way</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-09/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-09/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Tales from Earthsea</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-06/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-06/</guid><description>&lt;p>A collection of short stories and novellas set in the Earthsea setting that Ursula wrote to help her find out how to continue the story when prompted to do so by her publisher.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s some great stories here but I prefer the Earthsea novels to this generally (don&amp;rsquo;t get me started on The Farthest Shore).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Roadside Picnic</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-03/</guid><description>&lt;p>I love the S.T.A.L.K.E.R. games! Especially the third one. It&amp;rsquo;s a game I always come back to over the years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reading through the original inspiration for the games was a real pleasure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Memory Called Empire</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-29/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-29/</guid><description>&lt;p>A Memory Called Empire has big &amp;ldquo;Hugo award winner&amp;rdquo; energy: an interesting premise, consistent and intriguing world building, a promising start and a propulsive ending.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I loved my time with it and very excited to dig into the next book in the series although I suspect that it won&amp;rsquo;t be as good.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tehanu</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-27/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-27/</guid><description>&lt;p>A sequel to both The Tombs of Atuan and The Farthest Shore.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Considering how uninteresting The Farthest Shore is, I&amp;rsquo;m confident saying that you can skip that book and go straight to Tehanu.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ancient Legends, Mystic Charms and Superstitions of Ireland</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-25/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not sure who to blame for how boring most of this book is:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The British for their empire and the consequences of that on the Irish&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Catholics for influencing the Irish and warping their existing folkloric beliefs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lady Wylde herself for presenting these stories in a very blunt and uninteresting way.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>All of the above?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Maybe Next Time</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-16/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-16/</guid><description>&lt;p>This was the first romance novel I&amp;rsquo;ve read. Sometimes you have to unleash your inner mom and read a book by a mom for moms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m about as far from a mom as you can get but despite that, Cesca Major pulled me in with her writing in a way that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Futurological Congress</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-13/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-13/</guid><description>&lt;p>Stanislaw Lem pops off once again. I&amp;rsquo;m blown away at how he can integrate all these disparate emotions and ideas into one novel.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New Dark Age: Technology and the End of the Future</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-02/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-02/</guid><description>A bleak but compelling investigation on a variety of world ending issues we&amp;rsquo;re facing currently.
You have to be in the right mood for this text but if you are, you&amp;rsquo;re likely to learn something.</description></item><item><title>Death with Interruptions</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-01/</guid><description>Everyone in a small and nameless country becomes immortal, hijinks ensue. death, with a small &amp;ldquo;d&amp;rdquo;, shows up, does some stuff then falls in love with a bass player.
The End.
The weakest of Jose Saramago&amp;rsquo;s work by far.</description></item><item><title>The Child Thief</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-02-29/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-02-29/</guid><description>&lt;p>An edgy retelling of Peter Pan by Brom, the illustrator who&amp;rsquo;s work you&amp;rsquo;ve definitely seen before (Doom II, Diablo II).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sword &amp; Citadel: The Second Half of The Book of the New Sun</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-02-19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-02-19/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Shadow &amp; Claw: The First Half of The Book of the New Sun</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-02-11/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-02-11/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;What will you be, Severian? A torturer? You may leave the guild, you know, if you prefer.&amp;rdquo;
I told him firmly - and as though I were slightly shocked by the suggestion - that I had never considered it. It was a lie. I had known, as all the apprentices knew, that one was not firmly and finally a member of the guild until one consented as an adult to the connection.</description></item><item><title>The Iliad</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-01-27/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-01-27/</guid><description>&lt;p>I love Greek mythology which definitely elevated my appreciation of this text.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re not already a big fan of Greek mythology, you&amp;rsquo;re unlikely to get much out of it though.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Hundred Thousand Kingdoms</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-12-27/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-12-27/</guid><description/></item><item><title>All's Well</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-12-15/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-12-15/</guid><description>&lt;p>I appreciate the depiction of the alienation Miranda feels towards others caused by her chronic pain which is invisible to everyone else but very real to her.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It rings true to me as someone who struggled with chronic pain for a long time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Circe</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-12-01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-12-01/</guid><description>Madeline Miller, the first and the greatest of the authors writing Greek mythology fan fiction, like the hammer of Hephaestus, strikes again.
Circle rewrites the story of, well, Circe who you may have seen in Homer&amp;rsquo;s Odyssey. It was fantastic and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to read her previous novel, the Song of Achilles.</description></item><item><title>The Secret of the Golden Flower: A Chinese Book of Life</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-25/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-25/</guid><description> Conserve your semen. Achieve immortality. Rejoice.</description></item><item><title>Wuthering Heights</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-23/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-23/</guid><description>DNF on page 7
Yikes</description></item><item><title>The Ultimate Micro-RPG Book: 40 Fast, Easy, and Fun Tabletop Games</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-18/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-18/</guid><description>It is what it says it is. Being a collection of a bunch small one shot tabletop RPGs means that their quality will vary and not all of them will be of interest to the people you play with.
I read through all of them and picked out a few that seemed interesting, presented them to my group and we chose to play Unkindness, a game about adolescent ravens causing havoc and experiencing emotions.</description></item><item><title>Nettle &amp; Bone</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-14/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-14/</guid><description>Feels like an Arthurian legend, a mix of fairy tales but grounded in a reality somewhat like our own with some fantastical twists layered into it.
Christ is implied to have existed in this universe so that&amp;rsquo;s a little confusing. Where and when are we then? But it feels like an alternate fantastical reality.
Inverting tropes: instead of a prince saving a princess, the princess wants to kill the prince and save her sister.</description></item><item><title>Guards! Guards!</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-13/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s a Terry Pratchett novel so that implies that it&amp;rsquo;s pretty good. I liked this one quite a bit. After reading Thud! and enjoying that, I decided to start reading the entire Discworld City/Night Watch series. Captain Vimes, Carrot, Sergeant Colon and Nobby are great characters.
Sam Vimes suffers from a combination of alcoholism and depression leading to his skewed perspective of the world.
Lessee . . . he’d gone off after the funeral and got drunk.</description></item><item><title>Eyes of the Void</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-05/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-05/</guid><description>Probably the best &amp;ldquo;second novel in a trilogy&amp;rdquo; that I&amp;rsquo;ve read in a while. To no one&amp;rsquo;s surprise, Adrian Tchaikovsky is responsible.
Eyes of the Void clicked for me when I realized that Adrian Tchaikovsky is an avid tabletop roleplayer and this novel comes alive because he&amp;rsquo;s basically role-playing (to perfection) all of his characters.
He&amp;rsquo;s thought about (and nailed) the way each character thinks and speaks based on where they&amp;rsquo;re from, who they are, their culture, etc.</description></item><item><title>Murder on the Orient Express</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-29/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-29/</guid><description>Murder on the Orient Express is similar to Agatha Christie&amp;rsquo;s Death on the Nile (the other Agatha Christie novel I&amp;rsquo;ve read recently).
Both novels involve Hercule Poirot on vacation traveling (on a train or on a boat respectively), with the soon-to-be murder victim asking Poirot for help, him declining and then after the murder occurs, Poirot proceeds to solve the murder.
But Death on the Nile was SO MUCH MORE of a compelling read for me.</description></item><item><title>Terry Pratchett: A Life with Footnotes</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-28/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-28/</guid><description>Terry Pratchett is an all-timer. The rare case of an author who is immensely popular for the right reasons.
This is a biography about him, and it&amp;rsquo;s the best one we&amp;rsquo;re going to get, written by the best person for the job (other than Terry Pratchett himself of course), his assistant Rob Wilkins.
It is what it says it is, the story of Terry Pratchett from the beginning to the very end.</description></item><item><title>A Canticle for Leibowitz</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-26/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-26/</guid><description>Part 1: Amazing. Seems like this could have easily been an inspiration for the old school Fallout games I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved. Following one monk through the post-apocalypse is cool.
Part 2: Gigantic shift in tone. A less personal, more political story takes hold. Kind of hard to get through. The shift was really jarring.
Part 3: I haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten that far yet.
&amp;hellip;
I&amp;rsquo;ll have to get back to this eventually, it has a lot of potential but it was a challenge for me to read initially.</description></item><item><title>Being and Nothingness</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-25/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-25/</guid><description>Not my cup of tea. Philosophy should be understandable, this text is incomprehensible.
Maybe if was downing absinthe with Sartre and his crew back in the forties when this was written, I would &amp;ldquo;get&amp;rdquo; it. As-is though, this is pretty hard to get through.</description></item><item><title>We Have Always Lived in the Castle</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-23/</guid><description>It was strange to be inside myself, walking steadily and rigidly past the fence, putting my feet down strongly but without haste that they might have noticed, to be inside and know that they were looking at me; I was hiding very far inside but I could hear them and see them still from one corner of my eye. I wished they were all lying there dead on the ground.</description></item><item><title>Vengeful</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-22/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-22/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;In Vengeful, V. E. Schwab is at the top of her game, with twisty action, oddball family pairings, and unexpected antiheroes you can&amp;rsquo;t help but root for&amp;rdquo; - The Washington Post
Hold my beer.
&amp;hellip;
There&amp;rsquo;s no denying that V.E. Schwab is a great writer. She&amp;rsquo;s able to construct stories that entice you to keep reading even though the underlying story isn&amp;rsquo;t all it&amp;rsquo;s cracked up to be.
Her Villains duology leaves me feeling empty.</description></item><item><title>The Farthest Shore</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-21/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-21/</guid><description>Hasn&amp;rsquo;t aged as well as the first two books in the series IMO.
It&amp;rsquo;s kind of a retread of the first book with a little bit of the 80s crack epidemic and reganomics commentary spliced into it. It&amp;rsquo;s not as evergreen as the other books.</description></item><item><title>Blindness</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-20/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-20/</guid><description>&lt;p>José Saramago refuses to use quotation marks, question marks and exclamation marks in his writing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>José Saramago mostly rejects the idea that paragraphs are a writing tool that exist and can be used to make a text more readable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>José Saramago mostly refuses to name his characters and chooses to refer to them instead by their job, title or some aspect of their appearance (eg. The &amp;ldquo;doctor&amp;rsquo;s wife&amp;rdquo;, the &amp;ldquo;girl with the dark glasses&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why does José Saramago do this?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t know. All I know is that it makes reading his work harder than it needs to be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re able to get past the way he writes, or perhaps even enjoy it if you&amp;rsquo;re some kind of sicko, then you&amp;rsquo;ll usually find an interesting story lying underneath with twists and turns that keep you emotionally invested in the world he&amp;rsquo;s built.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Blindness is by far his most popular work and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see why. We follow a doctor and his wife during a pandemic of blindness as they, and others affected by the pandemic, are forced into a mental asylum repurposed to contain the newly blind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The doctor&amp;rsquo;s wife isn&amp;rsquo;t really blind though (she seems to be immune to this new affliction). Lucky for us because the story is mostly told from her perspective.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through her eyes we watch as the asylum fills up with the blind and we watch as they all struggle to perform the most simple of tasks rendered complex due to their lack of sight and their inexperience with this disability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tensions run high and conflict ensues as the last spark of hope is lost and gradually replaced with desperation and hunger for food and for control over their uncertain future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Blindness (the affliction and the novel) is terrifying. Our eyesight is something we rely on more than any other sense to navigate and interact with the world around us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The prospect of losing it is appropriately terrifying. Blindness (the novel) turns this fear into a reality we can perceive and forces us to imagine how horrifying it would be for you and everyone you know to lose their eyesight, and the chaos that would follow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even with a very surface level reading of the novel, Blindness offers a compelling narrative with meaningful stakes and mostly believable world building that sinks its teeth into you and doesn&amp;rsquo;t let go until the very end.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gideon the Ninth</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-18/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-18/</guid><description>A murder mystery set in a Warhammer 40k-esque far far future universe setting with necromancy at the core of everything. Also it&amp;rsquo;s horny but not explicitly so.
This novel is trying to do a little too much IMO and fails to tell a cohesive story that works all the way through as a result.
It&amp;rsquo;s not bad, far from it. It&amp;rsquo;s just inconsistent and a little long.
The setting is cool in theory but in execution I&amp;rsquo;m left feeling as though it&amp;rsquo;s internally inconsistent (and so, less believable than it could be otherwise).</description></item><item><title>The Martian</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-14/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-14/</guid><description>An astronaut is abandoned on Mars after a dust storm separates him from his crew. Through journal entries, he tells the story of how he tries to survive.
The story starts out a bit dry but it starts to shine once people on Earth realize he&amp;rsquo;s alive and begin to make plans to rescue him. The POV shifts around between the &amp;ldquo;Martian&amp;rdquo;, the NASA employees trying to save him and the members of the crew that left him behind.</description></item><item><title>Cain</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-11/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-11/</guid><description>Atheist fan fiction written about the Old Testament.
Cain, the murderer of Abel, wanders around iconic moments from the Old Testament (Noah&amp;rsquo;s Ark, the Tower of Babel, Sodom, Jericho, etc.) and points out how the God of the Old Testament is fucked up and not worth worshipping.
This is kind of a weird one. I don&amp;rsquo;t think Jose Saramago is going to be converting anyone with this text. It&amp;rsquo;s short, if you&amp;rsquo;re curious and a fan of Jose Saramago, go for it.</description></item><item><title>Lilith's Brood</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-10/</guid><description>Dawn - 5 stars Adulthood Rites - 3 stars Imago - 3 stars
What follows is mostly me rambling about the series.
I was blown away by the premise of Dawn and its execution. The remnants of humanity, after a nuclear apocalypse occurs, are &amp;ldquo;saved&amp;rdquo; by aliens and forced to choose between mating with their saviors or never being able to have children again.
This series is about biological determinism, consent, imbalanced power dynamics and sexual violence (among other things).</description></item><item><title>Vicious</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-27/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-27/</guid><description>In Vicious, V. E. Schwab writes some great prose and hooks you with a lot of writing gimmicks (past, present and future POVs, extremely convenient circumstances/decisions to set up exciting scenes, etc.) but she struggles to create a believable narrative with likeable characters.
Almost every character is straight from the Build-Your-Own-Fan-Fiction factory which would be fine but they have more in common with cardboard cutouts than living breathing characters.
The premise of the story and the way the story is told is as edgy as possible.</description></item><item><title>The Martian Chronicles</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-26/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-26/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Raven Tower</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-25/</guid><description>NB: &amp;ldquo;The Raven Tower&amp;rdquo; is one of the worst books I have ever read. I&amp;rsquo;ve only covered the tip of the iceberg in this review because reading through this book has left me completely drained of energy. Please don&amp;rsquo;t read this book, it is beyond trash. If you really want to, I can&amp;rsquo;t stop you but I really wish I could.
I have an important question for y&amp;rsquo;all.
Is this how people speak?</description></item><item><title>Zachary Ying and the Dragon Emperor</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-24/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-24/</guid><description>Xiran Jay Zhao strikes again. I was blown away by her YA novel Iron Window a few months ago so when I saw her next novel Zachary Ying and the Dragon Emperor on sale, I snatched it up.
Once again, Xiran has interwoven ancient Chinese history and mythology seamlessly with an anime inspired aesthetic (Yugioh in this case whereas Iron Window was very Darling in the Franxx) serving it all through a genre appropriate lens.</description></item><item><title>Words are my Matter</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-23/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-23/</guid><description>1/3 essays about life 1/3 book forewords 1/3 book reviews
All written by Ursula K. Le Guin between 2000 and 2016.
Ursula K. Le Guin is great so by the transitive property this text is also great.
As Le Guin writes in the book itself, the forewords and reviews she&amp;rsquo;s written here shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be misconstrued as recommendations per say.
But from reading the text, it&amp;rsquo;s relatively easy to tell the difference between her really liking a book/author vs.</description></item><item><title>The Crane Husband</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-22/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-22/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Gregor The Overlander</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-21/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-21/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s heartbreaking. I&amp;rsquo;m tearing up by page four. This series is advertised as a story for kids but it&amp;rsquo;s written in such a way that it&amp;rsquo;s just as interesting reading through it as an adult. A younger reader wouldn&amp;rsquo;t catch all the subtext (and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of it) consciously.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the oldest kid (11 years old) in his family, Gregor is tasked with taking care of his 2 year old baby sister over the summer while his single mother (Gregor&amp;rsquo;s father &amp;ldquo;disappeared&amp;rdquo; one night) works to put food on the table.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>His grandmother lives with them and has Dementia (although Gregor doesn&amp;rsquo;t know that&amp;rsquo;s what it is).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>For the last year his grandma had been slipping in and out of reality. One minute she was clear as a bell and the next she was calling him Simon. Who was Simon? He had no idea.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gregor doesn&amp;rsquo;t speak like a child, in a lot of ways he&amp;rsquo;s a grown ass man in a boy&amp;rsquo;s body. Children don&amp;rsquo;t speak like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;Great, Day One and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to a trip to the laundry room,&amp;rdquo; Gregor thought. &amp;ldquo;By September, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably be ecstatic when we get the phone bill.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is fine because:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>It makes it easier for me to step into Gregor&amp;rsquo;s shoes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It makes him more interesting.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Trauma forces you to grow up quicker than normal.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Gregor is old at heart and he&amp;rsquo;s been through some shit. He&amp;rsquo;s depressed as hell because he misses his dad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Gregor tried to remember the last time he&amp;rsquo;d felt as happy as Boots did with her ball. He had had some decent times over the past couple of years. [&amp;hellip;] But if he was honest with himself, Gregor knew it had been years since he&amp;rsquo;d felt real happiness.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>THIS IS A BOOK FOR CHILDREN, PLEASE SEND HELP!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not only has Gregor been through &amp;ldquo;some&amp;rdquo; shit, he&amp;rsquo;s about to go through &amp;ldquo;the&amp;rdquo; shit because each book involves Gregor going on a military/diplomatic mission in a world at war, or about to be at war.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Collapsing Empire</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-20/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-20/</guid><description>&lt;p>Felt more like a soap opera than a space opera at times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of people thinking about, talking about and having sex. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of scheming and plotting that sometimes makes sense but often doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PS: I&amp;rsquo;m looking to have a good time reading a book so I try to meet the book I&amp;rsquo;m reading halfway and appreciate what it&amp;rsquo;s trying to do instead of comment on what I think the author should have done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I rolled with it, strapped on my suspension of disbelief pants and enjoyed the ride.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John Scalzi is an amazing writer; every few pages I would have to stop reading and sit there, stunned, by how funny a joke was, or how well set up a scene was, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He managed to immerse me in this universe with an empire on the verge of collapse that felt real(ish) and lived in by real(ish) people which kept me engaged and interested in seeing what would happen next.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Empire of Wild</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-19/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-19/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m torn on this one. I enjoyed it but it was missing a bit of polish.
I enjoyed the cast of characters being mostly of Canadian Indigenous ancestry (well, except the villain). It&amp;rsquo;s not something I&amp;rsquo;ve seen before (which either speaks to my uncultured-ness or the lack of minority voices in the media I&amp;rsquo;m exposed to&amp;hellip; or both).
The story was simple (maybe too simple) but executed well. But it&amp;rsquo;s definitely not a story for a younger demographic though &amp;mdash; it&amp;rsquo;s got a few extremely explicit descriptions of sex in it (I&amp;rsquo;ve read some erotica in my day but this was something else).</description></item><item><title>Everyday Ethics: Inspired Solutions to Real-Life Dilemmas</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-18/</guid><description>DNF 50%
Joshua Halberstam is the king of strawmanning. Every chapter involves him describing these absurd caricatures of human beings and then using them to try to say to something interesting (keyword: try).
What is presented here is not &amp;ldquo;inspired solutions to real-life dilemmas&amp;rdquo; but &amp;ldquo;thoughts and comments on fabricated dilemmas the author came up with&amp;rdquo;.
It&amp;rsquo;s not all drivel but there&amp;rsquo;s so much of it that it was hard for me to care about the rest.</description></item><item><title>All the Names</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-16/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-16/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Iron Widow</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-13/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-13/</guid><description>Big robots,
fighting off aliens,
piloted by pairs of young men and women (mostly boys and girls), with the men draining the life force from the women (often killing them in the process).
Wu Zetian, eventually becoming the Iron Widow, is sold to the army by her family to become a concubine-pilot. She has a plan to avenge her sister, burn the system to the ground and build it back up again.</description></item><item><title>Neverwhere</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-09/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-09/</guid><description>NB: I read the &amp;ldquo;Author&amp;rsquo;s Preferred Text&amp;rdquo; version of this text published in 2016. I&amp;rsquo;m not certain what changes were made to the text compared to the original but just FYI.
This book is terrible. I read through this whole novel and I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything to show for it.
I probably should have put the book down and lit it on fire when the gigantic black Rastafarian sumo wrestler in a diaper showed up.</description></item><item><title>Good Thinking: Why Flawed Logic Puts Us All at Risk and How Critical Thinking Can Save the World</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-08/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-08/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Alice's Adventures in Wonderland / Through the Looking Glass</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-07/</guid><description>I love nonsense.
Yumyum.</description></item><item><title>Parable of the Sower</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-02/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-02/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Feline Philosophy: Cats and the Meaning of Life</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-27/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-27/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m deathly allergic to cats (especially unneutered cats) so despite liking them in theory, I can&amp;rsquo;t spend much time with them.
I&amp;rsquo;m not allergic to philosophy though. This book talks about cats, talks about philosophy and uses the promise of cats to ease you into thinking about philosophy.
At least, that&amp;rsquo;s what I think it&amp;rsquo;s trying to do?
It&amp;rsquo;s hard to tell because the author spends the first half of the book saying that philosophy is a waste of time and leads to depression.</description></item><item><title>Astounding: John W. Campbell, Isaac Asimov, Robert A. Heinlein, L. Ron Hubbard, and the Golden Age of Science Fiction</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-26/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-26/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Obelisk Gate</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-24/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-24/</guid><description>This novel suffers from middle book syndrome. It continues the story set up in the first book and, hopefully, sets up the third and final book.
Unlike The Fifth Season, this novel fails to coalesce the different POVs into a cohesive whole which was one of the best aspects of the first book.
The Obelisk Gate feels like two different stories that were spliced into each other and suffers for it.</description></item><item><title>The Miracle of Mindfulness</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-20/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Essential Tao</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-19/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-19/</guid><description>I much preferred Gia-Fu Feng and Jane English&amp;rsquo;s translation of the Tao Te Ching. I&amp;rsquo;m not an ancient Chinese scholar so I can&amp;rsquo;t speak to how faithful this translation is compared to the original manuscript.
But I can say that the poetry doesn&amp;rsquo;t flow well and some translation choices left me scratching my head &amp;mdash; wondering if Thomas Cleary understands how the English language works.
Read the Feng / English&amp;rsquo;s translation instead!</description></item><item><title>A Gathering of Shadows</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-18/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-18/</guid><description>An absolute page turner if I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read one (I couldn&amp;rsquo;t put this book down). Each time I sat down to read, it only took a few sentences to transport me completely into this world that V.E. Schwab has so carefully built.
A Gathering of Shadows develops the characters introduced in the previous book (along with some fresh faces), portrays the evolution of their relationships with one another and sets everything up for what I&amp;rsquo;m confident is going to be a riveting conclusion to the trilogy.</description></item><item><title>Terminal Alliance</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-17/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-17/</guid><description>This book is a joke and not a very funny one. It fails completely in its stated goal of being funny.
The tonal clash between the comedic intent of the author and the violent story centered around a group of janitors trying to stop a genocide is jarring.
The characters are nothing more than caricatures and this is a trainwreck waiting to happen given the inclusion of a comic relief autistic character.</description></item><item><title>Shards of Earth</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-16/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-16/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Solaris</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-11/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-11/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fantastic genre-bending sci-fi.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My mind&amp;rsquo;s eye has never been very good so I rarely latch on to descriptions of the spaces that characters find themselves in. But, the descriptions of Solaris&amp;rsquo;s space station and the planet it&amp;rsquo;s orbiting were so vivid and interesting that it elevated the story for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The space station&amp;rsquo;s color scheme of white combined with stripes of vibrant colors lit by the alternating blue and red hues of the system&amp;rsquo;s both suns was breathtaking.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Light Brigade</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-09/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-09/</guid><description>The Light Brigade is a story about breaking people down and putting them back together again, both mentally and physically, to turn them into perfect soldiers/monsters.
It&amp;rsquo;s a wild ride that kept me hooked all throughout. It makes reference to many science fiction tropes you&amp;rsquo;ve seen before to keep you guessing and subverting your expectations.
Overall I enjoyed it despite the politics feeling a little on the nose (Late stage capitalism baaaad?</description></item><item><title>The Consuming Fire</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-06/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-06/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Death on the Nile</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-05/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-05/</guid><description>Agatha Christie is described as the &amp;ldquo;Queen of Mystery&amp;rdquo; and the &amp;ldquo;Queen of Crime&amp;rdquo;.
After reading through Death on the Nile for the first time, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend that we add the &amp;ldquo;Queen of Camp&amp;rdquo; to that list.
Death on the Nile is one of the funniest books I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read. I don&amp;rsquo;t think that was the intention of the author almost one hundred years ago when it was first published but reading it now I was chuckling nonstop at how campy and absurd it is.</description></item><item><title>Tombs of Atuan</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-02/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Wizard of Earthsea</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-30/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-30/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Doorways in the Sand</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-25/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-25/</guid><description>In fair puzzles there should always be a way out. But I saw no doorways in the sand, and try as I might I could not make the puzzle fall fair.
Doorways in the Sand tells the story of Fred Cassidy the &amp;ldquo;Eternal Student&amp;rdquo;, a man who&amp;rsquo;s spent 13 years of his life as an undergrad.
He does everything he can to avoid getting a degree so he can continue benefiting from his uncle&amp;rsquo;s generous will, predicated on him being in school (once he graduates he&amp;rsquo;ll be cut off).</description></item><item><title>The Fifth Season</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-29/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-29/</guid><description>The shake that passes will echo. The wave that recedes will come back. The mountain that rumbles will roar.
The Fifth Season is a story about suffering and trying to find moments of pleasure and peace in a broken world.
The POV characters are all persecuted and forced to suffer because of circumstances outside of their control.
They&amp;rsquo;re &amp;ldquo;orogenes&amp;rdquo;, people born with the ability to exert control over stone, often, in exchange of their own life force and of the people around them.</description></item><item><title>The Lathe of Heaven</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-27/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-27/</guid><description> Gaslight, Manifest, Philosophize.</description></item><item><title>Chuang-Tsu: The Inner Chapters</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-23/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-23/</guid><description/></item><item><title>To Be Taught, If Fortunate</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-22/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-22/</guid><description>Humm&amp;hellip;
It was OK.
Unlike The Galaxy and The Ground Within (also written by Becky Chambers), this novella doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of space (see what I did there?) to develop its characters and have you care about them.
There&amp;rsquo;s a little bit of tension as the crew navigates to each planet they&amp;rsquo;ve been tasked with scouring for life. Will they be ok? What will they find? Etc.
But it was hard for me to care.</description></item><item><title>Witches Abroad</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-20/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Fugitive Telemetry</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-17/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Network Effect</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-16/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-16/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Exit Strategy</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-15/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-15/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Rogue Protocol</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-14/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-14/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Artificial Condition</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-13/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-13/</guid><description>The Murderbot Diaries series so far have been extremely cyberpunk:
Murderbot hacks its own brain (or part of it) and tells us about it on page 1 of the first novella. People with cybernetic enhancements are so commonplace that Murderbot can (with a little help) disguise itself like one of them and no one bats an eye. From the very start, the story is focused on big corporations having a lot of control and the consequences of that on the workers and slaves (like Murderbot) in the system.</description></item><item><title>Thud!</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-12/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-12/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>It would be a lot simpler [&amp;hellip;] if this was a story. A sword is pulled out of a stone or a magic ring is flung into the depths of the sea, and with general rejoicing the world turns.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>But this was real life. The world didn&amp;rsquo;t turn, it just went into a spin.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thud! by Terry Pratchett tells the story of Sam Vimes, head of the Ankh-Morpork City Watch, and his fellow coppers trying to solve a dwarf&amp;rsquo;s murder. The upcoming anniversary of the thousands years old Battle of Koom Valley is keeping tension high between the dwarves and the trolls; making it harder for the constables of the Watch to keep the peace and solve the crime.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thud! is a Terry Pratchett novel through and through. There&amp;rsquo;s ample comedy interlaced with impactful action scenes with just a little bit of drama sprinkled in. This time around, it&amp;rsquo;s a little grittier and darker than usual.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thud! is about prejudice. The main plot as well as every sub plot has something to say about prejudice, how it can cloud our judgement and prevent us from doing the right thing and treating everyone with the respect they deserve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The choice to have the protagonist be a prototypical white man in a position of power is great because I would have had a hard time taking the novel seriously if Terry Pratchett, a very white man, had chosen to tell this story from the perspective of a minority.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sam Vimes is an honest man doing the best he can but sometimes that&amp;rsquo;s just not good enough. So, for me, throughout the novel, he flip-flopped between being the hero I was rooting for and the antihero I loved to hate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Priestdaddy</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-07/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-07/</guid><description/></item><item><title>All Systems Red</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-06/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-06/</guid><description>All Systems Red is about a sentient robot-human hybrid, calling themselves Murderbot, a slave to a mega corporation, tasked with protecting the humans it&amp;rsquo;s told to protect.</description></item><item><title>I'm Thinking of Ending Things</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-05/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-05/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s got a twist.
Yayyyyyyyyyyyyy
I loooooOooOoove twists.
Especially when the foreshadowing of the twist is indistinguishable from terrible writing (absurd internal monologues, nonsensical dialogue between characters) on your first, and probably last, reading of the text.
SPOILER ALERT
SPOILER ALERT
SPOILER ALERT
Canonically, the book you&amp;rsquo;re reading, except for the flashforward interstitials between most chapters, was written by an autistic man who kills himself by the end of the book (a truly inspirational tale, thank you so much for your service Iain).</description></item><item><title>Small Gods</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-03/</guid><description>Terry is dedicated to the bit. More than anything he is committed to creating absurd worlds that feel real. His work has aged beautifully because the world we live in is as absurd as it&amp;rsquo;s ever been and it&amp;rsquo;s only getting more absurd from here on out.
Small Gods is about an autistic savant (pour a drink every time Terry Pratchett includes an autistic character in one of his Discworld books) named Brutha who is a lowly priest/monk in the church of Om.</description></item><item><title>Children of Memory</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-28/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-28/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;They think.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;Not thinking like us, though.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;Well that&amp;rsquo;s to be expected.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thief of Time</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-24/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-24/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Going Postal</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-23/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-23/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Galaxy, and the Ground Within</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-21/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-21/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Galaxy, and the Ground Within is a science fiction novel about a diverse cast of characters from all over the galaxy, stuck at an inter-planetary truck stop for an indeterminate span of time, getting to know one another and helping each other overcome (or make peace with) problems in their personal lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the characters learned about each other and gradually opened up about themselves, I started to see parts of myself reflected in them making me feel invested in the mostly low stakes interactions occurring between the characters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve seen complaints about the book not having a plot that propulses the characters forward. Although that&amp;rsquo;s mostly true, I don&amp;rsquo;t think this book needs one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a story about people, it focuses on them and their evolving relationships with one another, finding common ground despite their differences. That&amp;rsquo;s more than enough to keep someone enraptured for however long it takes them to read the book (I know I was).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a story about a ragtag group of underdogs overcoming stacked odds to save the universe, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to look elsewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for something a little bit out there, and are ok with reading something with less action, less sex (although there is some of that) and fewer universe ending apocalypses than you&amp;rsquo;re used to, then I can highly recommend this book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here be spoilers, you&amp;rsquo;ve been warned:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Conjuring of Light</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-18/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-18/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>spoiler alert&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cassandra in Reverse</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-17/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-17/</guid><description>Everything is too far away and too close at the same time, too loud and also too quiet; a yellow door, an orange can, a blue sliver of sky, a dropped navy glove, the red ring around a street sign; a kaleidoscope turning.
A pigeon flaps violently and I put my hands over my face.
It&amp;rsquo;s coming.
It&amp;rsquo;s coming and without my banana muffin there is nothing I can do to stop it.</description></item><item><title>A Darker Shade of Magic</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-12/</guid><description>I really loved it&amp;hellip;
I was skeptical at first (I&amp;rsquo;ve been burned too many times by boring and tropey fantasy novels that so many people love) but V. E. Schwab reeled me in with some gritty and edgy fantasy that felt really &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; to me.
I was so immersed in the world that I was tearing up by the end of the book which doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen to me very often (one character&amp;rsquo;s arc really spoke to me)</description></item><item><title>Space Opera</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-07/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-07/</guid><description>Which of us are people and which of us are meat?
Let&amp;rsquo;s set the stage (you can read all of this on the front cover so no spoilers):
In Space Opera, an intergalactic World War 2-standin breaks out, causing much destruction and suffering (while humans remain woefully unaware of this).
As a result of this confrontation, the remaining alien civilizations unite and organize a Eurovision-esque contest (the Metagalactic Grand Prix) to determine how the resources of the galaxy will be shared amongst the participants for the following year (based on their relative ranking in contest).</description></item><item><title>Children of Ruin</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-03/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-03/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re going on an adventure!&amp;rdquo;
If you liked the previous novel in this series, Children of Time, you&amp;rsquo;re likely to enjoy this one just as much if not more (I definitely did). If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read it, I suggest you start with that one (also great) and then read this sequel. Otherwise, you&amp;rsquo;ll be missing out.
Both novels take place in universes that feel very grounded in reality. The way in which the various species present evolve over time, communicate with each other, perceive the world around them and interact with it, feels satisfyingly plausible while simultaneously feeling truly alien.</description></item><item><title>Piranesi</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-05-30/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-05-30/</guid><description>I guess this is what happens when a tremendously successful author with a single published novel to her name spends 16 years writing another one.
I read Susanna Clarke&amp;rsquo;s first novel, Jonathan Strange and Mr. Norrel, when I was a kid and, now, I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten what it was about and if I enjoyed it (or not).
After reading Piranesi, I&amp;rsquo;m unlikely to forget this one and how I felt reading through it.</description></item><item><title>Children of Time</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-05-20/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-05-20/</guid><description/></item><item><title>To Hold Up the Sky</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-05-11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-05-11/</guid><description>To Hold Up the Sky is a collection of short stories from Liu Cixin who&amp;rsquo;s mostly known for his Three Body Problem trilogy.
This collection is a mixed bag. The stories range from very bad, to middling to great. Two (out of eleven) stories really spoke to me and the rest were mostly meh.</description></item><item><title>Acceptance</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-05-05/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-05-05/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Authority</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-05-04/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-05-04/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Annihilation</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-05-03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-05-03/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Brave New World</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-01-08/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-01-08/</guid><description>Brave New World is a dystopian novel from 1932 about dystopian shit and it has a lot to say about the dystopia we&amp;rsquo;re currently living in.</description></item><item><title>Terraform: Watch/Worlds/Burn</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-12-23/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-12-23/</guid><description>A collection of science-fiction short stories that&amp;rsquo;ll make you go &amp;ldquo;huh, interesting&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; and might encourage you to think about how technology affects your life currently and how it might affect it in the not so distant future.</description></item><item><title>Good Omens</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-12-10/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-12-10/</guid><description>A cool guy devil and a flamboyantly effeminate angel living on Earth try to stop the end times from happening because they&amp;rsquo;ve come to enjoy all of Earth&amp;rsquo;s pleasures (mosly driving fast cars and reading, respectively). Also, there&amp;rsquo;s the anti-christ, a descendant of a prophet who&amp;rsquo;s predicted everything, some dude, etc. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot going on here.</description></item><item><title>The Colour of Magic</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-28/</guid><description>An incompetent wizard is tasked with protecting a visitor visiting from a faraway land. A fantasy novel for people who don&amp;rsquo;t like fantasy novels.</description></item><item><title>Truth of the Divine</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-20/</guid><description>Aliens on Earth in the early/mid 2000s and everything that follows from that. Sequel to Axiom&amp;rsquo;s End, continues Cora&amp;rsquo;s story and adds some new fresh characters (alien and otherwise) into the mix.</description></item><item><title>Axiom's End</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-12/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-12/</guid><description>Set in 2007, the novel is about a U.S. government coverup of contact with extraterrestrial life. You follow the story of Cora, daughter of an exiled whistleblower, who finds herself in the middle of the whole &amp;lsquo;alien&amp;rsquo; situation.</description></item><item><title>Mork Borg</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-02/</guid><description>MÖRK BORG is a pitch-black apocalyptic fantasy RPG about lost souls and fools seeking redemption, forgiveness or the last remaining riches in a bleak and dying world.</description></item><item><title>Wicked Ones</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-01/</guid><description>WICKED ONES is a Forged in the Dark tabletop RPG about a group of fantasy monsters building a dungeon, launching raids on the surface to gather a hoard, and pursuing your nefarious master plan.</description></item><item><title>The Boulder: A Philosophy for Bouldering</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-10-20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-10-20/</guid><description>A collection of thoughts on the practice of bouldering, bringing it into conversation with arts and sports as varied as architecture, dance, skateboarding, painting, parkour, martial arts and gymnastics.</description></item><item><title>Living Beyond Borders: Growing up Mexican in America</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-10-04/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-10-04/</guid><description>An anthology of short stories, comics, and poems from Mexican American authors.</description></item><item><title>Aesthetic Life and Why It Matters</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-10-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-10-03/</guid><description>We all enjoy (and love to comment on) our experiences with media, cuisine, design, games and more. Clearly, aesthetic pursuits are an integral part of the human experience, this book tries to tell us why from three different points of view.</description></item><item><title>Performance Rock Climbing</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-17/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-17/</guid><description>Reference guide for experienced climbers who want to further hone their skills. Has newspaper comic-style characters as well as photos to show off the various techniques. Expresses a lot of information succinctly, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t waste your time.</description></item><item><title>9 out of 10 Climbers Make the Same Mistakes</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-16/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-16/</guid><description>A bunch of mistakes climbers (apparently) make and how to avoid them. Not as concrete and consise as I would like but if you&amp;rsquo;re willing to filter out the fluff, there&amp;rsquo;s some interesting information here.</description></item><item><title>Self Coached Climber</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-15/</guid><description>A climber&amp;rsquo;s guide to movement, training and performance.</description></item><item><title>Games: Agency as Art</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-14/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-14/</guid><description>Games are a unique art form. They do not just tell stories, nor are they simply conceptual art. They are the art form that works in the medium of agency. C. Thi Nguyen&amp;rsquo;s Games: Agency as Art dives deep into these ideas and expands on them.</description></item><item><title>On Being Awesome: A Unified Theory of How Not to Suck</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-19/</guid><description>A philosophical exploration of what it means to be awesome and not suck, and a plea for more awesomeness in our personal, social, and public lives.</description></item><item><title>Monster of the Week</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-17/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-17/</guid><description>Monster of the Week is a standalone action-horror RPG for 3-5 people. Hunt high school beasties a la Buffy the Vampire Slayer, travel the country to bring down unnatural creatures like the Winchester brothers of Supernatural, or head up the government investigation like Mulder and Scully. It seems OK, nothing extraordinary or unique other than the conceit.</description></item><item><title>Heart: The City Beneath</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-16/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-16/</guid><description>Heart: The City Beneath is a tabletop roleplaying game about delving into a nightmare undercity that will give you everything you’ve ever dreamed of – or kill you in the process. It is a dungeon-crawling, story-forward tabletop RPG that focuses on what characters have to lose in pursuit of their dreams in the chaotic darkness beneath the world. Weird but in a good way.</description></item><item><title>The Mindbody Prescription</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-01/</guid><description>As someone who&amp;rsquo;s been suffering with chronic pain issues for years now, I&amp;rsquo;m always on the lookout for anything I can do to help myself feel less pain. Underneath all the quackery contained in this book there seems to be a grain of truth (for me, at least). It helped helped me reduce my chronic pain symptoms considerably in just a short amount of time. If you (or someone you know) suffers from chronic pain, I would highly recommend this book.</description></item><item><title>Think</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-05-15/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-05-15/</guid><description>Think is a book about the big questions in life: knowledge, consciousness, fate, God, truth, goodness, justice. It is for anyone who believes there are big questions out there, but does not know how to approach them. Think sets out to explain what they are and why they are important. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, and you knew barely anything about philosophy before reading this, you&amp;rsquo;re in for a wild ride.</description></item><item><title>Amusing Ourselves to Death</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-05-01/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-05-01/</guid><description>Amusing Ourselves to Death is a book about the corrosive effects of television on our politics and public discourse. Now, with television joined by more sophisticated electronic media—from the Internet to cell phones to DVDs— it&amp;rsquo;s more relavent than ever.</description></item><item><title>The Pig that Wants to be Eaten</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-15/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-15/</guid><description>The Pig That Wants to Be Eaten offers one hundred philosophical thought-experiments. To get the most out of it, you might want to pull it out and discuss a thought-experiment with some friends because the book doesn&amp;rsquo;t do much more than present the thought-experiments one after the other.</description></item><item><title>Media Literacy</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-07/</guid><description>Media Literacy teaches you how to navigate through the overwhelming flood of information found in today&amp;rsquo;s media-saturated world. Drawing from thousands of media research studies, author W. James Potter explores key components to understanding the fascinating world of mass media. Potter presents examples and facts to help you understand how the media operate, how they attract attention, and how they influence you and the public.</description></item><item><title>The Man Who Mistook His Wife for a Hat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-01/</guid><description>The Man Who Mistook His Wife for a Hat tells the stories of individuals afflicted with perceptual and intellectual disorders: patients who have lost their memories and with them the greater part of their pasts; who are no longer able to recognize people and common objects; whose limbs seem alien to them; who lack some skills yet are gifted with uncanny artistic or mathematical talents.</description></item><item><title>Nine Lives</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-03-15/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-03-15/</guid><description>British guy goes to India and meets with nine different people, each one on a different religious path and with an interesting story to share. William Dalrymple acknowledges his white colonialist britishness and seems to mostly stay out of the way and let the people he meets tell their stories.</description></item><item><title>Night</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-03-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-03-01/</guid><description>Elie Wiesel&amp;rsquo;s Night is a retelling of what happened to him during World War 2. In a Nazi death camp, he witnesses the death of his family, the death of his innocence and the death of his God. Night shows you evil at its peak and convinces you that this horror must never be allowed to happen again.</description></item><item><title>Meditations: A New Translation</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-02-15/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-02-15/</guid><description>Marcus Aurelius Antoninus (a.d. 121–180) succeeded his adoptive father as emperor of Rome in a.d. 161—and in his Meditations he provides insights, wisdom, and practical guidance on everything from living in the world to coping with adversity to interacting with others. It&amp;rsquo;s surprising how much of his advice has aged well but given his position of supreme power and the changing times (eg. slavery is bad), some of his meditations have not aged so well.</description></item><item><title>The Anthropocene Reviewed</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-02-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-02-01/</guid><description>The Anthropocene Reviewed is a book where author/youtuber John Green reviews a random assortment of things and concepts that you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t expect to see reviewed. This conceit gives him a lot of room to write about anything he feels like. John Green is an expert at what he does, but I don&amp;rsquo;t find what he does to be very compelling.</description></item><item><title>Because Internet</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-01-20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-01-20/</guid><description>Because Internet: Understanding the New Rules of Language discusses how we express ourselves on the internet, how we got here and where we&amp;rsquo;re going from the perspective of a linguist.</description></item><item><title>The Odyssey</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-12-25/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-12-25/</guid><description>The Odyssey is a classic and there&amp;rsquo;s more stories that have been inspired by it than I can count. After reading it, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to see it echoed everywhere you look.</description></item><item><title>Norse Mythology</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-12-15/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-12-15/</guid><description>Neil Gaiman&amp;rsquo;s Norse Mythology is a retelling of a few stories from Norse mythology (which we don&amp;rsquo;t know very much about). I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of Neil Gaiman&amp;rsquo;s work generally but I found this to be quite boring.</description></item><item><title>The Greek Myths</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-12-01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-12-01/</guid><description>Robert Graves&amp;rsquo;s The Greek Myths is more of an encyclopedia about everything related to the Greek myths rather than a pure retelling of the myths themselves. It&amp;rsquo;s not meant to entertain, it&amp;rsquo;s meant to inform. Although, if learning everything there is to know about Greek myths sounds entertaining to you then this is the book for you.</description></item><item><title>The Joy of Mixology</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-11-15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-11-15/</guid><description>Everything you need to know about mixing cocktails.</description></item><item><title>On Writing</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-11-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-11-01/</guid><description>Stephen King tells you about his life and his advice on how you can become better at writing. This amounts to him basically saying &amp;ldquo;Just write a lot bro&amp;rdquo; but despite this, this was quite a fun read. And&amp;hellip; He&amp;rsquo;s not wrong.</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-10-01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-10-01/</guid><description>Infrastructure is a guide to all the major &amp;ldquo;ecosystems&amp;rdquo; of our modern industrial world. In exploring railroad tracks, antenna towers, highway overpasses, power lines, coal mines, nuclear power plants, grain elevators, oil refineries, steel mills, and more, Brian Hayes reveals how our familiar and often-overlooked industrial environment can be as dazzling as nature.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Power</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-09-01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-09-01/</guid><description>Understanding Power is the book that convinced me that I needed to start reading again. It&amp;rsquo;s just a bunch of transcripts taken from Noam Chomsky Q/A sessions, but man, I&amp;rsquo;m glad that I was convinced to sit down and read through it.
Noam Chomsky has eidetic memory (more commonly known as photographic memory) and so you can ask him about anything and he&amp;rsquo;ll be able to perfectly recall everything he&amp;rsquo;s read and written about the subject.</description></item><item><title>Sandcastles</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-22/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-22/</guid><description>Sandcastles is the french comic book that the recent M. Night Shyamalan&amp;rsquo;s movie Old was based on. A bunch of different people arrive for a relaxing day at the beach and find themselves aging extremely rapidly, babies become teens and older folk die. Hijinks ensue. I don&amp;rsquo;t get it.</description></item><item><title>Remina</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-15/</guid><description>Junji Ito is cool. Uzumaki is great. A lot of his other work is just OK. I think Remina is also just OK.</description></item><item><title>The Drifting Classroom</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-01/</guid><description>The Drifting Classroom is a Japanese horror manga series published from 1972 to 1974 that follows a school (and its students) that is mysteriously transported through time to a post-apocalyptic future.</description></item></channel></rss>