<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>What's Strat reading? on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/</link><description>Recent content in What's Strat reading? on Strat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/books/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Ultimate Micro-RPG Book: 40 Fast, Easy, and Fun Tabletop Games</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-18/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-18/</guid><description>It is what it says it is. Being a collection of a bunch small one shot tabletop RPGs means that their quality will vary and not all of them will be of interest to the people you play with.
I read through all of them and picked out a few that seemed interesting, presented them to my group and we chose to play Unkindness, a game about adolescent ravens causing havoc and experiencing emotions.</description></item><item><title>Lilith's Brood</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-10/</guid><description>Dawn - 5 stars Adulthood Rites - 3 stars Imago - 3 stars
What follows is mostly me rambling about the series.
I was blown away by the premise of Dawn and its execution. The remnants of humanity, after a nuclear apocalypse occurs, are &amp;ldquo;saved&amp;rdquo; by aliens and forced to choose between mating with their saviors or never being able to have children again.
This series is about biological determinism, consent, imbalanced power dynamics and sexual violence (among other things).</description></item><item><title>Collapsing Empire</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-20/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-20/</guid><description>Felt more like a soap opera than a space opera at times.
There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of people thinking about, talking about and having sex. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of scheming and plotting that sometimes makes sense but often doesn&amp;rsquo;t.
PS: I&amp;rsquo;m looking to have a good time reading a book so I try to meet the book I&amp;rsquo;m reading halfway and appreciate what it&amp;rsquo;s trying to do instead of comment on what I think the author should have done.</description></item><item><title>Solaris</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-11/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-11/</guid><description>Fantastic genre-bending sci-fi.
My mind&amp;rsquo;s eye has never been very good so I rarely latch on to descriptions of the spaces that characters find themselves in. But, the descriptions of Solaris&amp;rsquo;s space station and the planet it&amp;rsquo;s orbiting were so vivid and interesting that it elevated the story for me.
The space station&amp;rsquo;s color scheme of white combined with stripes of vibrant colors lit by the alternating blue and red hues of the system&amp;rsquo;s both suns was breathtaking.</description></item><item><title>Doorways in the Sand</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-25/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-25/</guid><description>In fair puzzles there should always be a way out. But I saw no doorways in the sand, and try as I might I could not make the puzzle fall fair.
Doorways in the Sand tells the story of Fred Cassidy the &amp;ldquo;Eternal Student&amp;rdquo;, a man who&amp;rsquo;s spent 13 years of his life as an undergrad.
He does everything he can to avoid getting a degree so he can continue benefiting from his uncle&amp;rsquo;s generous will, predicated on him being in school (once he graduates he&amp;rsquo;ll be cut off).</description></item><item><title>The Obelisk Gate</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-29/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-29/</guid><description>spoiler alert This novel suffers from middle book syndrome. It continues the story set up in the first book and, hopefully, sets up the third and final book.
Unlike The Fifth Season, this novel fails to coalesce the different POVs into a cohesive whole which was one of the best aspects of the first book.
The Obelisk Gate feels like two different stories that were spliced into each other and suffers for it.</description></item><item><title>All Systems Red</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-06/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-06/</guid><description>All Systems Red is about a sentient robot-human hybrid, calling themselves Murderbot, a slave to a mega corporation, tasked with protecting the humans it&amp;rsquo;s told to protect.</description></item><item><title>I'm Thinking of Ending Things</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-05/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-05/</guid><description>spoiler alert SPOILER ALERT
It&amp;rsquo;s got a twist.
Yayyyyyyyyyyyyy
I loooooOooOoove twists.
Especially when the foreshadowing of the twist is indistinguishable from terrible writing (absurd internal monologues, nonsensical dialogue between characters) on your first, and probably last, reading of the text.
SPOILER ALERT
SPOILER ALERT
SPOILER ALERT
Canonically, the book you&amp;rsquo;re reading, except for the flashforward interstitials between most chapters, was written by an autistic man who kills himself by the end of the book (a truly inspirational tale, thank you so much for your service Iain).</description></item><item><title>Small Gods</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-03/</guid><description>Terry is dedicated to the bit. More than anything he is committed to creating absurd worlds that feel real. His work has aged beautifully because the world we live in is as absurd as it&amp;rsquo;s ever been and it&amp;rsquo;s only getting more absurd from here on out.
Small Gods is about an autistic savant (pour a drink every time Terry Pratchett includes an autistic character in one of his Discworld books) named Brutha who is a lowly priest/monk in the church of Om.</description></item><item><title>Children of Memory</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-28/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-28/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;They think.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Not thinking like us, though.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Well that&amp;rsquo;s to be expected.&amp;rdquo;
Minor spoilers below about the basic premise of the series/novel
Children of Memory is the third novel in the Children of Time series by Adrian Tchaikovsky. It follows in the footsteps of the first two books by giving us another story about characters (various uplifted species, human/AI constructs and one fungi species) being thrust together onto another planet.</description></item><item><title>A Conjuring of Light</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-18/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-18/</guid><description>spoiler alert It was an enjoyable romp but doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily hit the highs of the previous books in the series. As the third and final(ish) book in the series I was expecting something a little bit more. Or maybe I was expecting a little bit less, a more tightly edited and polished story. Either would have been nice.
Here&amp;rsquo;s some thoughts:
It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to tell a story about an antagonistic character who is basically a god.</description></item><item><title>Cassandra in Reverse</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-17/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-17/</guid><description>Everything is too far away and too close at the same time, too loud and also too quiet; a yellow door, an orange can, a blue sliver of sky, a dropped navy glove, the red ring around a street sign; a kaleidoscope turning.
A pigeon flaps violently and I put my hands over my face.
It&amp;rsquo;s coming.
It&amp;rsquo;s coming and without my banana muffin there is nothing I can do to stop it.</description></item><item><title>Children of Ruin</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-03/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-03/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re going on an adventure!&amp;rdquo;
If you liked the previous novel in this series, Children of Time, you&amp;rsquo;re likely to enjoy this one just as much if not more (I definitely did). If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read it, I suggest you start with that one (also great) and then read this sequel. Otherwise, you&amp;rsquo;ll be missing out.
Both novels take place in universes that feel very grounded in reality. The way in which the various species present evolve over time, communicate with each other, perceive the world around them and interact with it, feels satisfyingly plausible while simultaneously feeling truly alien.</description></item><item><title>Brave New World</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-01-08/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-01-08/</guid><description>Brave New World is a dystopian novel from 1932 about dystopian shit and it has a lot to say about the dystopia we&amp;rsquo;re currently living in.</description></item><item><title>Terraform: Watch/Worlds/Burn</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-12-23/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-12-23/</guid><description>A collection of science-fiction short stories that&amp;rsquo;ll make you go &amp;ldquo;huh, interesting&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; and might encourage you to think about how technology affects your life currently and how it might affect it in the not so distant future.</description></item><item><title>Good Omens</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-12-10/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-12-10/</guid><description>A cool guy devil and a flamboyantly effeminate angel living on Earth try to stop the end times from happening because they&amp;rsquo;ve come to enjoy all of Earth&amp;rsquo;s pleasures (mosly driving fast cars and reading, respectively). Also, there&amp;rsquo;s the anti-christ, a descendant of a prophet who&amp;rsquo;s predicted everything, some dude, etc. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot going on here.</description></item><item><title>The Colour of Magic</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-28/</guid><description>An incompetent wizard is tasked with protecting a visitor visiting from a faraway land. A fantasy novel for people who don&amp;rsquo;t like fantasy novels.</description></item><item><title>Truth of the Divine</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-20/</guid><description>Aliens on Earth in the early/mid 2000s and everything that follows from that. Sequel to Axiom&amp;rsquo;s End, continues Cora&amp;rsquo;s story and adds some new fresh characters (alien and otherwise) into the mix.</description></item><item><title>Axiom's End</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-12/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-12/</guid><description>Set in 2007, the novel is about a U.S. government coverup of contact with extraterrestrial life. You follow the story of Cora, daughter of an exiled whistleblower, who finds herself in the middle of the whole &amp;lsquo;alien&amp;rsquo; situation.</description></item><item><title>Mork Borg</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-02/</guid><description>MÖRK BORG is a pitch-black apocalyptic fantasy RPG about lost souls and fools seeking redemption, forgiveness or the last remaining riches in a bleak and dying world.</description></item><item><title>Wicked Ones</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-01/</guid><description>WICKED ONES is a Forged in the Dark tabletop RPG about a group of fantasy monsters building a dungeon, launching raids on the surface to gather a hoard, and pursuing your nefarious master plan.</description></item><item><title>The Boulder: A Philosophy for Bouldering</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-10-20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-10-20/</guid><description>A collection of thoughts on the practice of bouldering, bringing it into conversation with arts and sports as varied as architecture, dance, skateboarding, painting, parkour, martial arts and gymnastics.</description></item><item><title>Living Beyond Borders: Growing up Mexican in America</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-10-04/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-10-04/</guid><description>An anthology of short stories, comics, and poems from Mexican American authors.</description></item><item><title>Aesthetic Life and Why It Matters (Thinking Art)</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-10-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-10-03/</guid><description>We all enjoy (and love to comment on) our experiences with media, cuisine, design, games and more. Clearly, aesthetic pursuits are an integral part of the human experience, this book tries to tell us why from three different points of view.</description></item><item><title>Performance Rock Climbing</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-17/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-17/</guid><description>Reference guide for experienced climbers who want to further hone their skills. Has newspaper comic-style characters as well as photos to show off the various techniques. Expresses a lot of information succinctly, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t waste your time.</description></item><item><title>9 out of 10 climbers make the same mistakes</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-16/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-16/</guid><description>A bunch of mistakes climbers (apparently) make and how to avoid them. Not as concrete and consise as I would like but if you&amp;rsquo;re willing to filter out the fluff, there&amp;rsquo;s some interesting information here.</description></item><item><title>Self Coached Climber</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-15/</guid><description>A climber&amp;rsquo;s guide to movement, training and performance.</description></item><item><title>Games: Agency as Art</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-14/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-14/</guid><description>Games are a unique art form. They do not just tell stories, nor are they simply conceptual art. They are the art form that works in the medium of agency. C. Thi Nguyen&amp;rsquo;s Games: Agency as Art dives deep into these ideas and expands on them.</description></item><item><title>On Being Awesome: A Unified Theory of How Not to Suck</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-19/</guid><description>A philosophical exploration of what it means to be awesome and not suck, and a plea for more awesomeness in our personal, social, and public lives.</description></item><item><title>Monster of the Week</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-17/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-17/</guid><description>Monster of the Week is a standalone action-horror RPG for 3-5 people. Hunt high school beasties a la Buffy the Vampire Slayer, travel the country to bring down unnatural creatures like the Winchester brothers of Supernatural, or head up the government investigation like Mulder and Scully. It seems OK, nothing extraordinary or unique other than the conceit.</description></item><item><title>Heart: The City Beneath</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-16/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-16/</guid><description>Heart: The City Beneath is a tabletop roleplaying game about delving into a nightmare undercity that will give you everything you’ve ever dreamed of – or kill you in the process. It is a dungeon-crawling, story-forward tabletop RPG that focuses on what characters have to lose in pursuit of their dreams in the chaotic darkness beneath the world. Weird but in a good way.</description></item><item><title>The Mindbody Prescription</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-01/</guid><description>As someone who&amp;rsquo;s been suffering with chronic pain issues for years now, I&amp;rsquo;m always on the lookout for anything I can do to help myself feel less pain. Underneath all the quackery contained in this book there seems to be a grain of truth (for me, at least). It helped helped me reduce my chronic pain symptoms considerably in just a short amount of time. If you (or someone you know) suffers from chronic pain, I would highly recommend this book.</description></item><item><title>Think</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-05-15/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-05-15/</guid><description>Think is a book about the big questions in life: knowledge, consciousness, fate, God, truth, goodness, justice. It is for anyone who believes there are big questions out there, but does not know how to approach them. Think sets out to explain what they are and why they are important. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, and you knew barely anything about philosophy before reading this, you&amp;rsquo;re in for a wild ride.</description></item><item><title>Amusing Ourselves to Death</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-05-01/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-05-01/</guid><description>Amusing Ourselves to Death is a book about the corrosive effects of television on our politics and public discourse. Now, with television joined by more sophisticated electronic media—from the Internet to cell phones to DVDs— it&amp;rsquo;s more relavent than ever.</description></item><item><title>The Pig that Wants to be Eaten</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-15/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-15/</guid><description>The Pig That Wants to Be Eaten offers one hundred philosophical thought-experiments. To get the most out of it, you might want to pull it out and discuss a thought-experiment with some friends because the book doesn&amp;rsquo;t do much more than present the thought-experiments one after the other.</description></item><item><title>Media Literacy</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-07/</guid><description>Media Literacy teaches you how to navigate through the overwhelming flood of information found in today&amp;rsquo;s media-saturated world. Drawing from thousands of media research studies, author W. James Potter explores key components to understanding the fascinating world of mass media. Potter presents examples and facts to help you understand how the media operate, how they attract attention, and how they influence you and the public.</description></item><item><title>The Man Who Mistook His Wife for a Hat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-01/</guid><description>The Man Who Mistook His Wife for a Hat tells the stories of individuals afflicted with perceptual and intellectual disorders: patients who have lost their memories and with them the greater part of their pasts; who are no longer able to recognize people and common objects; whose limbs seem alien to them; who lack some skills yet are gifted with uncanny artistic or mathematical talents.</description></item><item><title>Nine Lives</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-03-15/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-03-15/</guid><description>British guy goes to India and meets with nine different people, each one on a different religious path and with an interesting story to share. William Dalrymple acknowledges his white colonialist britishness and seems to mostly stay out of the way and let the people he meets tell their stories.</description></item><item><title>Night</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-03-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-03-01/</guid><description>Elie Wiesel&amp;rsquo;s Night is a retelling of what happened to him during World War 2. In a Nazi death camp, he witnesses the death of his family, the death of his innocence and the death of his God. Night shows you evil at its peak and convinces you that this horror must never be allowed to happen again.</description></item><item><title>Meditations: A New Translation</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-02-15/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-02-15/</guid><description>Marcus Aurelius Antoninus (a.d. 121–180) succeeded his adoptive father as emperor of Rome in a.d. 161—and in his Meditations he provides insights, wisdom, and practical guidance on everything from living in the world to coping with adversity to interacting with others. It&amp;rsquo;s surprising how much of his advice has aged well but given his position of supreme power and the changing times (eg. slavery is bad), some of his meditations have not aged so well.</description></item><item><title>The Anthropocene Reviewed</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-02-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-02-01/</guid><description>The Anthropocene Reviewed is a book where author/youtuber John Green reviews a random assortment of things and concepts that you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t expect to see reviewed. This conceit gives him a lot of room to write about anything he feels like. John Green is an expert at what he does, but I don&amp;rsquo;t find what he does to be very compelling.</description></item><item><title>Because Internet</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-01-20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-01-20/</guid><description>Because Internet: Understanding the New Rules of Language discusses how we express ourselves on the internet, how we got here and where we&amp;rsquo;re going from the perspective of a linguist.</description></item><item><title>The Odyssey</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-12-25/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-12-25/</guid><description>The Odyssey is a classic and there&amp;rsquo;s more stories that have been inspired by it than I can count. After reading it, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to see it echoed everywhere you look.</description></item><item><title>Norse Mythology</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-12-15/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-12-15/</guid><description>Neil Gaiman&amp;rsquo;s Norse Mythology is a retelling of a few stories from Norse mythology (which we don&amp;rsquo;t know very much about). I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of Neil Gaiman&amp;rsquo;s work generally but I found this to be quite boring.</description></item><item><title>The Greek Myths</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-12-01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-12-01/</guid><description>Robert Graves&amp;rsquo;s The Greek Myths is more of an encyclopedia about everything related to the Greek myths rather than a pure retelling of the myths themselves. It&amp;rsquo;s not meant to entertain, it&amp;rsquo;s meant to inform. Although, if learning everything there is to know about Greek myths sounds entertaining to you then this is the book for you.</description></item><item><title>The Joy of Mixology</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-11-15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-11-15/</guid><description>Everything you need to know about mixing cocktails.</description></item><item><title>On Writing</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-11-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-11-01/</guid><description>Stephen King tells you about his life and his advice on how you can become better at writing. This amounts to him basically saying &amp;ldquo;Just write a lot bro&amp;rdquo; but despite this, this was quite a fun read. And&amp;hellip; He&amp;rsquo;s not wrong.</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-10-01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-10-01/</guid><description>Infrastructure is a guide to all the major &amp;ldquo;ecosystems&amp;rdquo; of our modern industrial world. In exploring railroad tracks, antenna towers, highway overpasses, power lines, coal mines, nuclear power plants, grain elevators, oil refineries, steel mills, and more, Brian Hayes reveals how our familiar and often-overlooked industrial environment can be as dazzling as nature.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Power</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-09-01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-09-01/</guid><description>Understanding Power is the book that convinced me that I needed to start reading again. It&amp;rsquo;s just a bunch of transcripts taken from Noam Chomsky Q/A sessions, but man, I&amp;rsquo;m glad that I was convinced to sit down and read through it.
Noam Chomsky has eidetic memory (more commonly known as photographic memory) and so you can ask him about anything and he&amp;rsquo;ll be able to perfectly recall everything he&amp;rsquo;s read and written about the subject.</description></item><item><title>Sandcastles</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-22/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-22/</guid><description>Sandcastles is the french comic book that the recent M. Night Shyamalan&amp;rsquo;s movie Old was based on. A bunch of different people arrive for a relaxing day at the beach and find themselves aging extremely rapidly, babies become teens and older folk die. Hijinks ensue. I don&amp;rsquo;t get it.</description></item><item><title>Remina</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-15/</guid><description>Junji Ito is cool. Uzumaki is great. A lot of his other work is just OK. I think Remina is also just OK.</description></item><item><title>The Drifting Classroom</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-01/</guid><description>The Drifting Classroom is a Japanese horror manga series published from 1972 to 1974 that follows a school (and its students) that is mysteriously transported through time to a post-apocalyptic future.</description></item></channel></rss>