<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>1star on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/tags/1star/</link><description>Recent content in 1star on Strat</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 23:10:37 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/books/tags/1star/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Last Herald-Mage Trilogy</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780756411381/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780756411381/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sad/mad gay wizards doing sad/mad gay wizard things.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On the Meaning of Life</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780973769807/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780973769807/</guid><description>&lt;p>One part racist sexist misguided grandpa waxing philosophical about the meaninglessness of life, one part letters responding to Durant&amp;rsquo;s inflamattory prompt on the meaninglessness of life, one part toothless conclusion. Meh.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some of the letters were interesting to read but most of the rest of this was not.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Planetfall</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781473223851/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781473223851/</guid><description>&lt;p>Constant &amp;ldquo;mystery cucking&amp;rdquo; for 95% of the novel, a super rushed ending and paper-thin antagonists heavily detract from the interesting POV and the &amp;ldquo;promised land&amp;rdquo; religious/scientific colonial premise and setting, which is sadly a little underdeveloped.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Meh.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Songs Of The Gorilla Nation</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781400050581/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781400050581/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote cite="p.%20216">
 
 &lt;p>[&amp;hellip;] (I rarely make revisions once I have written).&lt;/p>
 
 &lt;p class="page-number">p. 216&lt;/p>
 
 &lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>No shit girl, we can tell.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This story is about an autistic woman who remembers and describes being born, she goes through some shit (homelessness and stripping, etc.), discovers a passion for gorillas and leverages her understanding of gorillas to help her understand other people.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Royal Blood</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781782760979/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781782760979/</guid><description>&lt;p>Gorgeous art by Dongzi Liu can&amp;rsquo;t save the horrendous writing by Jodorowsky. The extremely taboo and fucked up premise for this is one thing, but I&amp;rsquo;ll read a story about anything. It&amp;rsquo;s just so bad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I cannot begin to imagine what sort of circumstances would have led to the production of this comic. That&amp;rsquo;s the story I want to read about.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fifth Head of Cerberus</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781250840103/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781250840103/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Fifth Head of Cerberus is three novellas Frankenstein-ed together, it lacks the cohesiveness that Wolfe&amp;rsquo;s Book of the New Sun has. It feels like a prototype of what Gene Wolfe would go on to write.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Kaiju Preservation Society</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780765389121/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780765389121/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Kaiju Preservation Society is John Scalzi&amp;rsquo;s attempt at writing a Jurassic Parc-esque light sci-fi romp that pokes fun at billionaires and postures as hard as a heterosexual white man like John Scalzi can about inclusion and diversity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tomie: Complete Deluxe Edition</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781421590561/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781421590561/</guid><description>&lt;p>Juniji Ito&amp;rsquo;s drawing ability vastly surpasses his writing ability. Reading through Tomie has made that abundantly clear to me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What I Mean When I Say I'm Autistic - Unpuzzling A Life On The Autism Spectrum</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9798986482712/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9798986482712/</guid><description>&lt;p>What I Mean When I Say I&amp;rsquo;m Autistic is more of a personal diary made public rather than a memoir or a primer on Autism and suffers for it. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it&amp;rsquo;s something in-between either, I don&amp;rsquo;t really know what it is. It&amp;rsquo;s OK, I guess?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Desolation Called Peace</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781529001648/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781529001648/</guid><description>&lt;p>In working through my thoughts after reading this trashfire of a novel, I wrote five first drafts of a review. They&amp;rsquo;re incomplete but I&amp;rsquo;m posting them here mostly un-edited (just some typo fixes) for posterity. They&amp;rsquo;re either too incomplete, too snarky, too snooty or too mean-spirited to post on Goodreads.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ancient Legends, Mystic Charms And Superstitions Of Ireland</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781398834323/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781398834323/</guid><description>&lt;p>
 
 &lt;img
 loading="lazy"
 class="img-fluid rounded mx-auto d-block"
 width="250" src="https://strategineer.com/img/react/dunno.gif"/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not sure who to blame for how boring most of this book is:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The British for their empire and the consequences of that on the Irish.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The Catholics for influencing the Irish and warping their existing folkloric beliefs.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Lady Wylde herself for presenting these stories in a very blunt and uninteresting way.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>All of the above?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Secret Of The Golden Flower - A Chinese Book Of Life</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780156799805/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780156799805/</guid><description>&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Conserve your semen.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Achieve immortality.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Rejoice.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Wuthering Heights</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781840221893/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781840221893/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yikes&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Being And Nothingness</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781982105440/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781982105440/</guid><description>&lt;p>Not my cup of tea. Philosophy should be understandable, this text is incomprehensible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe if was downing absinthe with Sartre and his crew back in the forties when this was written, I would &amp;ldquo;get&amp;rdquo; it. As-is though, this is pretty hard to get through.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vengeful</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780765387523/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780765387523/</guid><description>&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s no denying that V.E. Schwab is a great writer. She&amp;rsquo;s able to construct stories that entice you to keep reading despite the underlying story not being all it&amp;rsquo;s cracked up to be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Her Villains duology leaves me feeling empty. She knows what the big moments she wants to have in her story are and she constantly steers her characters in the direction of those big moments without it feeling earned.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Raven Tower</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780316388696/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780316388696/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The Raven Tower&amp;rdquo; is one of the worst books I have ever read. I&amp;rsquo;ve only covered the tip of the iceberg in this review because reading through this book has left me completely drained of energy. Please don&amp;rsquo;t read this book, it is beyond trash. If you really want to, I can&amp;rsquo;t stop you but I really wish I could.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Everyday Ethics - Inspired Solutions To Real-Life Dilemmas</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780140165586/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780140165586/</guid><description>&lt;p>Joshua Halberstam is the king of strawmanning. Every chapter involves him describing these absurd caricatures of human beings and then using them to try to say to something interesting (keyword: try).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Neverwhere - Author's Preferred Text</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780062476371/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780062476371/</guid><description>&lt;p>This book is terrible. I read through this whole novel and I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything to show for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I probably should have put the book down and lit it on fire when the gigantic black Rastafarian sumo wrestler in a diaper showed up. I probably should have stopped reading when the profoundly unlikable protagonist turns out to be a pedo. I probably should have stopped reading when I realized that none of the characters were interesting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Feline Philosophy - Cats And The Meaning Of Life</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780374154110/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780374154110/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m deathly allergic to cats (especially unneutered cats) so despite liking them in theory, I can&amp;rsquo;t spend much time with them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not allergic to philosophy though. This book talks about cats, talks about philosophy and uses the promise of cats to ease you into thinking about philosophy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At least, that&amp;rsquo;s what I think it&amp;rsquo;s trying to do?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Terminal Alliance</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780756412746/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780756412746/</guid><description>&lt;p>This book is a joke and not a very funny one. It fails completely in its stated goal of being funny.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The tonal clash between the comedic intent of the author and the violent story centered around a group of janitors trying to stop a genocide is jarring.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The characters are nothing more than caricatures and this is a trainwreck waiting to happen given the inclusion of a comic relief autistic character.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>To Be Taught, If Fortunate</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780062936011/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780062936011/</guid><description>&lt;p>Humm&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was OK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unlike The Galaxy and The Ground Within (also written by Becky Chambers), this novella doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of space (see what I did there?) to develop its characters and have you care about them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I'm Thinking Of Ending Things</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781982152611/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781982152611/</guid><description>&lt;p>Uhhhhhh. Heavy sigh.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Je cultive l'anti-ambition</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9782501140812/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9782501140812/</guid><description/></item><item><title>To Hold Up The Sky</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781250306081/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781250306081/</guid><description>&lt;p>To Hold Up the Sky is a collection of short stories from Liu Cixin who&amp;rsquo;s mostly known for his Three Body Problem trilogy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This collection is a mixed bag. The stories range from very bad, to middling to great. Two (out of eleven) stories really spoke to me and the rest were mostly meh.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Truth Of The Divine</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781250830227/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781250830227/</guid><description>&lt;p>Aliens on Earth in the early/mid 2000s and everything that follows from that. Sequel to Axiom&amp;rsquo;s End, continues Cora&amp;rsquo;s story and adds some new fresh characters (alien and otherwise) into the mix.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Living Beyond Borders</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780593204986/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780593204986/</guid><description>&lt;p>An anthology of short stories, comics, and poems from Mexican American authors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>9 Out Of 10 Climbers Make The Same Mistakes</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780956428103/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780956428103/</guid><description>&lt;p>A bunch of mistakes climbers (apparently) make and how to avoid them. Not as concrete and concise as I would like but if you&amp;rsquo;re willing to filter out the fluff, there&amp;rsquo;s some interesting information here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Games - Agency As Art</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780190052089/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780190052089/</guid><description>&lt;p>Games are a unique art form. They do not just tell stories, nor are they simply conceptual art. They are the art form that works in the medium of agency. C. Thi Nguyen&amp;rsquo;s Games: Agency as Art dives deep into these ideas and expands on them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Pig That Wants To Be Eaten</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780452287440/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780452287440/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Pig That Wants to Be Eaten offers one hundred philosophical thought-experiments. To get the most out of it, you might want to pull it out and discuss a thought-experiment with some friends because the book doesn&amp;rsquo;t do much more than present the thought-experiments one after the other.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Anthropocene Reviewed</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780525555216/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780525555216/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Anthropocene Reviewed is a book where author/youtuber John Green reviews a random assortment of things and concepts that you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t expect to see reviewed. This conceit gives him a lot of room to write about anything he feels like. John Green is an expert at what he does, but I don&amp;rsquo;t find what he does to be very compelling.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Norse Mythology</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780393356182/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780393356182/</guid><description>&lt;p>Neil Gaiman&amp;rsquo;s Norse Mythology is a retelling of a few stories from Norse mythology (which we don&amp;rsquo;t know very much about). I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of Neil Gaiman&amp;rsquo;s work generally but I found this to be quite boring.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sandcastle</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781906838386/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781906838386/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sandcastle is the french comic book that the recent M. Night Shyamalan&amp;rsquo;s movie Old was based on. A bunch of different people arrive for a relaxing day at the beach and find themselves aging extremely rapidly, babies become teens and older folk die. Hijinks ensue. I don&amp;rsquo;t get it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Remina</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781974717477/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781974717477/</guid><description>&lt;p>Junji Ito is cool. Uzumaki is great. A lot of his other work is just OK. I think Remina is also just OK.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>