<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thumbs_down on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/reviews/tags/thumbs_down/</link><description>Recent content in Thumbs_down on Strat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 09:34:06 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/reviews/tags/thumbs_down/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spintires</title><link>https://strategineer.com/reviews/2019-02-27/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/reviews/2019-02-27/</guid><description>WARNING: I&amp;rsquo;ve given a negative review of Spintires even though I find the game to be truly unique and interesting based on the fact that the publisher of the game is not paying the developer for his work and because the sequel to the game Spintires: Mudrunner (with a different publisher who&amp;rsquo;s paying the developer) is a more polished and complete experience.
In Spintires you play a driver tasked with bringing lumber from point A to point B in various muddy, forested, swampy and sometimes watery Eastern European wilderness locations by making use of different heavy duty vehicles.</description></item><item><title>ATOM RPG</title><link>https://strategineer.com/reviews/2019-02-26/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/reviews/2019-02-26/</guid><description>WARNING: This a rant more than it is a comprehensive review. I did not enjoy my time with ATOM RPG even though I&amp;rsquo;m a big old school Fallout fan but I seem to be in the minority so take my words with a grain of salt (a bucket of salt perhaps).
ATOM RPG is Fallout 1/2 if it was set in Russia in an uninspired world filled with hundreds of characters who barely have anything interesting to say with little to no environmental storytelling, it strongly encourages you to play certain character builds and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to actually allow you to make meaningful choices (small or big) defeating the purpose of playing a CRPG in the first place.</description></item><item><title>F3AR</title><link>https://strategineer.com/reviews/2019-02-06/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/reviews/2019-02-06/</guid><description>F3AR is a horror themed FPS that I played as a cooperative experience with a friend. Its core gameplay of shooting bad dudes is quite dated, combining that with its hard to follow and impossible to care about storyline told through very video gamey cinematics results in an experience that leaves much to be desired.
One of its only redeeming factors are the asymmetric characters that you play as in coop: one is a classic FPS protagonist that can slow down time and the other is a classic evil dude who can force choke people and take control of their bodies temporarily.</description></item><item><title>Wasteland 2</title><link>https://strategineer.com/reviews/2018-03-27/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/reviews/2018-03-27/</guid><description>Wasteland 2 is an interesting but unbalanced and dated CRPG in a post apocalyptic setting. It is a sequel to Wasteland, the game which inspired Fallout.</description></item><item><title>Dead Synchronicity Tomorrow Comes Today</title><link>https://strategineer.com/reviews/2018-01-06/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/reviews/2018-01-06/</guid><description>In Dead Synchronicity Tomorrow Comes Today, you play as an amnesiac named Michael, the world has hit by some kind of mysterious calamity.
Dead Synchronicity Tomorrow Comes Today is a graphic adventure game, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty shit.</description></item><item><title>Just Cause 3</title><link>https://strategineer.com/reviews/2018-01-03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/reviews/2018-01-03/</guid><description>In Just Cause 3, you play as Rico Rodriguez returning to his homeland of Medici in order to aid the rebels to overthrow the dictactor, General Sebastiano Di Ravello, in control of the country.
Just Cause 3 is an open world action game whereby you&amp;rsquo;ll be flying around and blowing red stuff up&amp;hellip; Which is fun for a couple hours but quickly becomes tedious primarily because nothing that matters changes as you progress through the game.</description></item></channel></rss>