<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fiction on Strategineer</title>
    <link>https://strategineer.com/blog/tags/fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fiction on Strategineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/blog/tags/fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A bar fight to remember</title>
      <link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-03-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-03-09/</guid>
      <description>We found ourselves at the abandoned mine shaft, home to the mysterious entity we call the Eye.
Preacher, our leader, a man of the cloth with the heavy weight of his unconventional faith on his shoulders.
Desmond, an old man who&amp;rsquo;s been around and knows everyone there is to know.
Teddy, an academic with a desire to gain political power for yet to be determined reasons.
And myself, Blade. Ostracised from the Academy for my &amp;ldquo;dangerous&amp;rdquo; research, I took to the streets where my ability to make things go boom would be put to good use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Positive Thinking by Vincent B. Clear</title>
      <link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-12/</guid>
      <description>The following text is an excerpt from The Power of Positive Thinking™ by Vincent B. Clear.
 What if your thoughts could become reality?
What if you believed hard enough in something, it became true?
Take the next step in your life&amp;rsquo;s journey by learning to harness The Power of Positive Thinking™ to make your life and the lives of those around you, greater than.
My name is Vincent B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diary of a Galaxy Conquering Middle Manager</title>
      <link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-31/</guid>
      <description>Ahhhhhhhhhhhhhhhh I don&amp;rsquo;t want to bathe in the blood of my enemies againnnnnnnnnnn.
Huh.
But, I do it anyway because it&amp;rsquo;s what my boss, my colleagues and my employees expect of me.
Keeping up appearances is important when you&amp;rsquo;re leading a horde of fanatics across the galaxy in a quest to conquer and kill everyone and everything.
I am but a cog in the machine upholding the status quo in charge of killing any living being that steps out of line.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
