<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Roleplaying on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/tags/roleplaying/</link><description>Recent content in Roleplaying on Strat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>me@strategineer.com (Strategineer)</managingEditor><webMaster>me@strategineer.com (Strategineer)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 14:26:59 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/books/tags/roleplaying/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Ultimate Micro-RPG Book: 40 Fast, Easy, and Fun Tabletop Games</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-18/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>me@strategineer.com (Strategineer)</author><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-18/</guid><description>It is what it says it is. Being a collection of a bunch small one shot tabletop RPGs means that their quality will vary and not all of them will be of interest to the people you play with.
I read through all of them and picked out a few that seemed interesting, presented them to my group and we chose to play Unkindness, a game about adolescent ravens causing havoc and experiencing emotions.</description></item><item><title>Mork Borg</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>me@strategineer.com (Strategineer)</author><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-02/</guid><description>MÖRK BORG is a pitch-black apocalyptic fantasy RPG about lost souls and fools seeking redemption, forgiveness or the last remaining riches in a bleak and dying world.</description></item><item><title>Wicked Ones</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>me@strategineer.com (Strategineer)</author><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-01/</guid><description>WICKED ONES is a Forged in the Dark tabletop RPG about a group of fantasy monsters building a dungeon, launching raids on the surface to gather a hoard, and pursuing your nefarious master plan.</description></item><item><title>Monster of the Week</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-17/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>me@strategineer.com (Strategineer)</author><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-17/</guid><description>Monster of the Week is a standalone action-horror RPG for 3-5 people. Hunt high school beasties a la Buffy the Vampire Slayer, travel the country to bring down unnatural creatures like the Winchester brothers of Supernatural, or head up the government investigation like Mulder and Scully. It seems OK, nothing extraordinary or unique other than the conceit.</description></item><item><title>Heart: The City Beneath</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-16/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>me@strategineer.com (Strategineer)</author><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-16/</guid><description>Heart: The City Beneath is a tabletop roleplaying game about delving into a nightmare undercity that will give you everything you’ve ever dreamed of – or kill you in the process. It is a dungeon-crawling, story-forward tabletop RPG that focuses on what characters have to lose in pursuit of their dreams in the chaotic darkness beneath the world. Weird but in a good way.</description></item></channel></rss>