<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Adrian Tchaikovsky on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/authors/adrian-tchaikovsky/</link><description>Recent content in Adrian Tchaikovsky on Strat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 03:59:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/authors/adrian-tchaikovsky/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Eyes of the Void</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-05/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-05/</guid><description>Probably the best &amp;ldquo;second novel in a trilogy&amp;rdquo; that I&amp;rsquo;ve read in a while. To no one&amp;rsquo;s surprise, Adrian Tchaikovsky is responsible.
Eyes of the Void clicked for me when I realized that Adrian Tchaikovsky is an avid tabletop roleplayer and this novel comes alive because he&amp;rsquo;s basically role-playing (to perfection) all of his characters.
He&amp;rsquo;s thought about (and nailed) the way each character thinks and speaks based on where they&amp;rsquo;re from, who they are, their culture, etc.</description></item><item><title>Shards of Earth</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-16/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-16/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Children of Memory</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-28/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-28/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;They think.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Not thinking like us, though.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Well that&amp;rsquo;s to be expected.&amp;rdquo;
Minor spoilers below about the basic premise of the series/novel
Children of Memory is the third novel in the Children of Time series by Adrian Tchaikovsky. It follows in the footsteps of the first two books by giving us another story about characters (various uplifted species, human/AI constructs and one fungi species) being thrust together onto another planet.</description></item><item><title>Children of Ruin</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-03/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-03/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re going on an adventure!&amp;rdquo;
If you liked the previous novel in this series, Children of Time, you&amp;rsquo;re likely to enjoy this one just as much if not more (I definitely did). If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read it, I suggest you start with that one (also great) and then read this sequel. Otherwise, you&amp;rsquo;ll be missing out.
Both novels take place in universes that feel very grounded in reality. The way in which the various species present evolve over time, communicate with each other, perceive the world around them and interact with it, feels satisfyingly plausible while simultaneously feeling truly alien.</description></item></channel></rss>