<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Comic on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/tags/comic/</link><description>Recent content in Comic on Strat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 23:14:15 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/books/tags/comic/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Futurological Congress</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-13/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-13/</guid><description>Stanislaw Lem pops off once again. I&amp;rsquo;m blown away at how he can integrate all these disparate emotions and ideas into one novel. He did a similar thing for me with Solaris.
This book is very scary for how funny the first part of it is. The horror caught me by surprise which elevated its effect on me.
I&amp;rsquo;m interested in reading more of his work!</description></item><item><title>Guards! Guards!</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-13/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s a Terry Pratchett novel so that implies that it&amp;rsquo;s pretty good. I liked this one quite a bit. After reading Thud! and enjoying that, I decided to start reading the entire Discworld City/Night Watch series. Captain Vimes, Carrot, Sergeant Colon and Nobby are great characters.
Sam Vimes suffers from a combination of alcoholism and depression leading to his skewed perspective of the world.
Lessee . . . he’d gone off after the funeral and got drunk.</description></item><item><title>Doorways in the Sand</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-25/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-25/</guid><description>In fair puzzles there should always be a way out. But I saw no doorways in the sand, and try as I might I could not make the puzzle fall fair.
Doorways in the Sand tells the story of Fred Cassidy the &amp;ldquo;Eternal Student&amp;rdquo;, a man who&amp;rsquo;s spent 13 years of his life as an undergrad.
He does everything he can to avoid getting a degree so he can continue benefiting from his uncle&amp;rsquo;s generous will, predicated on him being in school (once he graduates he&amp;rsquo;ll be cut off).</description></item><item><title>Witches Abroad</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-20/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Thud!</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-12/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-12/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>It would be a lot simpler [&amp;hellip;] if this was a story. A sword is pulled out of a stone or a magic ring is flung into the depths of the sea, and with general rejoicing the world turns.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>But this was real life. The world didn&amp;rsquo;t turn, it just went into a spin.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thud! by Terry Pratchett tells the story of Sam Vimes, head of the Ankh-Morpork City Watch, and his fellow coppers trying to solve a dwarf&amp;rsquo;s murder. The upcoming anniversary of the thousands years old Battle of Koom Valley is keeping tension high between the dwarves and the trolls; making it harder for the constables of the Watch to keep the peace and solve the crime.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thud! is a Terry Pratchett novel through and through. There&amp;rsquo;s ample comedy interlaced with impactful action scenes with just a little bit of drama sprinkled in. This time around, it&amp;rsquo;s a little grittier and darker than usual.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thud! is about prejudice. The main plot as well as every sub plot has something to say about prejudice, how it can cloud our judgement and prevent us from doing the right thing and treating everyone with the respect they deserve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The choice to have the protagonist be a prototypical white man in a position of power is great because I would have had a hard time taking the novel seriously if Terry Pratchett, a very white man, had chosen to tell this story from the perspective of a minority.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sam Vimes is an honest man doing the best he can but sometimes that&amp;rsquo;s just not good enough. So, for me, throughout the novel, he flip-flopped between being the hero I was rooting for and the antihero I loved to hate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Small Gods</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-03/</guid><description>Terry is dedicated to the bit. More than anything he is committed to creating absurd worlds that feel real. His work has aged beautifully because the world we live in is as absurd as it&amp;rsquo;s ever been and it&amp;rsquo;s only getting more absurd from here on out.
Small Gods is about an autistic savant (pour a drink every time Terry Pratchett includes an autistic character in one of his Discworld books) named Brutha who is a lowly priest/monk in the church of Om.</description></item><item><title>Thief of Time</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-24/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-24/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Going Postal</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-23/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-23/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Good Omens</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-12-10/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-12-10/</guid><description>A cool guy devil and a flamboyantly effeminate angel living on Earth try to stop the end times from happening because they&amp;rsquo;ve come to enjoy all of Earth&amp;rsquo;s pleasures (mosly driving fast cars and reading, respectively). Also, there&amp;rsquo;s the anti-christ, a descendant of a prophet who&amp;rsquo;s predicted everything, some dude, etc. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot going on here.</description></item><item><title>The Colour of Magic</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-28/</guid><description>An incompetent wizard is tasked with protecting a visitor visiting from a faraway land. A fantasy novel for people who don&amp;rsquo;t like fantasy novels.</description></item></channel></rss>