<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tabletop on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/tags/tabletop/</link><description>Recent content in Tabletop on Strat</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 09:57:21 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/blog/tags/tabletop/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>After Action Report - Sleepaway Oneshot</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2025-08-03/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2025-08-03/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll briefly describe Sleepaway, a TTRPG designed by Jay Dragon, then I&amp;rsquo;ll cover my story game &amp;ldquo;credentials&amp;rdquo; (or lack thereof) and then I&amp;rsquo;ll conclude with some thoughts on the oneshot I played on August 3rd 2025 with some folks from the Quinns Quest&amp;rsquo;s community (thanks to Sparky for pitching and organizing the oneshot and thanks to &lt;a href="https://secretsundaysampler.com/">birdmilk&lt;/a> and TundraFundra for showing up and being great).&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-sleepaway-ttrpg">The Sleepaway TTRPG&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#my-story-game-experience">My Story Game Experience&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-oneshot">The Oneshot&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-less-good">The Less Good&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#time-or-lack-of-it">Time (or lack of it)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#my-roleplaying">My Roleplaying&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-good">The Good&lt;/a>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#moves-and-objectives">Moves and Objectives&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-charactercamp-creation-process">The Character/Camp Creation Process&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>







&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="the-sleepaway-ttrpg">
&lt;h1>
The Sleepaway TTRPG
 &lt;a href="#the-sleepaway-ttrpg">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>

&lt;p>Sleepaway is a horror TTRPG where players each play a camp counselor in a camp of their own creation suffering from the evil and chaotic influence of the Lindworm (like John Carpenter&amp;rsquo;s The Thing but more lovecraftian).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Potluck of TTRPG Mechanics</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2025-05-19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2025-05-19/</guid><description>&lt;p>Most of the tabletop RPG systems that I&amp;rsquo;m familiar with are gathering together today to party like it&amp;rsquo;s 2025 and they&amp;rsquo;ve all brought something to the table (my brain).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In no particular order, here&amp;rsquo;s a show and tell of the most interesting mechanics from TTRPG systems that I&amp;rsquo;ve played and/or ran in the past few years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Delving into Surreal Depths: Lessons from Running Maze of the Blue Medusa with Shadowdark on Foundry VTT</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2025-01-23/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2025-01-23/</guid><description>&lt;p>Running a tabletop RPG campaign is always a learning experience. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share insights from my recent campaign, the &lt;strong>Labyrinth of the Blue Gorgon&lt;/strong>, and the lessons I learned as a GM.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tabletop RPG GMing Lessons Learned (1)</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-11-18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-11-18/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few months ago, I began running an old school rennaissance (mega)dungeon crawling tabletop roleplaying campaign using the Shadowdark RPG rules. It&amp;rsquo;s been the most successful of my attempts at Gamemastering by far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a lot about GMing since the first time I tried it sometime in the mid-00s. I&amp;rsquo;ve been in love with the platonic ideal of tabletop roleplaying for a long time. But my early roleplaying experiences were far removed from what I imagined they could be.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tabletop Roleplaying: Getting your players to care</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 09:15:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-22/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re new to roleplaying or just curious, &lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-14/">take a look at my tabletop roleplaying 101 post&lt;/a> before reading this one.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Tabletop roleplaying works best when everyone at the table is fully invested in the world that the characters you&amp;rsquo;re playing exist in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everyone at the table should be fully bought in to the idea of all of you roleplaying together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s a few tips on achieving this and, in doing so, getting your players to care.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tabletop Roleplaying 101</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-14/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 09:15:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-14/</guid><description>&lt;p>So&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You, or someone you know, has expressed interest in participating in some form of tabletop roleplaying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is tabletop roleplaying?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tabletop roleplaying is a form of interactive storytelling. We&amp;rsquo;ve been telling each other stories sitting around a campfire for as long as anyone can remember. Tabletop roleplaying games are an extension of this. At their core, these games are all about people connecting with each other, creating shared experiences through play and discovering themselves by becoming someone else.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>