<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tabletop on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/tags/tabletop/</link><description>Recent content in Tabletop on Strat</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 20:41:14 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/blog/tags/tabletop/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tabletop RPG GMing Lessons Learned (1)</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-11-18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-11-18/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few months ago, I began running an old school rennaissance (mega)dungeon crawling tabletop roleplaying campaign using the Shadowdark RPG rules. It&amp;rsquo;s been the most successful of my attempts at Gamemastering by far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a lot about GMing since the first time I tried it sometime in the mid-00s. I&amp;rsquo;ve been in love with the platonic ideal of tabletop roleplaying for a long time. But my early roleplaying experiences were far removed from what I imagined they could be.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tabletop Roleplaying: Getting your players to care</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 09:15:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-22/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re new to roleplaying or just curious, &lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-14/">take a look at my tabletop roleplaying 101 post&lt;/a> before reading this one.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Tabletop roleplaying works best when everyone at the table is fully invested in the world that the characters you&amp;rsquo;re playing exist in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everyone at the table should be fully bought in to the idea of all of you roleplaying together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s a few tips on achieving this and, in doing so, getting your players to care.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tabletop Roleplaying 101</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-14/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 09:15:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-14/</guid><description>&lt;p>So&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You, or someone you know, has expressed interest in participating in some form of tabletop roleplaying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is tabletop roleplaying?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tabletop roleplaying is a form of interactive storytelling. We&amp;rsquo;ve been telling each other stories sitting around a campfire for as long as anyone can remember. Tabletop roleplaying games are an extension of this. At their core, these games are all about people connecting with each other, creating shared experiences through play and discovering themselves by becoming someone else.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>