<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>media on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/tags/media/</link><description>Recent content in media on Strat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/blog/tags/media/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Turbo Kid</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-28/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-28/</guid><description>The following text contains spoilers for the movie Turbo Kid (2015), reader discretion is advised.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get into a relatively quick but complete summary of the plot of Turbo Kid before I dive into some of my thoughts.
Feel free to skip ahead if you&amp;rsquo;ve recently watched the movie.
A quick summary ¶ The story takes place in an alternate reality of 1997. Many years ago, humanity lost a war against the robots they created which led to the destruction of civilization.</description></item><item><title>I'm not laughing, you're laughing...</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-26/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-26/</guid><description>Documental is a Japanese reality TV show with a simple premise.
10 comedians (ponying up 1 million Yen each) are locked in a room for 6 hours with cameras filming everything that happens inside.
If one of them smiles or laughs, they get a yellow card. If they do it again, they&amp;rsquo;re kicked out of the room.
The last comedian left in the room after 6 hours have past is declared the winner, and receives a 10 million Yen prize.</description></item><item><title>TLDR: Media Literacy by W. James Potter</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-07/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading the Media Literacy (8th edition) textbook by W. James Potter recently. It&amp;rsquo;s a super interesting topic. Here&amp;rsquo;s a few passages that I&amp;rsquo;ve underlined in the text (I&amp;rsquo;ve read about half of the textbook so far).
Hopefully reading a few of these passages encourages you to pick up a media literacy textbook and start learning about the topic so that I can talk about it with you!
&amp;ldquo;[&amp;hellip;] while choice is attractive, too much choice can paralyze us into inaction.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Marcus Aurelius's Meditations</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-26/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-26/</guid><description>I recently read Marcus Aurelius&amp;rsquo;s Meditations (translated by Gregory Hays) and I quite enjoyed it. Some of his ideas are still relevant today and others haven&amp;rsquo;t aged very well (which is not surprising given how far removed Marcus&amp;rsquo;s experience of life is from our own).
Overall, the text was interesting enough for me to be motivated to make this little toy that shows you one of the &amp;ldquo;meditations&amp;rdquo; every time you refresh the page (tip: if you click/tap on a word it&amp;rsquo;ll bring you to another meditation containing that word).</description></item><item><title>👉 🌐: 🤔 🌱 📃 🔠</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-20/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m always been in 💖 with words but, somehow, I&amp;rsquo;ve gone through most of my life without studying linguistics at all.
(ノಠ益ಠ)ノ彡┻━┻
(┛◉Д◉)┛彡┻━┻
(┛ಠ_ಠ)┛彡┻━┻
┏━┓┏━┓┏━┓ ︵ /(^.^/)
I started listening to the Lingthusiasm podcast in early 2021. It took me a while (until early 2022) to read the book written by one of the hosts (Gretchen McCulloch), but here we are.
Because Internet: Understanding the New Rules of Language is a book that discusses how we express ourselves on the internet, how we got here and where we&amp;rsquo;re going from the perspective of a linguist.</description></item><item><title>Jacob Geller is a god, other people are not</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-18/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-18/</guid><description>Video game Youtube people like Joseph Anderson and Noah Caldwell-Gervais (and many others) have been encouraged by the algorithm (and the way Youtube is monetized) to create longer and longer videos.
It&amp;rsquo;s gotten completely out of hand buuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuut some people seem to be really into it.
I don&amp;rsquo;t see the appeal myself but the numbers don&amp;rsquo;t lie.
Noah Caldwell-Gervais&amp;rsquo; video on the Resident Evil series has a 7h28min long runtime&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Movies I watched in 2021</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-22/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-22/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of the movies I loved (and hated) in 2021 in categories that describe how I felt about them (within each category, the ordering is irrelevant).
Movies I loved ¶ Johnny Mnemonic Keanu Reeves in a business suit going insane in a dystopian cyberpunk world. Keanu&amp;rsquo;s inability to act and William Gibson&amp;rsquo;s inability to write only added to the charm of this movie. The pile of trash that Johnny stands on when making his speech about wanting &amp;ldquo;room service&amp;rdquo; near the end of the movie represents the movie itself.</description></item><item><title>Books I read in 2021</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-19/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-19/</guid><description>Please don&amp;rsquo;t judge me.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t read many books this year but I&amp;rsquo;ve read infinitely more than I did last year.
I used to read during my daily commute&amp;hellip; One day, I just stopped commuting and so I stopped reading too.
This summer, I decided to set aside a bit of time every day to read and here we are. Here&amp;rsquo;s each book I read this year in the order that I read them.</description></item><item><title>TWRP - The Odyssey - Icarus</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-06/</guid><description>Tupper Ware Remix Party ¶ I don&amp;rsquo;t really want to write about Tupper Ware Remix Party.
Writing about music is pain and suffering. Just listen to it, maybe you&amp;rsquo;ll like it.
look at those costumes!
The Odyssey ¶ I just finished reading the Odyssey (translated by Emily Wilson). Odysseus is a mass murderer and a villain&amp;hellip; yet in the story he&amp;rsquo;s presented as a victim and a hero.</description></item><item><title>It's dead, Jim</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-26/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-26/</guid><description>I can&amp;rsquo;t write a hook for my life right now so I&amp;rsquo;m not even going to try.
If that bothers you, I would love to hear from you.
Giant Bomb has been my primary source for gaming news for a long time. I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to and watching the people who work(ed) there since the early 2000s when they were working at Gamespot. The online personas of people like Jeff Gerstmann, Vinny Caravella, Alex Navarro, Ryan Davis and Brad Shoemaker have been a constant presence for most of my life.</description></item><item><title>4 chill beats to work to</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-16/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-16/</guid><description>nervoustestpilot Macross 82-99 Panchiko LukHash &amp;hellip;
I feel like my productivity gets boosted substantially if I&amp;rsquo;m listening to the right kind of music music?
Or maybe listening to good music makes me happy (and more productive)?.
Or maybe I decide to listen to music when I&amp;rsquo;m happy and I&amp;rsquo;m already being more productive than usual because I&amp;rsquo;m happy?
I don&amp;rsquo;t know.</description></item><item><title>The Odyssey Book 1-7: Two Soy Boy Beta Cucks becoming men (again)</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-08/</guid><description>The story of the Odyssey begins with Telemachus, the son of Odysseus, being a soy boy beta cuck. The men vying for the hand of his mother Penelope treat him like shit. Odysseus&amp;rsquo;s long absence has created a power vacuum in Ithaca and many suitors are now waiting in line to court and wed Penelope.
Telemachus attempts to become less of a soy boy beta cuck by becoming more of a misogynist and treating his exceptionally beautiful and intelligent mother like crap.</description></item></channel></rss>