<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Savage Rifts on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/rifts/</link><description>Recent content in Savage Rifts on Strat</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/tabletop/rifts/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GMing Aid</title><link>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/rifts/gming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/rifts/gming/</guid><description>&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="gming-things-to-remember">
&lt;h1>
Gming things to remember
 &lt;a href="#gming-things-to-remember">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>

&lt;ul>
&lt;li>NPCs should communicate during combat whether to taunt, compromise or surrender
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>PCs should usually be able to communicate with most NPCs they encounter at a distance.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>eg: Coalition captains should talk over short range comms. Demons should shout. Mages should mindspeak.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>On a main NPC&amp;rsquo;s turn they should always say something.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Always talk to PCs directly &amp;mdash; instead of saying &amp;ldquo;John, what does Evicerator Jones do?&amp;rdquo;, say &amp;ldquo;Evicerator Jones what do &lt;strong>you&lt;/strong> do?&amp;rdquo;
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;What do you do?&amp;rdquo; should be something I say often when trying to bring players into the action/roleplay and help everyone at the table both set the scene and have their PCs be included in the events going on&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make PC choices matter &amp;mdash; focus on bringing to life the parts of the setting that the players are interacting with most and seem to be the most curious about.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This can and should start at character creation time / session 0 &amp;mdash; if a player creates a character who&amp;rsquo;s on the run from a group of cultists who want to sacrifice him for being a heretic -&amp;gt; work on that faction, build it out, create some NPC sheets for it and figure out interesting ways of bringing them into play.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If PCs really like a particular NPC, be open to turning them into a recurring ally, maybe a Diana-esque handler or an NPC that joins their party. Have the NPC in-character offer this as an option they&amp;rsquo;d be into.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Be flexible &amp;mdash; try to &amp;ldquo;yes, and&amp;rdquo; everything, if you can&amp;rsquo;t say yes adjucate a compromise, write it down for future reference then continue play.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>






&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="one-pager-draft">
&lt;h1>
One Pager Draft
 &lt;a href="#one-pager-draft">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>

&lt;p>&lt;strong>The campaign’s premise and flavor&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>