<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Trash on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/tags/trash/</link><description>Recent content in Trash on Strat</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 22:18:49 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/books/tags/trash/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Desolation Called Peace</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-11/</guid><description>&lt;p>In working through my thoughts after reading this trashfire of a novel, I wrote five first drafts of a review. They&amp;rsquo;re incomplete but I&amp;rsquo;m posting them here mostly un-edited (just some typo fixes) for posterity. They&amp;rsquo;re either too incomplete, too snarky, too snooty or too mean-spirited to post on Goodreads.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Secret Of The Golden Flower - A Chinese Book Of Life</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-25/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-25/</guid><description>&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Conserve your semen.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Achieve immortality.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Rejoice.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Wuthering Heights</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-23/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-23/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yikes&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Being And Nothingness</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-25/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-25/</guid><description>&lt;p>Not my cup of tea. Philosophy should be understandable, this text is incomprehensible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe if was downing absinthe with Sartre and his crew back in the forties when this was written, I would &amp;ldquo;get&amp;rdquo; it. As-is though, this is pretty hard to get through.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Raven Tower</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-25/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The Raven Tower&amp;rdquo; is one of the worst books I have ever read. I&amp;rsquo;ve only covered the tip of the iceberg in this review because reading through this book has left me completely drained of energy. Please don&amp;rsquo;t read this book, it is beyond trash. If you really want to, I can&amp;rsquo;t stop you but I really wish I could.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Everyday Ethics - Inspired Solutions To Real-Life Dilemmas</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-18/</guid><description>&lt;p>Joshua Halberstam is the king of strawmanning. Every chapter involves him describing these absurd caricatures of human beings and then using them to try to say to something interesting (keyword: try).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Neverwhere - Author's Preferred Text</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-09/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-09/</guid><description>&lt;p>This book is terrible. I read through this whole novel and I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything to show for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I probably should have put the book down and lit it on fire when the gigantic black Rastafarian sumo wrestler in a diaper showed up. I probably should have stopped reading when the profoundly unlikable protagonist turns out to be a pedo. I probably should have stopped reading when I realized that none of the characters were interesting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Feline Philosophy - Cats And The Meaning Of Life</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-27/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-27/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m deathly allergic to cats (especially unneutered cats) so despite liking them in theory, I can&amp;rsquo;t spend much time with them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not allergic to philosophy though. This book talks about cats, talks about philosophy and uses the promise of cats to ease you into thinking about philosophy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At least, that&amp;rsquo;s what I think it&amp;rsquo;s trying to do?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Terminal Alliance</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-17/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-17/</guid><description>&lt;p>This book is a joke and not a very funny one. It fails completely in its stated goal of being funny.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The tonal clash between the comedic intent of the author and the violent story centered around a group of janitors trying to stop a genocide is jarring.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The characters are nothing more than caricatures and this is a trainwreck waiting to happen given the inclusion of a comic relief autistic character.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I'm Thinking Of Ending Things</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-05/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-05/</guid><description>&lt;p>Uhhhhhh. Heavy sigh.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>9 Out Of 10 Climbers Make The Same Mistakes</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-16/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-16/</guid><description>&lt;p>A bunch of mistakes climbers (apparently) make and how to avoid them. Not as concrete and concise as I would like but if you&amp;rsquo;re willing to filter out the fluff, there&amp;rsquo;s some interesting information here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Pig That Wants To Be Eaten</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-15/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-15/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Pig That Wants to Be Eaten offers one hundred philosophical thought-experiments. To get the most out of it, you might want to pull it out and discuss a thought-experiment with some friends because the book doesn&amp;rsquo;t do much more than present the thought-experiments one after the other.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Anthropocene Reviewed</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-02-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-02-01/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Anthropocene Reviewed is a book where author/youtuber John Green reviews a random assortment of things and concepts that you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t expect to see reviewed. This conceit gives him a lot of room to write about anything he feels like. John Green is an expert at what he does, but I don&amp;rsquo;t find what he does to be very compelling.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wheel of Time Premium Boxed Set I</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-11-21/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-11-21/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sandcastle</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-22/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-22/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sandcastle is the french comic book that the recent M. Night Shyamalan&amp;rsquo;s movie Old was based on. A bunch of different people arrive for a relaxing day at the beach and find themselves aging extremely rapidly, babies become teens and older folk die. Hijinks ensue. I don&amp;rsquo;t get it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>