<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jose Saramago on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/authors/jose-saramago/</link><description>Recent content in Jose Saramago on Strat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 14:46:34 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/authors/jose-saramago/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Death with Interruptions</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-01/</guid><description>Everyone in a small and nameless country becomes immortal, hijinks ensue. death, with a small &amp;ldquo;d&amp;rdquo;, shows up, does some stuff then falls in love with a bass player.
The End.
The weakest of Jose Saramago&amp;rsquo;s work by far.</description></item><item><title>Blindness</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-20/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-20/</guid><description>&lt;p>José Saramago refuses to use quotation marks, question marks and exclamation marks in his writing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>José Saramago mostly rejects the idea that paragraphs are a writing tool that exist and can be used to make a text more readable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>José Saramago mostly refuses to name his characters and chooses to refer to them instead by their job, title or some aspect of their appearance (eg. The &amp;ldquo;doctor&amp;rsquo;s wife&amp;rdquo;, the &amp;ldquo;girl with the dark glasses&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why does José Saramago do this?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t know. All I know is that it makes reading his work harder than it needs to be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re able to get past the way he writes, or perhaps even enjoy it if you&amp;rsquo;re some kind of sicko, then you&amp;rsquo;ll usually find an interesting story lying underneath with twists and turns that keep you emotionally invested in the world he&amp;rsquo;s built.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Blindness is by far his most popular work and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see why. We follow a doctor and his wife during a pandemic of blindness as they, and others affected by the pandemic, are forced into a mental asylum repurposed to contain the newly blind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The doctor&amp;rsquo;s wife isn&amp;rsquo;t really blind though (she seems to be immune to this new affliction). Lucky for us because the story is mostly told from her perspective.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through her eyes we watch as the asylum fills up with the blind and we watch as they all struggle to perform the most simple of tasks rendered complex due to their lack of sight and their inexperience with this disability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tensions run high and conflict ensues as the last spark of hope is lost and gradually replaced with desperation and hunger for food and for control over their uncertain future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Blindness (the affliction and the novel) is terrifying. Our eyesight is something we rely on more than any other sense to navigate and interact with the world around us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The prospect of losing it is appropriately terrifying. Blindness (the novel) turns this fear into a reality we can perceive and forces us to imagine how horrifying it would be for you and everyone you know to lose their eyesight, and the chaos that would follow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even with a very surface level reading of the novel, Blindness offers a compelling narrative with meaningful stakes and mostly believable world building that sinks its teeth into you and doesn&amp;rsquo;t let go until the very end.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cain</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-11/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-11/</guid><description>Atheist fan fiction written about the Old Testament.
Cain, the murderer of Abel, wanders around iconic moments from the Old Testament (Noah&amp;rsquo;s Ark, the Tower of Babel, Sodom, Jericho, etc.) and points out how the God of the Old Testament is fucked up and not worth worshipping.
This is kind of a weird one. I don&amp;rsquo;t think Jose Saramago is going to be converting anyone with this text. It&amp;rsquo;s short, if you&amp;rsquo;re curious and a fan of Jose Saramago, go for it.</description></item><item><title>All the Names</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-16/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-16/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>