<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Philosophy on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/tags/philosophy/</link><description>Recent content in Philosophy on Strat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 03:59:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/books/tags/philosophy/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lao Tzu: Tao Te Ching: A Book about the Way and the Power of the Way</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-09/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-09/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Secret of the Golden Flower: A Chinese Book of Life</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-25/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-25/</guid><description>Conserve your semen. Achieve immortality. Rejoice. I&amp;rsquo;m on it!</description></item><item><title>Feline Philosphy: Cats and the Meaning of Life</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-27/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-27/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m deathly allergic to cats (especially unneutered cats) so despite liking them in theory, I can&amp;rsquo;t spend much time with them.
I&amp;rsquo;m not allergic to philosophy though. This book talks about cats, talks about philosophy and uses the promise of cats to ease you into thinking about philosophy.
At least, that&amp;rsquo;s what I think it&amp;rsquo;s trying to do?
It&amp;rsquo;s hard to tell because the author spends the first half of the book saying that philosophy is a waste of time and leads to depression.</description></item><item><title>The Miracle of Mindfulness</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-20/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Essential Tao</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-19/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-19/</guid><description>I much preferred Gia-Fu Feng and Jane English&amp;rsquo;s translation of the Tao Te Ching. I&amp;rsquo;m not an ancient Chinese scholar so I can&amp;rsquo;t speak to how faithful this translation is compared to the original manuscript.
But I can say that the poetry doesn&amp;rsquo;t flow well and some translation choices left me scratching my head &amp;mdash; wondering if Thomas Cleary understands how the English language works.
Read the Feng / English&amp;rsquo;s translation instead!</description></item><item><title>Aesthetic Life and Why It Matters (Thinking Art)</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-10-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-10-03/</guid><description>We all enjoy (and love to comment on) our experiences with media, cuisine, design, games and more. Clearly, aesthetic pursuits are an integral part of the human experience, this book tries to tell us why from three different points of view.</description></item><item><title>Games: Agency as Art</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-14/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-14/</guid><description>Games are a unique art form. They do not just tell stories, nor are they simply conceptual art. They are the art form that works in the medium of agency. C. Thi Nguyen&amp;rsquo;s Games: Agency as Art dives deep into these ideas and expands on them.</description></item><item><title>On Being Awesome: A Unified Theory of How Not to Suck</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-19/</guid><description>A philosophical exploration of what it means to be awesome and not suck, and a plea for more awesomeness in our personal, social, and public lives.</description></item><item><title>Think</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-05-15/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-05-15/</guid><description>Think is a book about the big questions in life: knowledge, consciousness, fate, God, truth, goodness, justice. It is for anyone who believes there are big questions out there, but does not know how to approach them. Think sets out to explain what they are and why they are important. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, and you knew barely anything about philosophy before reading this, you&amp;rsquo;re in for a wild ride.</description></item><item><title>The Pig that Wants to be Eaten</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-15/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-15/</guid><description>The Pig That Wants to Be Eaten offers one hundred philosophical thought-experiments. To get the most out of it, you might want to pull it out and discuss a thought-experiment with some friends because the book doesn&amp;rsquo;t do much more than present the thought-experiments one after the other.</description></item><item><title>Meditations: A New Translation</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-02-15/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-02-15/</guid><description>Marcus Aurelius Antoninus (a.d. 121–180) succeeded his adoptive father as emperor of Rome in a.d. 161—and in his Meditations he provides insights, wisdom, and practical guidance on everything from living in the world to coping with adversity to interacting with others. It&amp;rsquo;s surprising how much of his advice has aged well but given his position of supreme power and the changing times (eg. slavery is bad), some of his meditations have not aged so well.</description></item></channel></rss>