<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>philosophy on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/tags/philosophy/</link><description>Recent content in philosophy on Strat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/books/tags/philosophy/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On Being Awesome: A Unified Theory of How Not to Suck</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-08-19/</guid><description>A philosophical exploration of what it means to be awesome and not suck, and a plea for more awesomeness in our personal, social, and public lives.</description></item><item><title>Think</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-05-15/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-05-15/</guid><description>Think is a book about the big questions in life: knowledge, consciousness, fate, God, truth, goodness, justice. It is for anyone who believes there are big questions out there, but does not know how to approach them. Think sets out to explain what they are and why they are important. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, and you knew barely anything about philosophy before reading this, you&amp;rsquo;re in for a wild ride.</description></item><item><title>Meditations: A New Translation</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-02-15/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-02-15/</guid><description>Marcus Aurelius Antoninus (a.d. 121–180) succeeded his adoptive father as emperor of Rome in a.d. 161—and in his Meditations he provides insights, wisdom, and practical guidance on everything from living in the world to coping with adversity to interacting with others. It&amp;rsquo;s surprising how much of his advice has aged well but given his position of supreme power and the changing times (eg. slavery is bad), some of his meditations have not aged so well.</description></item><item><title>Games: Agency as Art</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-14/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-14/</guid><description>Games are a unique art form. They do not just tell stories, nor are they simply conceptual art. They are the art form that works in the medium of agency. C. Thi Nguyen&amp;rsquo;s Games: Agency as Art dives deep into these ideas and expands on them.</description></item><item><title>The Pig that Wants to be Eaten</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-15/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-04-15/</guid><description>The Pig That Wants to Be Eaten offers one hundred philosophical thought-experiments. To get the most out of it, you might want to pull it out and discuss a thought-experiment with some friends because the book doesn&amp;rsquo;t do much more than present the thought-experiments one after the other.</description></item></channel></rss>