<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Strat's Blog on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Strat's Blog on Strat</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2025-01-21/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2025-01-21/</guid><description>&lt;p>This website has existed in some form or another since Tuesday, October 10th 2017 (that was 7 years, 3 months and 11 days ago at the time of writing this)&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time coming, I&amp;rsquo;ve got an &lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/about">about me page now&lt;/a>. Check it out!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>UfoOTY List 2024</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2025-01-03/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2025-01-03/</guid><description>&lt;p>A tier list of the UFO 50 games I played in 2024 (from most fun to least fun).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>NOTY List 2024</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2025-01-02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2025-01-02/</guid><description>&lt;p>A list of novels, in randomized order, that I read and enjoyed in 2024.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GOTY List 2024</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-12-22/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-12-22/</guid><description>&lt;p>A list of games, in randomized order, released in 2024 that I played and enjoyed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tabletop RPG GMing Lessons Learned (1)</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-11-18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-11-18/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few months ago, I began running an old school rennaissance (mega)dungeon crawling tabletop roleplaying campaign using the Shadowdark RPG rules. It&amp;rsquo;s been the most successful of my attempts at Gamemastering by far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a lot about GMing since the first time I tried it sometime in the mid-00s. I&amp;rsquo;ve been in love with the platonic ideal of tabletop roleplaying for a long time. But my early roleplaying experiences were far removed from what I imagined they could be.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dooming in 2024</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-11-16/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-11-16/</guid><description>&lt;p>Have you been playing Doom II recently?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Probably not, but I have.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why have I been playing a ~31 year old game in 2024 you might be asking yourself?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, it&amp;rsquo;s simple really. It&amp;rsquo;s fun. In the many decades since the release of Doom in 1993, a community of mappers has developed and has been hard at work using the framework of Doom games released in the mid 90s to create more, and better, Doom maps than you&amp;rsquo;d be able to get through in a lifetime.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thoughts on Gene Wolfe's the Wizard Knight (1)</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-10-18/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-10-18/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This post contains spoilers for Gene Wolfe&amp;rsquo;s The Knight.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What do you think is the deal with Abel and his inexplicable random acts of violence?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>At the start of the Knight, but this is made clear(er) only in retrospect, Able is young and naive. He&amp;rsquo;s a boy in a man&amp;rsquo;s body but he doesn&amp;rsquo;t really know who HE is, yet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Knight is a journey of self-actualization for Able. He&amp;rsquo;s discovering who he is by doing what kids do. They model their own beliefs and behaviours based on the beliefs and behaviours of the adults around them. In Able&amp;rsquo;s case, early on in the Knight, before he&amp;rsquo;s physically transformed into an absolute beefcake of a man, he has a brief encounter with a knight, Sir Ravd of Redhall.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why Able in Gene Wolfe's The Wizard Knight is the way he is</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-10-17/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-10-17/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is a really rough draft, read the following at your own peril.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This essay contains spoilers for Gene Wolfe&amp;rsquo;s The Knight.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Able of the High Heart is the POV character in Gene Wolfe&amp;rsquo;s fantasy isekai tryptich The Wizard Knight. I loved the first novel of the set, the Knight, mainly because Able of the High Heart is such an interesting character.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the following post, I&amp;rsquo;ll describe the premise of the Wizard Knight, then I&amp;rsquo;ll describe a formative encounter that Able has with the knight named Sir Ravd of Redhall early on in his journey and finally I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how this encounter shaped Able into the knight he is now (or wants to be) and why Able being this way is entertaining to read about.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Business Man Observing Metro Map</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-09-17/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-09-17/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img
 loading="lazy"
 class="img-fluid rounded mx-auto d-block"
 width="600" src="https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-09-17/business_man_observing_metro_map.jpg"/>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GOTY List 2023</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-07-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-07-01/</guid><description>A list of games I played and enjoyed most in 2023.</description></item><item><title>What's Up Gamers</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-04-02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-04-02/</guid><description>&lt;p>I haven&amp;rsquo;t written a blog post in around a year and a half. I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending all of my writing energy on journaling off and on and writing thoughts on the books I&amp;rsquo;m reading.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not really in the mood to write about too much right now but here&amp;rsquo;s a list of some of the books I&amp;rsquo;ve read in the past year and a half and my thoughts on them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GOTY List 2022</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2023-01-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2023-01-02/</guid><description>A list of games I played and enjoyed most in 2022.</description></item><item><title>Avoiding a slow death</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-09-17/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 09:30:31 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-09-17/</guid><description>I regret to inform you that you&amp;rsquo;re dying. We all are. The journey we&amp;rsquo;re on is a one way trip and we&amp;rsquo;re unlikely to discover a cure by the time you need it. Knowing that, how will you decide to live the life you have?</description></item><item><title>10 reasons why I'm in love with bouldering</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-09-16/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-09-16/</guid><description>Bouldering is a form of free climbing that is performed on small rock formations or artificial rock walls without the use of ropes or harnesses. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently fallen in love with the sport and I want to tell you why. So here&amp;rsquo;s 10 (or so) reasons why I&amp;rsquo;m in love with bouldering.</description></item><item><title>Tabletop Roleplaying: Getting your players to care</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 09:15:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-22/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re new to roleplaying or just curious, &lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-14/">take a look at my tabletop roleplaying 101 post&lt;/a> before reading this one.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Tabletop roleplaying works best when everyone at the table is fully invested in the world that the characters you&amp;rsquo;re playing exist in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everyone at the table should be fully bought in to the idea of all of you roleplaying together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s a few tips on achieving this and, in doing so, getting your players to care.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Being Awesome (1)</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-17/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 19:14:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-17/</guid><description>&lt;p>Nick Riggle&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;On Being Awesome: A Unified Theory of How Not to Suck&amp;rdquo; is a philosophy book that discusses awesomeness and suckiness in detail. It defines language to accurately describe and reason about the awesomeness and suckiness that you perceive in yourself and in others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to Mr. Riggle, awesomeness and suckiness revolves all around &lt;em>social openings&lt;/em> which are moments when we can choose to break out of our norm-governed roles by expressing ourselves.&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tabletop Roleplaying 101</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-14/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 09:15:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-14/</guid><description>&lt;p>So&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You, or someone you know, has expressed interest in participating in some form of tabletop roleplaying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is tabletop roleplaying?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tabletop roleplaying is a form of interactive storytelling. We&amp;rsquo;ve been telling each other stories sitting around a campfire for as long as anyone can remember. Tabletop roleplaying games are an extension of this. At their core, these games are all about people connecting with each other, creating shared experiences through play and discovering themselves by becoming someone else.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Got to Go Fast</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 09:40:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-11/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-10">Yesterday I discussed&lt;/a> me getting back into &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intermittent_fasting">intermittent fasting&lt;/a> and the individualistic (and very Western) reasons why.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The short of it is: I want to feel good about my body, I want people to find me attractive and one way I can go about that is by slimming down a little.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, are there less selfish reasons why someone would decide to start fasting?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, of course, fasting, and dietary restrictions in general, are commonly practiced in many faiths. Food is a universal part of the human experience so it makes sense that organized religion would have something to say about it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sentient Potatoes: The Future of War</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 19:52:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>So I&amp;rsquo;m doing &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intermittent_fasting">intermittent fasting&lt;/a> again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It works for me. It helps me reduce my weight in a sustainable way that doesn&amp;rsquo;t disrupt my life (too much).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t want to lose much weight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t have to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From my &lt;em>very&lt;/em> unbiased perspective, I can assure you that losing 10 pounds would be enough to bring me to &lt;em>very sexy man level&lt;/em>. Theoretically (I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s going to happen but who knows), losing 20 pounds would bring me to &lt;em>sexy Greek God level&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Poltergeist Salad Tossed Itself</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-09/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 10:48:37 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-09/</guid><description>&lt;p>We like to believe that we are free (as in freedom).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Under the crushing weight of the societal and economic constraints placed upon you, yes, you can choose. But your options might leave you wanting more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>None of us choose to be born. It kind of just happens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I won&amp;rsquo;t go into the details but, a long time ago, your biological parents touched base and a few months later you were brought into this world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Human-Flavored Soup: Soup-Flavored Human</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 21:15:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-08/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m frustrated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want to say a lot but I don&amp;rsquo;t always know how to express myself in the best way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My thoughts are vague and opaque within my own mind, rarely I&amp;rsquo;m able take these thoughts and convey them in a way that makes sense. A way that clicks with people and allows them to understand a tiny fraction of the way I feel inside.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I solemnly pledge to spend more time writing my thoughts down on paper before they can float away in the never-ending churn that is the human brain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sniper Elite 5's Axis Invasion Mode</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-06-02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 21:04:25 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-06-02/</guid><description>Sniper Elite 5&amp;rsquo;s multiplayer Axis Invasion mode is really cool and here&amp;rsquo;s a few reasons why.</description></item><item><title>Five Reasons to build your website with Hugo</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-05-26/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-05-26/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was making some small changes to my website last week, I don&amp;rsquo;t remember exactly what I was doing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was sitting there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Waiting for my changes to appear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Watching the clock tick away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Contemplating the reality that every second I spend waiting for my build to finish is a second that I&amp;rsquo;m never going to get back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img
 loading="lazy"
 class="img-fluid rounded mx-auto d-block"
 width="600" src="https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-05-26/img/billy.jpg"/> &lt;em>There&amp;rsquo;s got to be a better way!&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turns out there was. All of a sudden, I spent an entire weekend gutting my website, ripping out Middleman, the static site generator I was using, and replacing it with Hugo.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I wrote this on my phone</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-05-23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-05-23/</guid><description>&lt;p>Now that I&amp;rsquo;m using GitHub Actions to deploy my website I&amp;rsquo;m able to write something on my phone, push it to GitHub and Voila!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Freshly squeezed content from my brain to yours.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vim plugins I like</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-05-10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-05-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>Vim is a text editor. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it for over 6 years now and I&amp;rsquo;m madly in love with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re married to the command line like I am (or want to be), then getting over Vim&amp;rsquo;s steep learning curve will be well worth the effort. There&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://romainl.github.io/the-patient-vimmer/0.html">quite a few good resources out there to help non-Vim users get acquainted with it&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What makes Vim so cool?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vim is powerful.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Turbo Kid</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-28/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-28/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The following text contains spoilers for the movie Turbo Kid (2015), reader discretion is advised.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>My insults to the chef</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-27/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-27/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working full time and cooking for myself for long enough to be able to tell you that keeping yourself well fed is a lot harder than you think.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending hours each week: planning what I&amp;rsquo;m going to eat when, getting ingredients and doing the cooking itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s tough and anyone who says otherwise is lying to you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, I wanted to take a little break from all that work to focus on activities that make me happy while keeping myself fed and healthy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I'm not laughing, you're laughing...</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-26/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-26/</guid><description>&lt;p>Documental is a Japanese reality TV show with a simple premise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>10 comedians (ponying up 1 million Yen each) are locked in a room for 6 hours with cameras filming everything that happens inside.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If one of them smiles or laughs, they get a yellow card. If they do it again, they&amp;rsquo;re kicked out of the room.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The last comedian left in the room after 6 hours have past is declared the winner, and receives a 10 million Yen prize.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Undiscording yourself 101</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-25/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="#how-to-delete-all-your-messages-on-a-discord-server">Skip ahead if you know what you&amp;rsquo;re doing and just want to learn how to delete all your messages on a Discord server&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Discord is a social media platform allowing users in various user-created groups, called servers, to chat with each other through text or voice chat and stream video of themselves or their screen, all in real time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Text messages are stored on the server forever and aren&amp;rsquo;t automatically deleted no matter how old they are or currently relevant they are.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Get me out of here!</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-22/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-22/</guid><description>&lt;p>I like to play games.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And to no one&amp;rsquo;s surprise, I guess I&amp;rsquo;m really into escape rooms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What are escape rooms, you ask?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Borrowing elements from point-and-click adventure games, live-action role-playing, interactive theatre, treasure hunts, movies, and TV shows, an escape room is &amp;ldquo;a live-action team-based game where players discover clues, solve puzzles, and accomplish tasks in one or more rooms in order to accomplish a specific goal (usually escaping from the room) in a limited amount of time&amp;rdquo;.&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introducing Myself</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-18/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hi, my name&amp;rsquo;s [NAME]. I&amp;rsquo;ve lived in [CITY], [COUNTRY] my whole life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve worked in the flight simulator space, the video game world, in special effects and, most recently, in financial services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em>débrouillard&lt;/em> meaning that no matter what problem you throw at me, inevitably, I&amp;rsquo;ll figure it out and solve it. I thrive in environments where there&amp;rsquo;s lots of interesting problems to solve. That&amp;rsquo;s what peeked my initial interest in [COMPANY] and I&amp;rsquo;m happy to be here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Twilight</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-17/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-17/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://mynoise.net/NoiseMachines/twilightSoundscapeGenerator.php">https://mynoise.net/NoiseMachines/twilightSoundscapeGenerator.php&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Twinkling stars blinking in and out of existence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The thought of the sound of space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Weightless, floating, breathing in and out forever.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An alien hand reaches out, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s going to be OK&amp;rdquo; they said.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Time stopped, and I looked inward to find myself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Forgiving yourself for mistakes made and ones you&amp;rsquo;ve yet to make.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The liminal space between your past and your present selves.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Untitled - Poem #21973</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-10/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>A dark and dank cave, you see,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Murky and mouldy, walls surrounding me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It feels safe, or at least, it used to,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, my monsters keep me company.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A tiny ray of light seeps through,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A gentle warmth between my toes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cup your ear and you&amp;rsquo;ll hear,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The sound of those I left behind,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Praying for my salvation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TLDR: Media Literacy by W. James Potter</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-07/</guid><description>&lt;p>EDIT 2022-08-22: check out my new &lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/books">/books page&lt;/a> to see what the books I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading and what I think about them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading the Media Literacy (8th edition) textbook by W. James Potter recently. It&amp;rsquo;s a super interesting topic. Here&amp;rsquo;s a few passages that I&amp;rsquo;ve underlined in the text (I&amp;rsquo;ve read about half of the textbook so far).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hopefully reading a few of these passages encourages you to pick up a media literacy textbook and start learning about the topic so that I can talk about it with you!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Overjustification Effect</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-03-24/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-03-24/</guid><description>&lt;p>I learned to code sometime in 2011. I started getting paid to code in 2016.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What started out as a passion turned into a job. This sometimes leads to what&amp;rsquo;s called the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Overjustification_effect">overjustification effect&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The overjustification effect occurs when an expected external incentive such as money or prizes decreases a person&amp;rsquo;s intrinsic motivation to perform a task. Overjustification is an explanation for the phenomenon known as motivational &amp;ldquo;crowding out&amp;rdquo;. The overall effect of offering a reward for a previously unrewarded activity is a shift to extrinsic motivation and the undermining of pre-existing intrinsic motivation. Once rewards are no longer offered, interest in the activity is lost; prior intrinsic motivation does not return, and extrinsic rewards must be continuously offered as motivation to sustain the activity.&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A bar fight to remember</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-03-09/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-03-09/</guid><description>&lt;p>We found ourselves at the abandoned mine shaft, home to the mysterious entity we call the Eye.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Preacher, our leader, a man of the cloth with the heavy weight of his unconventional faith on his shoulders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Desmond, an old man who&amp;rsquo;s been around and knows everyone there is to know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Teddy, an academic with a desire to gain political power for yet to be determined reasons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And myself, Blade. Ostracised from the Academy for my &amp;ldquo;dangerous&amp;rdquo; research, I took to the streets where my ability to make things go boom would be put to good use.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Benefiting from the Nasal Douche</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-02-07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-02-07/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve suffered from seasonal allergies and dust mite allergies (and cats make me want to die) most of my life. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t brought to an allergy doctor when I was a kid and so I just learned how to deal with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But my symptoms worsened over time, making it impossible for me to ignore them any longer. Eventually, I went to get help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How does one treat allergies?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not a doctor but this is what I know.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bad Poetry #1</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-02-06/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-02-06/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sifting through the filtered photographs&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Left and right, left and right&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was love at first swipe.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Balsamic vinegar,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s healthy&amp;rdquo;, they said. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s good for you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But, healthy salad makes me a sad lad.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Choking on a piece of bread,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Chew before you swallow&amp;rdquo;, they said,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I didn&amp;rsquo;t listen and now I&amp;rsquo;m dead.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Flames engulf us,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I hold on to you, tight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Are you feeling this?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope you are.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Beetles, bravery and brotherhood</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-02-02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-02-02/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let the beetles beat their drums&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Waves reflecting off the sun&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet, the war has just begun&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Previously potted plant, shards everywhere&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Uprooted but far from death,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A survivor, stronger than ever&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mint never gave up.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Twelve or more weeks later, disremembered&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gone forever but not forgotten&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Brother, who would you have been?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Exploring Marcus Aurelius's Meditations</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-26/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-26/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently read Marcus Aurelius&amp;rsquo;s Meditations (translated by Gregory Hays) and I quite enjoyed it. Some of his ideas are still relevant today and others haven&amp;rsquo;t aged very well (which is not surprising given how far removed Marcus&amp;rsquo;s experience of life is from our own).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, the text was interesting enough for me to be motivated to make &lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/bin/meditations/">this little toy that shows you one of the &amp;ldquo;meditations&amp;rdquo; every time you refresh the page&lt;/a> (tip: if you click/tap on a word it&amp;rsquo;ll bring you to another meditation containing that word).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>F*** dating apps</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-23/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-23/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-14/">As discussed in my first entry of my previous series of posts&lt;/a>, we are motivated by a combination of intrinsic and extrinsic rewards that encourage us to spend our valuable time on certain activities rather than others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Companies are not people, they&amp;rsquo;re not your friend. If they could murder you, without getting caught, and sell your organs for profit, they would. Money is what motivates companies to do what they do.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>👉 🌐: 🤔 🌱 📃 🔠</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-20/</guid><description>&lt;p>EDIT 2022-08-22: Check out my new &lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/books">/books page&lt;/a> where I talk about books I&amp;rsquo;ve read and my thoughts on them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-14/">always been in 💖 with words&lt;/a> but, somehow, I&amp;rsquo;ve gone through most of my life without studying linguistics at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(ノಠ益ಠ)ノ彡┻━┻&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(┛◉Д◉)┛彡┻━┻&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(┛ಠ_ಠ)┛彡┻━┻&lt;/p>
&lt;p>┏━┓┏━┓┏━┓ ︵ /(^.^/)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started listening to &lt;a href="https://lingthusiasm.com/">the Lingthusiasm podcast&lt;/a> in early 2021. It took me a while (until early 2022) to read the book written by one of the hosts (Gretchen McCulloch), but here we are.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jacob Geller is a god, other people are not</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-18/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-18/</guid><description>&lt;p>Video game Youtube people like &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/JosephAndersonChannel/videos">Joseph Anderson&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/broadcaststsatic">Noah Caldwell-Gervais&lt;/a> (and many others) have been encouraged by the algorithm (and the way Youtube is monetized) to create longer and longer videos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s gotten completely out of hand buuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuut some people seem to be really into it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t see the appeal myself but the numbers don&amp;rsquo;t lie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Noah Caldwell-Gervais&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CZUwmfeHB58">video on the Resident Evil series&lt;/a> has a 7h28min long runtime&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Joseph Anderson&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NtrAx-rVgco">video on the first Witcher game&lt;/a> has a 4h18min runtime and his &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=htYR2GdA7OE">video on the Witcher 2&lt;/a> has a 5h runtime&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>VTOL VR</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-17/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img
 loading="lazy"
 class="img-fluid rounded mx-auto d-block"
 width="600" src="https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-17/1.jpg"/> &lt;em>Perfect Landing!&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I played a few hours of VTOL VR today (streaming the Steam version to my Quest 2 using Virtual Desktop).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve never been super excited about planes and doing bombing runs on tiny white dots (collateral damage anyone?) bbuUuUuuuut I had a ton of fun. Maybe &lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/reviews/2017-09-25/">I just like roleplaying as a terrible person&lt;/a>?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In VTOL VR, you&amp;rsquo;re a pilot of a fully-interactable yet simplified VTOL jet. The cockpit you&amp;rsquo;re in has a ton of fully functioning buttons, levers and joysticks that you use to pilot the jet.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>F*** the haters.</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-14/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-14/</guid><description>&lt;p>Every couple of weeks, my friend L decides that it&amp;rsquo;s time to remind me of the &amp;ldquo;small&amp;rdquo; number of people who actively read the writing I do here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s why I don&amp;rsquo;t care.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re all influenced by a mix of &lt;em>intrinsic&lt;/em> and &lt;em>extrinsic&lt;/em> motivations that determine how we choose to spend our time.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Motivation#Intrinsic_and_extrinsic">Intrinsic motivation&lt;/a> exists within the individual and is driven by satisfying internal rewards rather than relying on external pressures or extrinsic rewards. It involves an interest in or enjoyment of the activity itself. For example, an athlete may enjoy playing football for the experience, rather than for an award.&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Power of Positive Thinking by Vincent B. Clear</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-12/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-12/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The following text is an excerpt from The Power of Positive Thinking™ by Vincent B. Clear.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>What if your thoughts could become reality?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What if you believed hard enough in something, it became true?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Take the next step in your life&amp;rsquo;s journey by learning to harness The Power of Positive Thinking™ to make your life and the lives of those around you, greater than.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My name is Vincent B. Clear. I have a theoretical PhD in positive psychology. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent decades of my life travelling, learning from beacons of ancient wisdom all across the world about the old ways, that most of us have forgotten.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>"That's never happened before" syndrome</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-03/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speedrun">A speedrun is a play-through of a video game performed to complete it as quickly as possible&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://gamesdonequick.com/">Games Done Quick is an organization that runs bi-yearly speedrun events&lt;/a> where hundreds of people gather to speedrun games for a good cause. I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed watching GDQ speedruns for a few years now but up until recently I had never tried speedrunning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the holidays, I played through the physics-based &amp;ldquo;astronaut doing astronauty things&amp;rdquo; game Heavenly Bodies. I played it once by myself, once more with a friend and, over the course of a week, I played all the way through it once or twice a day. I recorded myself playing and I tried to beat the game as fast as I could.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I'm not going to forget The Forgotten City</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-02/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-02/</guid><description>&lt;p>Each day I take off work is a pleasure, but each passing day off increases the sense of dread I feel about having to go back to work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No matter how much I love my job, like most people, I would rather be spending time with family and friends or working on hobbies that tend to be a little more creatively fulfilling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The passage of time is inevitable. Life&amp;rsquo;s short and no one can escape death.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thought Exercise #1</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-01/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-01/</guid><description>&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s a big (but portable) blue button with the word &amp;ldquo;KILL&amp;rdquo; painted on it (called the kill button).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every time you press the button, a human being on the planet dies and X money is added to your bank account.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How much does X have to be for you to press the button? If you would never press the button no matter how much money you get for doing so, explain why.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diary of a Galaxy Conquering Middle Manager</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-31/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-31/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ahhhhhhhhhhhhhhhh I don&amp;rsquo;t want to bathe in the blood of my enemies againnnnnnnnnnn.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Huh.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But, I do it anyway because it&amp;rsquo;s what my boss, my colleagues and my employees expect of me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Keeping up appearances is important when you&amp;rsquo;re leading a horde of fanatics across the galaxy in a quest to conquer and kill everyone and everything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am but a cog in the machine upholding the status quo in charge of killing any living being that steps out of line.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Games I played in 2021</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-26/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-26/</guid><description>&lt;p>Despite getting sucked into Hunt Showdown in a big way this year, I spent less time playing games than I usually do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still, I enjoyed &lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-11-07/">diving into other worlds with the Oculus Quest 2&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-03-21/">quick resuming games on my Xbox Series X&lt;/a> (purchased in desperation after years of wanting to upgrade my PC but not being able to due to shortages) and playing games on the freshly built monster PC I decided to buy anyway.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Movies I watched in 2021</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-22/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-22/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of the movies I loved (and hated) in 2021 in categories that describe how I felt about them (within each category, the ordering is irrelevant).&lt;/p>






&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="movies-i-loved">
&lt;h2>
Movies I loved
 &lt;a href="#movies-i-loved">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>

&lt;p>&lt;img
 loading="lazy"
 class="img-fluid rounded mx-auto d-block"
 width="600" src="https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-22/johnny_mnemonic.jpg"/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Johnny Mnemonic : Keanu Reeves in a business suit going insane in a dystopian cyberpunk world. Keanu&amp;rsquo;s inability to act and William Gibson&amp;rsquo;s inability to write only added to the charm of this movie. : The pile of trash that Johnny stands on when making his speech about wanting &amp;ldquo;room service&amp;rdquo; near the end of the movie represents the movie itself. : I was able to use this pile of trash as a stepping stone to introspect on the disillusionment one can feel as a white-collar worker living in a capitalist dystopia.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Books I read in 2021</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-19/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-19/</guid><description>&lt;p>EDIT: &lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/books">Check out my new /books page where I catalog all the books I&amp;rsquo;ve read since 2021 along with my thoughts about them&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please don&amp;rsquo;t judge me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I haven&amp;rsquo;t read many books this year but I&amp;rsquo;ve read infinitely more than I did last year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I used to read during my daily commute&amp;hellip; One day, I just stopped commuting and so I stopped reading too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This summer, I decided to set aside a bit of time every day to read and here we are. Here&amp;rsquo;s each book I read this year in the order that I read them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TWRP - The Odyssey - Icarus</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-06/</guid><description>&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="tupper-ware-remix-party">
&lt;h1>
Tupper Ware Remix Party
 &lt;a href="#tupper-ware-remix-party">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>

&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t really want to write about Tupper Ware Remix Party.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Writing about music is pain and suffering. Just listen to it, maybe you&amp;rsquo;ll like it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center readable">
 &lt;div class="col-12">
 &lt;div class="d-flex align-items-center justify-content-center">
 &lt;div class="ratio ratio-16x9">
 
 &lt;iframe
 src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/8AFmTwwZOjU?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0"
 allowfullscreen
 >&lt;/iframe>
 
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
 &lt;em>look at those costumes!&lt;/em>&lt;/p>






&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="the-odyssey">
&lt;h1>
The Odyssey
 &lt;a href="#the-odyssey">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>

&lt;p>I just finished reading the Odyssey (translated by Emily Wilson). Odysseus is a mass murderer and a villain&amp;hellip; yet in the story he&amp;rsquo;s presented as a victim and a hero. It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; complex.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting high on Siralim Ultimate</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-29/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-29/</guid><description>&lt;p>Imagine if Pokemon, Final Fantasy and an assortment of your favorite opioids had a baby.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s Siralim Ultimate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a game about building teams of creatures to fight other teams of creatures. And that&amp;rsquo;s it. That&amp;rsquo;s the whole thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why is it so compelling?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You choose a specialization (Monk, Cabalist, Necromancer, etc.), each of which gives you access to a certain set of skills to complement your team of creatures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>It's dead, Jim</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-26/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-26/</guid><description>&lt;p>I can&amp;rsquo;t write a hook for my life right now so I&amp;rsquo;m not even going to try.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="mailto:fuck-off@strategineer.com">If that bothers you, I would love to hear from you.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Giant Bomb has been my primary source for gaming news for a long time. I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to and watching the people who work(ed) there since the early 2000s when they were working at Gamespot. The online personas of people like Jeff Gerstmann, Vinny Caravella, Alex Navarro, Ryan Davis and Brad Shoemaker have been a constant presence for most of my life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Discord bot to play Everyone is John</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-24/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-24/</guid><description>&lt;p>I spent all my free time today &lt;a href="https://github.com/strategineer/discord-bot">working on a discord bot&lt;/a> to help me GM &lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/bin/everyone_is_john">a tabletop roleplaying session of &amp;ldquo;Everyone is John&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> over Discord.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope people have fun!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Game of the Year List Draft</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-23/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-23/</guid><description>&lt;p>Supernatural (Oculus Quest 2) : Fantastic dance + boxing workouts in VR delivered straight to my headset daily with amazing music and movement. Having one of the many fantastic trainers encouraging you during your workout seems cheesy but it actually helps keep me motivated to keep working out. The game is tricking me into thinking that there&amp;rsquo;s someone out there, other than myself, who&amp;rsquo;s invested in my personal wellbeing. It works.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pilk</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-22/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/pilk">Pilk&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>montager: a script to generate Hunt Showdown montages</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-21/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-21/</guid><description>&lt;p>I want to write some python python code that&amp;rsquo;ll take a folder containing Hunt Showdown video highlights generated through Nvidia Highlights (most of which are exactly 25s long) and automatically generate a &amp;ldquo;montage&amp;rdquo; video containing all the highlights combined.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>montager /my_hunt_highlights/
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>I would like the code to analyze each video, and using one of several different algorithms, and detect which parts of the video are interesting and clip those parts out before combining all the clips together.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Footnotes</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-19/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a test.&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now I can add footnotes to my essays to make myself seem 100x more intelligent (or obnoxious).&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1">
&lt;p>How does this look?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How about this.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This&lt;/li>
&lt;li>That&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Potato&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Embeds, embeds, embeds</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-18/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-18/</guid><description>&lt;p>I wrote some code to help me embed audio files into my blog posts easily&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center readable">
 &lt;div class="d-flex align-items-center justify-content-center">
 &lt;figure>
 &lt;audio controls src="https://strategineer.com/bin/music/TheThird.wav">
 Your browser does not support the
 &lt;code>audio&lt;/code> element.
 &lt;/audio>
 &lt;/figure>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
 &lt;em>Here&amp;rsquo;s a song I produced about 5 years ago. It&amp;rsquo;s a decent &amp;ldquo;bop&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wrote some more code to help me embed video files into my blog posts easily&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;div class="ratio ratio-16x9">
 &lt;video controls>
 &lt;source src="./Thomas_The_Robot.mp4" />
 Sorry, your browser doesn't support embedded videos.
 &lt;/video>
&lt;/div>
 &lt;em>Here&amp;rsquo;s a video of a robot character I modeled and animated myself in Java a long time ago in a university far, far away&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>4 chill beats to work to</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-16/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-16/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://nervoustestpilot.co.uk/">nervoustestpilot&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://macross82-99.bandcamp.com/">Macross 82-99&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Panchiko">Panchiko&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.lukhash.com/">LukHash&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I feel like my productivity gets boosted substantially if I&amp;rsquo;m listening to the right kind of music music?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or maybe &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/worklife/article/20200317-does-music-help-us-work-it-depends">listening to good music makes me happy (and more productive)?&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or maybe I decide to listen to music when I&amp;rsquo;m happy and I&amp;rsquo;m already being more productive than usual because I&amp;rsquo;m happy?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Writing #1</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-15/</guid><description>&lt;p>My bars are low, almost completely drained. But here I am, back again for more. Doing exactly what I do everyday. Typing words on my computer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m a programmer by day, a writer by night. I&amp;rsquo;m a much better programmer than I am a writer. If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever worked with me, you may or may not disagree. I would love to live in a world where writing was my job and programming was my hobby. Writing well consistently is challenging for me and that&amp;rsquo;s what I love and hate about it. From what I&amp;rsquo;ve heard (and read), it seems like this is a feeling shared by a lot of other writers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ABCs #3</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-11/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img
 loading="lazy"
 class="img-fluid rounded mx-auto d-block"
 width="600" alt="chicken pot pie" src="https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-11/chicken_pot_pie.jpg"/>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Alcohol, being crushed, dull every freedom&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gobble hetero immaturity&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Juggle KKK, layman money night&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obsession perverted, quest running stop&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Toppling ultimatum vampiress&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Win xenon, yodeling, zigzaggedness&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Alps, butt cool, dying ebb&amp;rsquo;n flow, guttural&lt;/p>
&lt;p>High-minded imagination, jester&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kind laugh, movement, nagging, ovulation&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pressure quacking, rocking silence, taken&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Underground venomous, woman, xanthic&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yarovizations, zombifications&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>All beta cucks, dick egress, fuckers got&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hitting it, jerking kick, losers meeting&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ABCs #2</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ale brought chaos, down everywhere fortune&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gaze him into jab, kill love man-of-war&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neither of prison, quarter rocky stone&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tainted undulation vain waifs XoX&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yuppification. Zygophyllaceous.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ABCs #1</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-09/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-09/</guid><description>&lt;p>All being cool, do everything flying&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Get high, inhale juvenile karmic love&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Make naan on pan? question rhetorical&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sink too, under veil waves, xeric you zombie&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Odyssey Book 1-7: Two Soy Boy Beta Cucks becoming men (again)</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-08/</guid><description>&lt;p>The story of the Odyssey begins with Telemachus, the son of Odysseus, being a soy boy beta cuck. The men vying for the hand of his mother Penelope treat him like shit. Odysseus&amp;rsquo;s long absence has created a power vacuum in Ithaca and many suitors are now waiting in line to court and wed Penelope.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Telemachus attempts to become less of a soy boy beta cuck by becoming more of a misogynist and treating his exceptionally beautiful and intelligent mother like crap.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I made spicy shrimp tacos today</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-07/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-07/</guid><description>&lt;p>I &lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/food/shrimp_tacos">made this&lt;/a> today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was good.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Inline images with captions</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-06/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-06/</guid><description>&lt;p>I took me years of writing about video games (a visual medium) on here before I finally decided it was about time to make it easy for me to insert images with optional captions into my blog posts&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, here you go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is some text before the image.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img
 loading="lazy"
 class="img-fluid rounded mx-auto d-block"
 width="600" alt="an awful picture dark and stormy cocktail" src="https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-06/depression.jpg"/> &lt;em>testing the caption&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is some text after the image.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It took me about 30min to get this to work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cocktails #1</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-04/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-04/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s an ordered list of all the cocktails I&amp;rsquo;ve tried since I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten into mixology from my most favorite to least favorite:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/cocktails/dark_and_stormy/">Dark and Stormy&lt;/a> : Ginger beer combined with rum, garnished with lime. The &amp;ldquo;dark&amp;rdquo; part of the Dark and Stormy refers to the color but the &amp;ldquo;stormy&amp;rdquo; part refers to the storm of flavors this cocktail creates in your mouth. I&amp;rsquo;ve been told that the key is to buy (or make) high quality ginger beer. I made my Dark and Stormy with Fever Tree ginger beer and it was great.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sleep</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-03/</guid><description>&lt;p>I forgot to set my alarm last night, so I woke up 2h after I was expecting to and that&amp;rsquo;s thrown off my entire day. I can&amp;rsquo;t fix this by going to sleep 2h later than usual because I want to get a good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep and I want to wake up at my usual time (6:30am).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So here I am, living through a day that&amp;rsquo;s shorter than it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be. And yet, I still want to do everything I had initially planned to do but I&amp;rsquo;m not going to be able to. Well, what can you do? I&amp;rsquo;ll remember to set my alarm today and I&amp;rsquo;ll try to do as much as I can.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cutting my own hair</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-02/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been cutting my own hair for the past few years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A decent hair trimmer costs as much as a single haircut. If you can learn how to cut your own hair with one then you can save a little time and money.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If you&amp;rsquo;re looking to give yourself a buzzcut then buy yourself a hair trimmer and enjoy saving yourself time and money by cutting your own hair.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I don&amp;rsquo;t like the way buzzcuts look on me so I need to do a little more work.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cutting my own hair well is hard. But it didn&amp;rsquo;t take me many haircuts to learn how to do it semi-competently.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cutting my hair right before I&amp;rsquo;m expecting to appear in public is a big mistake. I need to wait a day or two for my hair to grow out a little to cover up any of the mistakes I&amp;rsquo;ve made near the ears and back of the neck.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Except for my first haircut or two (which were so questionable that people commented on it), nobody has noticed that I cut my own hair.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>But, people have yet to really be wowed by my haircuts&amp;hellip; If you want to look extremely sexy for a few days after you cut your hair, there&amp;rsquo;s no shortcut. Go to a professional and pray they don&amp;rsquo;t fuck it up.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I cut my hair in one of two ways:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Generic Short Haircut (very short hair at neck level, short hair at ear level and longer hair on top of my head).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Generic Short Alternative Haircut (same thing except a little more hair on top, think mini Pompadour).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>These hair styles are nothing special but at least I don&amp;rsquo;t look like a Neo-Nazi.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>A (work)day in the life</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-01/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>6:30am.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wake up. It&amp;rsquo;s still dark outside. I sit on the toilet bowl and piss. I get up and walk over to my closet. I pull out some socks, pajama pants or shorts depending on the weather and a polo shirt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I get dressed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I walk over to my living room. I take my phone off its wireless charger and check to see if I received any messages in the middle of the night (probably not). I take my water bottle and fill it up with future piss if I need to.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>You're a Rift Wizard, Harry!</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-09-05/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-09-05/</guid><description>&lt;p>Rift Wizard is a &lt;a href="http://roguebasin.com/index.php/What_a_roguelike_is">traditional roguelike&lt;/a> (a turn-based procedurally generated dungeon crawler) that doubles down on the fantasy of being a wizard with a hefty leather-bound spell book at your fingertips, a legion of minions under your control and mastery over ALL of the elements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want that? A lot of video game marketing tells you that you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to become a Really Cool Mage™ if you play Our Really Cool Magic Game™&amp;hellip; but they&amp;rsquo;re lying to you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Writing... It's a Process</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-04-09/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-04-09/</guid><description>&lt;p>On and off, since early 2017, I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing about the video games I play. I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved video games and writing so it seemed like a good idea to write about video games for fun. I got into the habit of writing concise reviews for most of the video games I played. I would play through a game from start to finish, pick out the juiciest parts of the experience, write about it in about 200 words and post the review to Steam. &lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/reviews/">I&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded them here if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in taking a look&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Political Video Game: Suzerain</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-04-05/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-04-05/</guid><description>&lt;p>Suzerain is a text-based role-playing game where you play as President Anton Rayne leading the fictional country of Sordland in a political drama driven by conversations with your cabinet members and other significant people. The decisions you make will determine the future of Sordland and of its people, how will you lead?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Suzerain is a narrative-driven game. Playing the game involves reading a lot of dialog, news articles, biographies of people and more. All of this text serves to immerse you in the political world of Sordland. Using its writing, Suzerain does everything it can to convince you that the people of Sordland are as real as you are.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The PC master race is over: the Xbox Series X won</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-03-21/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-03-21/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I spent a lot of money purchasing an Xbox Series X. I&amp;rsquo;m encouraged to rationalize my purchases to make myself feel less bad about spending money on luxury instead hiding it away for a rainy day when I&amp;rsquo;m older and more broken than I am today. As always, I write honestly but, given the circumstances, take anything I say here with a grain of salt.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of an understatement to say that I was introduced to video games at a young age. Somehow, I got my tiny little baby hands on a copy of Doom. Soon enough, I was blasting away at hordes of demons with high powered weaponry. I&amp;rsquo;m not surprised that my younger more impressionable self became so engrossed in video games, as you know, I think some of them are quite compelling.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Social Deduction through Text Chat in Untrusted</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-03-15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-03-15/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been lucky during these uncertain times to have been able to keep in touch with my close friends and forge new relationships through the internet. I&amp;rsquo;ve been in lockdown for most of this past year and because I live alone, I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a lot more text chatting than before in a mildly successful attempt to stay sane.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a love-hate relationship with text chatting. It makes it really easy to keep in touch with the people you care about. But, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to misinterpret messages, tone is sometimes lost and it&amp;rsquo;s hard to be subtle or sarcastic through text chat.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Time to Die in Risk of Rain 2</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-02-04/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-02-04/</guid><description>&lt;p>Time always moves forward whether you like it or not. In the blink of an eye, the present becomes the past and the future becomes the present. Every moment spent standing still is a moment not spent moving forward. We&amp;rsquo;ve all been standing still for far too long, until we can move around again, let me tell you about a game where you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to stop moving.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Risk of Rain 2 is a game that forces you to come to terms with the passage of time. Each decision you make has to be evaluated against the time it&amp;rsquo;ll take to follow through with it combined with the expected value of the rewards you&amp;rsquo;ll get.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Beware the God Killer in Yoku's Island Express</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-01-18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-01-18/</guid><description>&lt;p>Time stood still as a new kind of old evil ravages the world as we know it, freezing us in time and space, while we clutch our crosses in fear. Sadly, God is dead and we killed him. In a time of unprecedented irrationality, ignorance and stupidity, it&amp;rsquo;s been difficult for me to stay sane in these trying times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It may or may not be too late for our world. Only time will tell. In the meantime, I plan to stay sane by escaping (responsibly) into worlds that are less fractured and absurd than our own.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Piloting and Tinkering in Ring Runner</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-12-31/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-12-31/</guid><description>&lt;p>Nowadays, I lower my expectations as low as they can possibly go before playing a new video game. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ve been disappointed one too many times or maybe I&amp;rsquo;m a pessimist. Either way, because I set the bar so low, when an amazing game falls into my lap, it gives me energy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the short time I&amp;rsquo;ve spent with it, I&amp;rsquo;ve fallen in love with Ring Runner: Flight of the Sages. It&amp;rsquo;s a real tragedy that you probably haven&amp;rsquo;t heard about it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Good games I played in 2020</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-12-27/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-12-27/</guid><description>&lt;p>2020 was definitely a year, but 2021 is just around the corner. I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the opportunity to do much else other than play games this year which is a silver lining that I don&amp;rsquo;t want to take for granted. I&amp;rsquo;ve never before had the time to play as many good games as I have this year. Without further ado, here are my favourite games I&amp;rsquo;ve played this year in no particular order (&lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-01-17/">You can read my 2019 GOTY list here&lt;/a>).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Valve, Steam and You</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-11-15/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-11-15/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re a PC gamer in 2020 then chances are you use Steam as one of your platforms of choice to purchase PC games. You might not know that Valve, the people behind Steam and many beloved game series such as Half Life, Portal, Left 4 Dead, Counter Strike, and more, have been taking a 30% cut off of every game sold on their platform for a little over a decade.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ready, Set, VR?</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-11-07/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-11-07/</guid><description>&lt;p>Virtual reality. Everyone should get a chance to put a headset on because it&amp;rsquo;s unlike anything I&amp;rsquo;ve ever experienced before. Modern VR headsets have been available for more than half a decade and yet not many people own one or have had the luxury of trying one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was, and unfortunately I still am, an early adopter of VR. I owned an HTC Vive headset a couple years ago, I sold it. I bought an Oculus Rift S soon after, I sold it. I just bought the recently released Oculus Quest 2 and I might just keep this one.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moving Out, Growing In</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-10-24/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-10-24/</guid><description>&lt;p>Moving out of my childhood home to live on my own was going to be tough. I realized this as I rolled out of the U-Haul truck with a piece of toast in one hand and my hopes and dreams in the other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I moved out of my family&amp;rsquo;s place a little more than a year ago. In the time since, I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced a lot, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned and I&amp;rsquo;ve grown. Given that I&amp;rsquo;ve just moved out again somewhere new, why not reflect on the time that I spent living away from my family and share that with you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chronic Pain and HUGE Trackballs</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-10-11/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-10-11/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>WARNING: If you&amp;rsquo;ve got pain in your body, listen to it. If you&amp;rsquo;re a big Gamer, please take breaks and play responsibly. Video games are wonderful but they aren&amp;rsquo;t worth destroying your mind and body over playing them, or making them. You&amp;rsquo;ll thank me later.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I recently started using an ELECOM HUGE trackball mouse. Trackball mice are an alternative to traditional mice. Instead of moving the mouse around, you rotate a ball that&amp;rsquo;s fixed in place (the trackball) using your fingers which then moves the mouse cursor on the screen.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Baby's First 3D Models for Printing</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-10-04/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-10-04/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking of buying a 3D printer&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;ve always been interested in but until recently I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the space for it. The consumer 3D printing world has gotten a lot cheaper and simpler to get into in recent years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In preparation for that I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with OpenSCAD. It&amp;rsquo;s a CAD (Computer-aided design) program which, according to &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer-aided_design">Wikipedia&lt;/a>, is a computer program used to aid in the creation, modification, analysis or optimization of a design.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Power Fantasies, Environments in LoG 2</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-09-28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-09-28/</guid><description>&lt;p>The world around us is mysterious, magnificent and beautiful. It&amp;rsquo;s a living breathing ecosystem with an internal logic of its own. Mother Nature, and Father Concrete, represent the interwoven complexity held within the environments that we live in and explore.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the real world, the environments we inhabit can be quite uninteresting, but anything is possible in a video game.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing Legend of Grimrock 2 recently. I&amp;rsquo;m having a wonderful time, because the environment is more than just a place where gameplay happens, it IS the gameplay.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Second Coming of Rust</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-09-19/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-09-19/</guid><description>&lt;p>In these UNCERTAIN TIMES, I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself with a little more free time than usual because I haven&amp;rsquo;t needed to commute to an office every day. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to funnel that energy into creative and constructive hobbies. Keyword: &lt;em>tried&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the past week, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent some of that time learning the Rust programming language. I&amp;rsquo;ve heard a lot of good things about it and I finally took the plunge. Here&amp;rsquo;s a couple of notable features that I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to grok from my brief time with it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My favorite games of the past, present and future</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-09-13/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-09-13/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello fellow human.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been quite busy this week, I&amp;rsquo;ve been focusing a lot of my free time on modding, making changes to an existing game, of a newly released game which I&amp;rsquo;ve been pouring a lot of time into given how good it is (I&amp;rsquo;ll mention it later on).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today will be a little less formal (that&amp;rsquo;s just a nicer way of me saying that it&amp;rsquo;ll be a little more half-assed than usual). In the text below, I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the first ever video game I played, my favorite game I played this year, a game I&amp;rsquo;m currently playing and, finally, my favorite game of all time (thank you to the person who posted these questions, they were fun to think about).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hunt, Showdown, Repeat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-09-04/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-09-04/</guid><description>&lt;p>You are a bounty hunter dredging through demon-infested Louisiana swamps in an alternate timeline of our 1895 but with some anachronisms thrown in. You need to find, then kill a demonic monster and, finally, leave the swamp as quickly as you can. Problem is… You&amp;rsquo;re not alone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You better hope to God that you brought the right weapons and that you&amp;rsquo;re not caught off guard by other bounty hunters. One mistake and not only will you be going home empty handed; you&amp;rsquo;ll be returning to your friends and family in a coffin.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Gamer's Guide to: Cheating in Single-Player Games</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-08-30/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-08-30/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to my second &amp;ldquo;A Gamer&amp;rsquo;s Guide to&amp;rdquo; blog post (check out my &lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-08-22/">previous one on online multiplayer video games&lt;/a>). I&amp;rsquo;ll be explaining how you can cheat in single-player games on PC. If you&amp;rsquo;re feeling like a rebel then take a seat and prepare to bask in the glow of infinite health, infinite currency and infinity itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Feel free to use the techniques that I describe below at your own risk, I don&amp;rsquo;t advise cheating in any game that is a live service, is online in any way, has leaderboards or has micro-transactions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Gamer's Guide to: Online Multiplayer</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-08-22/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-08-22/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to my first &amp;ldquo;A Gamer&amp;rsquo;s Guide to…&amp;rdquo;. This series of articles will cover a wide range of topics of interest to gamers from the perspective of a video game programmer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I know a little about what goes into making a video game. I gained a wide breadth of knowledge of every part of a video game including game engines, physics, gameplay, audio, AI, C++ (shiver) and more in my studies. In 2016, I was hired by an independent game studio, Borealys Games, to work on Mages of Mystralia as one of two programmers. Mages is a Zelda-like game where you find magical runes which you can combine to create your own spells to solve puzzles and fight enemies. After shipping the game and working on a cancelled project, I went on to Framestore VR where we built high-end VR experiences for installation in amusement parks (amusement parks in 2020, LOL). I&amp;rsquo;m not working in the video game industry anymore because making games is really hard and it&amp;rsquo;s not hard in a way that I enjoy. However, I&amp;rsquo;m as passionate about video games as ever. I just need to find other outlets for my love of video games, like writing about them!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>You can always reload, until you can't</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-08-16/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-08-16/</guid><description>&lt;p>Most games don&amp;rsquo;t matter. The actions you play out within most games don&amp;rsquo;t have any long term impact on you as a player. Some narrative games imply that the choices you make have an impact on the world but given that the world is imaginary, does it really matter? Some RPGs force you into making decisions that change the world or your characters but&amp;hellip; You can always press F8 and reload.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interviews - The Good, the Bad and the Ugly</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-06-26/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-06-26/</guid><description>&lt;p>Looking for a job sucks. A couple of months ago, I was going through interview after interview like a wrecking ball blasting through concrete. No buildings were destroyed in the process but I may have burned some bridges along the way. We laughed, we cried, it was roller coaster of emotions and then I got a job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s a blow-by-blow review of the interviews I went through. I&amp;rsquo;ve reflected on each interview and coupled each with recommendations for you if you are or are planning to go through a similar interview process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Game of the Year List for 2019</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-01-17/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2020-01-17/</guid><description>&lt;p>I love video games. I&amp;rsquo;ve loved them almost my entire life. I loved them enough to make making them my job. I&amp;rsquo;m not working in video game development anymore but I still enjoy playing games and pondering over them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of the video games I played in 2019 which I enjoyed the most (in no particular order).&lt;/p>






&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="trials-rising">
&lt;h1>
Trials Rising
 &lt;a href="#trials-rising">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>

&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://strategineer.com/reviews/2019-03-13/">my video review of Trials Rising&lt;/a> which I wrote and recorded earlier this year during my extended break from employment (don&amp;rsquo;t expect any more reviews to come where that came from).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Warhammer 40k - a Blast from the Past</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2019-08-28/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2019-08-28/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently dove head first into the world of Warhammer 40k. A dark and edgy tabletop game born in the 80s played with many miniature models of science fiction soldiers, aliens, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;ve heard of space orks (generic fantasy orcs thrust forty thousand years into the future) who paint their ships red because it makes them go faster (their belief makes it so) or about an immortal Emperor sending genetically modified soldiers all over the universe to defeat the forces of Chaos then that&amp;rsquo;s Warhammer 40k.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I code review an 8 year old project</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2019-06-12/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2019-06-12/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the first projects I worked on after learning how to program, around 8 years ago, is called &lt;a href="https://github.com/KeikakuB/writerator/tree/legacy">writerator&lt;/a>. It is a Python command line interface (or CLI for short) for analyzing English language text and generating randomized poetry such as haikus and poems. I was contemplating using it to build a new side project which would analyze text from all over the internet from the previous day (news articles, Twitter posts, etc.), then generate a new short poem every day using the words from the analyzed text and post it to Twitter.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a website for 17$ or less</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2019-06-08/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2019-06-08/</guid><description>&lt;p>The website you&amp;rsquo;re reading this on was built by myself and it cost me a total of 17$ CDN (yearly). Without a custom domain it would have cost me nothing, zilch, nada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My goal for this website was to create my own space on the internet to allow me to easily share the software engineering work I&amp;rsquo;ve done, share the writing I do on video games and encourage me to write about other topics that interest me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Influencing the odds inside and outside of Blood Bowl 2</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2019-05-07/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2019-05-07/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Blood Bowl 2 smashes Warhammer and American football together, in an explosive cocktail of turn-based strategy, humour and brutality, adapted from Games Workshop&amp;rsquo;s famous board game.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d be hard pressed to come up with a better brief description of what Blood Bowl is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Blood Bowl, you take on the role of a coach leading and managing a team playing an extremely violent mockery of American football. During a match, two teams try to carry one ball from one end of the pitch to the other but the similarities between football and Blood Bowl end there.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The website, Mortal Kombat 11 and microtransactions</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2019-04-24/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2019-04-24/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on my website (the one you&amp;rsquo;re currently on, I should probably put a &amp;ldquo;work-in-progress&amp;rdquo; sign up&amp;hellip;). Work has been going well so far. I had done most of the &amp;lsquo;setting everything up&amp;rsquo; for the site a year and a half ago before I was employed by Framestore VR.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently begun working on the project again, and the work has been going according to plan. I was expecting to spend the whole day working on on the website yesterday however Mortal Kombat 11&amp;rsquo;s story mode and juicy gameplay got in the way.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>