<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Slavic on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/tags/slavic/</link><description>Recent content in Slavic on Strat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 13:35:25 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/books/tags/slavic/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>We</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-14/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-14/</guid><description>&lt;p>The much more interesting but lesser known dystopian novel that inspired George Orwell&amp;rsquo;s 1984.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not as prophetic as Aldous Huxley&amp;rsquo;s Brave New World but it&amp;rsquo;s more consistently well written and has mostly aged better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s more open to interpretation than I was expecting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Roadside Picnic</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-03/</guid><description>I love the S.T.A.L.K.E.R. games! Especially the third one. It&amp;rsquo;s a game I always come back to over the years.
Over the many years since the game&amp;rsquo;s were abandoned, fans took up the mantle and continued developing the games, creating a new version of the engine, putting all of the series&amp;rsquo;s maps together and making everything moddable.
The GAMMA mod pack for S.T.A.L.K.E.R. which I&amp;rsquo;ve played recently is fantastic and the best realization of the S.</description></item><item><title>The Futurological Congress</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-13/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-13/</guid><description>Stanislaw Lem pops off once again. I&amp;rsquo;m blown away at how he can integrate all these disparate emotions and ideas into one novel. He did a similar thing for me with Solaris.
This book is very scary for how funny the first part of it is. The horror caught me by surprise which elevated its effect on me.
I&amp;rsquo;m interested in reading more of his work!</description></item><item><title>Solaris</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-11/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-11/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fantastic genre-bending sci-fi.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My mind&amp;rsquo;s eye has never been very good so I rarely latch on to descriptions of the spaces that characters find themselves in. But, the descriptions of Solaris&amp;rsquo;s space station and the planet it&amp;rsquo;s orbiting were so vivid and interesting that it elevated the story for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The space station&amp;rsquo;s color scheme of white combined with stripes of vibrant colors lit by the alternating blue and red hues of the system&amp;rsquo;s both suns was breathtaking.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>