<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>LoBG on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/</link><description>Recent content in LoBG on Strat</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GMing Aid</title><link>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/gming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/gming/</guid><description>Bangs ¶ Ashen Chanterelle encounters PCs: she tries to escape from her chains through any means and escape through the painting, locking the PCs in the LoBG. Lady Crucem Capilli encounters PCs: she provides context on the LoBG and sends the PCs off to acquire art, artifacts or curios for her in exchange for handsome rewards. Chameleon Women encounter/discover PCs: they begin to gain strength, increasing HD with each subsequent encounter, and begin to inform the other denizens of the LoBG about the PCs actions if this would turn the NPCs against the PCs.</description></item><item><title>Session Notes</title><link>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/session_notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/session_notes/</guid><description> Session 0 ¶ Session 1 ¶ The group should gives themselves a name and this is what they&amp;rsquo;ll be known as in the dungeon.</description></item><item><title>Intro</title><link>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/intro/</guid><description>TLDR - what is the LoBG? to be revealed by early NPCs (like Lady Crucem Capilli) ¶ an Escheresque and irrational labyrinth, created by the Blue Goron, Illyria, to store the many strange and useful items (Lady Crucem Capilli is interested in these) she&amp;rsquo;s collected throughout her aons of life and as an escape from her many terminally angry enemies. The Elephant King -&amp;gt; Rise of the Reptile Empire -&amp;gt; The brutal Triarchy rises with power of the Three Perfect Sisters -&amp;gt; Fall of the Reptile Empire -&amp;gt; Ashen Chanterelle breaks her way into the Maze but is imprisoned in a painting formed from her own portal -&amp;gt; stairs leading to the LoBG on Eliator treated as a kind of afterlife -&amp;gt; (a few hours ago) Lady Crucem Capilli enters the halls -&amp;gt; PCs enter the halls.</description></item><item><title>House Rules</title><link>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/house_rules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/house_rules/</guid><description>When creating PCs, each one must be linked another character in some way (siblings? childhood friends? colleagues?). Ideally, each should be able to describe one memorable moment that occurred between them. PC death timers (1d4 + CON modifier rounds, min. 1), are kept secret by the GM from all players until another PC checks their pulse or tries to heal or stabilize them. Luck tokens are lost if not used at the end of every session.</description></item><item><title>Ideas</title><link>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/ideas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/ideas/</guid><description>NPCs ¶ Renamed NPCs ¶ The Blue Medusa, Psathyrella -&amp;gt; The Blue Gorgon, Illyria the collector ¶ tall gangly slender man with custom fit suit All he wants is something to remember this encounter by, he&amp;rsquo;ll take it by force if needed.
Secrets &amp;amp; Clues &amp;hellip; not sure about these ¶ The mage who hires the crew initially to steal the painting is actually Lady Crucem Capilli. She&amp;rsquo;s put a geas on the party compelling them to venture forth into the LoBG to help her achieve her goal of buying and preserving artifacts of many different kinds and to have people investigate the Maze, retrieve these for her, and bring back information.</description></item><item><title>TODO</title><link>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/todo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/todo/</guid><description> create 5min intro to the shadowdark system for session 0, using cheatsheet</description></item></channel></rss>