<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>LoBG on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/</link><description>Recent content in LoBG on Strat</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GMing Aid</title><link>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/gming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/gming/</guid><description>&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="session-notes">
&lt;h1>
Session Notes
 &lt;a href="#session-notes">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>

&lt;p>Negamancer escaped! he&amp;rsquo;ll be back&lt;/p>






&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="learning-rolls">
&lt;h1>
Learning rolls
 &lt;a href="#learning-rolls">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>

&lt;p>Marlon tried to learn flanking/dnd backstab using range weapons: tried once
Freeya tried to learn how to heal people using Marlon&amp;rsquo;s Staff of Healing: tried once&lt;/p>






&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="bangs">
&lt;h1>
Bangs
 &lt;a href="#bangs">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>

&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;del>&lt;a href="#ashen-chanterelle">Ashen Chanterelle&lt;/a> encounters PCs: she tries to escape from her chains through any means and escape through the painting, locking the PCs in the LoBG.&lt;/del>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;del>&lt;a href="#lady-crucem-capilli">Lady Crucem Capilli&lt;/a> encounters PCs: she provides context on the LoBG and sends the PCs off to acquire art, artifacts or curios for her in exchange for handsome rewards.&lt;/del>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;del>&lt;a href="#chameleon-woman">Chameleon Women&lt;/a> encounter/discover PCs: they begin to gain strength, increasing HD with each subsequent encounter, and begin to inform the other denizens of the LoBG about the PCs actions if this would turn the NPCs against the PCs.&lt;/del>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;del>Lanmino disappears&amp;hellip; [see following]&lt;/del>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;del>Marlon finds a letter in his Cloak of Avoidance from L.G. &amp;ldquo;Marlon, my dear friend and ally, enjoy this cloak I found just for you. Use it well! PS. I have dire need of your &amp;ldquo;friend&amp;rdquo; Lanmino and I will be taking him for now. Yours truly, L.G.&amp;quot;&lt;/del>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Freeya finds an occult tarot deck used by the Chameleon women to summon demons and begins using it himself. Anyone can pull a card from the deck once per day and summon a demon but a charisma/spellcasting check must be done to compel the demon to help them instead of hindering the summonner.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>PCs encounter &lt;a href="#bondye-reparat%C3%A8">Bondye Reparatè&lt;/a> cleaning up and removing the corpses of Brod&amp;rsquo;s previous adventuring party (Brod comes from the same place they come from), they scould Brod for his behaviour pointing to his dead companions for defiling this sacred place: they will guide the PCs to &lt;a href="#lady-nine-bones">Lady Nine-Bones&lt;/a> (Halls 17) and/or straight to Elatior, a safehaven where the party can rest and recover between expeditions into the LoBG. Brod can figure out who he used to be and choose to investigate there if desired.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>PCs enter Vinebeasts + Heart room. A theaticral spotlight shines on a PC, everyone else is frozen in place while the &amp;ldquo;scene&amp;rdquo; plays out. The PC will respond to the accusations of the vinebeasts and when they have no responses left or when it feels right, the spotlight will shift to another PC.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>PCs find a book, probably &lt;a href="#table---random-books">generated with the following table&lt;/a> (See following bullet point, books are art).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>PCs damage/steal art: &lt;a href="#the-curator">The Curator&lt;/a> (big hand thing) becomes aware of them and begins to hound them. Blotbug and Brod must resist commenting on art otherwise they become more (cannibal) critical of them.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The &lt;a href="#oku">&amp;ldquo;Oku&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> encounter PCs: &amp;hellip;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>(1 month after PCs enter the LoBG): &lt;a href="#ashen-chanterelle">Ashen Chanterelle&lt;/a> will re-enter with a small group of members from the Cult of the Shattered Moon with the intention of persuading Chronia, Zamia and Charity to enter the world once more. The Medusa will oppose this. The Cult&amp;rsquo;s goal in entering the Labyrinth is to find Blotbug and sacrifice him.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The group meet with L.G., the supervillain who knows everything that will happen and is using the group to defeat his frenemy the Blue Gorgon.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If the PCs exit from the Labyrinth through the painting, they come out in the same place where they came in from but thousands of years later (time passes slowly in the Labyrinth compared to the other world) in a Dying Earth-style combined with weird fantasy / gonzo genre-mish-mashing (refer to Dark Sun and Anomalous Subsurface Environment for context). This world is sparsely populated by small settlements of rural/Western-style people and ruled by remnants of the Cult of the Moon (which shattered but was pieced back together through advanced technology which has since been lost) found in towers and broken down astrology labs throughout the land.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>






&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="dungeon-key">
&lt;h1>
Dungeon Key
 &lt;a href="#dungeon-key">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>







&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="halls-1">
&lt;h2>
Halls 1
 &lt;a href="#halls-1">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>

&lt;p>The Crew is using this area as a resting place and storage area (they dragged a chest all the way over here).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Session Notes</title><link>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/session_notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/session_notes/</guid><description>&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="session-0">
&lt;h1>
Session 0
 &lt;a href="#session-0">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>







&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="session-1">
&lt;h1>
Session 1
 &lt;a href="#session-1">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>

&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The group should gives themselves a name and this is what they&amp;rsquo;ll be known as in the dungeon.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Intro</title><link>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/intro/</guid><description>&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="tldr---what-is-the-lobg-to-be-revealed-by-early-npcs-like-lady-crucem-capilli">
&lt;h1>
TLDR - what is the LoBG? to be revealed by early NPCs (like Lady Crucem Capilli)
 &lt;a href="#tldr---what-is-the-lobg-to-be-revealed-by-early-npcs-like-lady-crucem-capilli">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>

&lt;ul>
&lt;li>an Escheresque and irrational labyrinth, created by the Blue Goron, Illyria, to store the many strange and useful items (Lady Crucem Capilli is interested in these) she&amp;rsquo;s collected throughout her aons of life and as an escape from her many terminally angry enemies.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Elephant King -&amp;gt; Rise of the Reptile Empire -&amp;gt; The brutal Triarchy rises with power of the Three Perfect Sisters -&amp;gt; Fall of the Reptile Empire -&amp;gt; Ashen Chanterelle breaks her way into the Maze but is imprisoned in a painting formed from her own portal -&amp;gt; stairs leading to the LoBG on Eliator treated as a kind of afterlife -&amp;gt; (a few hours ago) Lady Crucem Capilli enters the halls -&amp;gt; PCs enter the halls.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A remnant of a long-gone civilization, the Triarchy, ruled three perfect sisters, Chronia, Charity, Zamia Torn, betrayed by a few obsessives in their empire leading to the world falling into bloody chaos, slightly worse than the bloody order provided by their government.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>House Rules</title><link>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/house_rules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/house_rules/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>When creating PCs, each one must be linked another character in some way (siblings? childhood friends? colleagues?). Ideally, each should be able to describe one memorable moment that occurred between them.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>PC death timers (1d4 + CON modifier rounds, min. 1), are kept secret by the GM from all players until another PC checks their pulse or tries to heal or stabilize them.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Luck tokens are lost if not used at the end of every session. However, players can gain a luck token for the next session by providing the GM with their feedback for the session in the form of &lt;a href="#stars-and-wishes">Stars and Wishes&lt;/a> at the end of each session.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>






&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="stars-and-wishes">
&lt;h2>
Stars and Wishes
 &lt;a href="#stars-and-wishes">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>

&lt;p>&lt;strong>Stars&lt;/strong> are simple: Every involved person shall point to one item, person, or incident that they really enjoyed during the session. It could be &amp;ldquo;I really loved how you portrayed that Rat-Chaos-Mutant&amp;rsquo;s speech, GM-Bob.&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Christy, your Barbarian was so cool when she burst through the door yelling bloody murder.&amp;rdquo; Just name something that you really enjoyed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ideas</title><link>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/ideas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/ideas/</guid><description>&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="npcs">
&lt;h1>
NPCs
 &lt;a href="#npcs">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>







&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="renamed-npcs">
&lt;h2>
Renamed NPCs
 &lt;a href="#renamed-npcs">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>

&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The Blue Medusa, Psathyrella -&amp;gt; The Blue Gorgon, Illyria&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>






&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="the-collector">
&lt;h2>
the collector
 &lt;a href="#the-collector">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>

&lt;p>tall gangly slender man with custom fit suit
All he wants is something to remember this encounter by, he&amp;rsquo;ll take it by force if needed.&lt;/p>






&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="secrets--clues--not-sure-about-these">
&lt;h1>
Secrets &amp;amp; Clues &amp;hellip; not sure about these
 &lt;a href="#secrets--clues--not-sure-about-these">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>

&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The mage who hires the crew initially to steal the painting is actually Lady Crucem Capilli. She&amp;rsquo;s put a geas on the party compelling them to venture forth into the LoBG to help her achieve her goal of buying and preserving artifacts of many different kinds and to have people investigate the Maze, retrieve these for her, and bring back information.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Anyone who&amp;rsquo;s been put into contact with the painting can&amp;rsquo;t:&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Leave the city of Astergrave (they turn back at the edge of the urban area and return to whatever they were doing previously, short-term amnesia is likely).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>They can&amp;rsquo;t talk to anyone about the painting unless they also know about the painting (the first and second rules of Fight Club).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;ol start="3">
&lt;li>The man, Sir August the Great, who&amp;rsquo;s private collection used to contain the painting might want it back, if the crew starts acting weird in the city maybe he&amp;rsquo;ll find them. He just likes the painting, he doesn&amp;rsquo;t know that it&amp;rsquo;s actually a portal into another world.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;hellip;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>TODO</title><link>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/todo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/lobg/todo/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>create 5min intro to the shadowdark system for session 0, using cheatsheet&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>