<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DNF on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/tags/dnf/</link><description>Recent content in DNF on Strat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 02:25:12 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/books/tags/dnf/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ancient Legends, Mystic Charms and Superstitions of Ireland</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-25/</guid><description>A really tough read. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure who to blame exactly for how boring most of the parts of this book are: the British for their empire and the consequences of that on the Irish, the Catholics for influencing the Irish and warping their existing folkloric beliefs, or Lady Wylde herself for presenting these stories in a very blunt and uninteresting way.
All I know is that I DNF this one at around the 70% mark, life&amp;rsquo;s too short.</description></item><item><title>The Secret of the Golden Flower: A Chinese Book of Life</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-25/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-25/</guid><description> Conserve your semen. Achieve immortality. Rejoice.</description></item><item><title>Wuthering Heights</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-23/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-23/</guid><description>DNF on page 7
Yikes</description></item><item><title>A Canticle for Leibowitz</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-26/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-26/</guid><description>Part 1: Amazing. Seems like this could have easily been an inspiration for the old school Fallout games I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved. Following one monk through the post-apocalypse is cool.
Part 2: Gigantic shift in tone. A less personal, more political story takes hold. Kind of hard to get through. The shift was really jarring.
Part 3: I haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten that far yet.
&amp;hellip;
I&amp;rsquo;ll have to get back to this eventually, it has a lot of potential but it was a challenge for me to read initially.</description></item><item><title>Being and Nothingness</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-25/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-25/</guid><description>Not my cup of tea. Philosophy should be understandable, this text is incomprehensible.
Maybe if was downing absinthe with Sartre and his crew back in the forties when this was written, I would &amp;ldquo;get&amp;rdquo; it. As-is though, this is pretty hard to get through.</description></item><item><title>Everyday Ethics: Inspired Solutions to Real-Life Dilemmas</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-18/</guid><description>DNF 50%
Joshua Halberstam is the king of strawmanning. Every chapter involves him describing these absurd caricatures of human beings and then using them to try to say to something interesting (keyword: try).
What is presented here is not &amp;ldquo;inspired solutions to real-life dilemmas&amp;rdquo; but &amp;ldquo;thoughts and comments on fabricated dilemmas the author came up with&amp;rdquo;.
It&amp;rsquo;s not all drivel but there&amp;rsquo;s so much of it that it was hard for me to care about the rest.</description></item><item><title>Games: Agency as Art</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-14/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-09-14/</guid><description>Games are a unique art form. They do not just tell stories, nor are they simply conceptual art. They are the art form that works in the medium of agency. C. Thi Nguyen&amp;rsquo;s Games: Agency as Art dives deep into these ideas and expands on them.</description></item></channel></rss>