<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Campaign Notes on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/campaigns/</link><description>Recent content in Campaign Notes on Strat</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/tabletop/campaigns/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FIST - Campaign Notes</title><link>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/campaigns/fist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/campaigns/fist/</guid><description>&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="one-pager">
&lt;h1>
One Pager
 &lt;a href="#one-pager">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>

&lt;p>&lt;strong>The campaign’s premise and flavor&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You play as potential recruits of FIST (Freelance Infantry Strike Team), a scrappy private military company employing many exceptional misfits just like you. You&amp;rsquo;ve just begun to gain control over your powers (what kind of powers would a Metal Gear Solid boss have?), use them effectively or die trying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;re being sent on your first mission. If you survive you&amp;rsquo;ll be given a year-long contract, some minimal health care benefits and a basic life insurance policy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Labyrinth of the Blue Gorgon - Campaign Notes</title><link>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/campaigns/labyrinth_of_the_blue_gorgon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/campaigns/labyrinth_of_the_blue_gorgon/</guid><description>&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="session-recaps">
&lt;h1>
Session Recaps
 &lt;a href="#session-recaps">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>







&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="session-0">
&lt;h2>
Session 0
 &lt;a href="#session-0">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>

&lt;p>Lanmino, an elf with all the connections, Freeya the Magnificent, a novice painter and apprentice mage extraordinaire, Blotbug, a goblin witch on the run from the death cult who tried to sacrifice him to their dark god, Marlon, a thief and expert con artist, form a thieving crew unlike any other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Due to their recent exploits, the Crew found themselves taking on their biggest job yet. Breaking into a vault and stealing a painting, the Labyrinth of the Blue Gorgon (painted by Freeya the Magnificent many years ago, or so he claims). They were asked by the wizard who gave them this job to hang the painting in their safehouse at night after stealing it and waiting for the moonlight to shine onto it. Desperate for money, they accepted the odd request.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tomorrow Legion Never Dies - Campaign Notes</title><link>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/campaigns/tomorrow-never-dies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/tabletop/campaigns/tomorrow-never-dies/</guid><description>&lt;/section>
&lt;section id="one-pager">
&lt;h1>
One Pager
 &lt;a href="#one-pager">
 ¶
 &lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>

&lt;p>&lt;strong>The campaign’s premise and flavor&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In December 2098, the Great Cataclysm ended the Golden Age of Mankind and brought with it torrents of magical energies tearing open rifts in space and time all over Earth. Out of those rifts came creatures long extinct, aliens and previously thought to be supernatural beings of all kinds. The remnants of humanity cowered in the shadows as the world as they knew it shattered around them.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>