<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Detective Fiction on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/tags/detective-fiction/</link><description>Recent content in Detective Fiction on Strat</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 11:13:51 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/books/tags/detective-fiction/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Murder On The Orient Express - A Hercule Piorot Mystery</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780062073495/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780062073495/</guid><description>&lt;p>Murder on the Orient Express is similar to Agatha Christie&amp;rsquo;s Death on the Nile (the other Agatha Christie novel I&amp;rsquo;ve read recently).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Both novels involve Hercule Poirot on vacation traveling (on a train or on a boat respectively), with the soon-to-be murder victim asking Poirot for help, him declining and then after the murder occurs, Poirot proceeds to solve the murder.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But Death on the Nile was SO MUCH MORE of a compelling read for me. Murder on the Orient Express is&amp;hellip; Uhhhhh&amp;hellip; Express, it&amp;rsquo;s fast and straightforward. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t waste any time. As soon as possible you&amp;rsquo;re jumping straight into the murder followed by a by-the-numbers solving of the mystery.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Death On The Nile</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780062073556/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780062073556/</guid><description>&lt;p>Agatha Christie is described as the &amp;ldquo;Queen of Mystery&amp;rdquo; and the &amp;ldquo;Queen of Crime&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After reading through Death on the Nile for the first time, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend that we add the &amp;ldquo;Queen of Camp&amp;rdquo; to that list.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Death on the Nile is one of the funniest books I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read. I don&amp;rsquo;t think that was the intention of the author almost one hundred years ago when it was first published but reading it now I was chuckling nonstop at how campy and absurd it is.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Doorways In The Sand</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781515444985/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781515444985/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
 
 &lt;p>In fair puzzles there should always be a way out. But I saw no doorways in the sand, and try as I might I could not make the puzzle fall fair.&lt;/p>
 
 &lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Doorways in the Sand tells the story of Fred Cassidy the &amp;ldquo;Eternal Student&amp;rdquo;, a man who&amp;rsquo;s spent 13 years of his life as an undergrad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He does everything he can to avoid getting a degree so he can continue benefiting from his uncle&amp;rsquo;s generous will, predicated on him being in school (once he graduates he&amp;rsquo;ll be cut off).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fred&amp;rsquo;s idyllic existence is disrupted by the theft of a priceless alien artifact, the star-stone. He&amp;rsquo;s a person of interest for reasons outside of his control and so he is pursued by humans and aliens alike who think he can help them find the stone (can he?).&lt;/p>


 &lt;blockquote>
 
 &lt;p>&amp;ldquo;You are a living example of the absurdity of things.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
 
 &lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Hijinks ensue.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>