<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fiction on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/tags/fiction/</link><description>Recent content in fiction on Strat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/books/tags/fiction/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Odyssey</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-12-25/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 07:41:45 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-12-25/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never read the Odyssey, and so I chose to read a recent translation of it by Emily Wilson.
It&amp;rsquo;s written in modern English making it easy to read. There&amp;rsquo;s no reason to use archaic English, which apparently is the norm with these kinds of texts, when translating a text that was originally in Greek. It&amp;rsquo;s a poem with the same number of lines as the original which is just plain fun.</description></item><item><title>Norse Mythology</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-12-15/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 07:38:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-12-15/</guid><description>Unlike Greek mythology, we don&amp;rsquo;t have many written records describing Norse mythology as it existed. So, there&amp;rsquo;s not really much we know about Norse mythology.
In his book titled Norse Mythology, Neil Gaiman riffs on what we know about the Norse myths and creates his own retellings of the stories and some completely new ones.
It&amp;rsquo;s OK. I like a lot of Neil Gaiman&amp;rsquo;s work (especially American Gods), his passion for mythology is clear and it shines through most of his work.</description></item><item><title>Sandcastles</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-22/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 07:48:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-22/</guid><description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t like Sandcastles. I&amp;rsquo;m not exactly qualified to critique graphic novels. I&amp;rsquo;m either too stupid to understand what it&amp;rsquo;s trying to say or it&amp;rsquo;s not trying to say anything at all. Either way, it didn&amp;rsquo;t make me feel anything&amp;hellip; Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m dead inside?</description></item><item><title>Remina</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 07:47:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-15/</guid><description>Junji Ito is cool. Uzumaki is great. A lot of his other work is just OK. I think Remina is also just OK.</description></item><item><title>The Drifting Classroom</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 07:46:26 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-01/</guid><description>Everyone knows about Junji Ito but not many people know about the work of Kazuo Umezz and that&amp;rsquo;s a shame.
This manga falls into one of my preferred manga sub-genres &amp;ldquo;kids suffering greatly and no one knows why&amp;rdquo; (Bokurano by Mohiro Kitoh is a great one of these). The story takes place in a classroom that&amp;rsquo;s drifting&amp;hellip; If you&amp;rsquo;re a fan of Junji Ito&amp;rsquo;s work like Uzumaki then you should check this one out too.</description></item></channel></rss>