<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fiction on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/tags/fiction/</link><description>Recent content in fiction on Strat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/books/tags/fiction/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Solaris</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-11/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-11/</guid><description>Fantastic genre-bending sci-fi.
My mind&amp;rsquo;s eye has never been very good so I rarely latch on to descriptions of the spaces that characters find themselves in. But, the descriptions of Solaris&amp;rsquo;s space station and the planet it&amp;rsquo;s orbiting were so vivid and interesting that it elevated the story for me.
The space station&amp;rsquo;s color scheme of white combined with stripes of vibrant colors lit by the alternating blue and red hues of the system&amp;rsquo;s both suns was breathtaking.</description></item><item><title>Doorways in the Sand</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-25/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-25/</guid><description>In fair puzzles there should always be a way out. But I saw no doorways in the sand, and try as I might I could not make the puzzle fall fair.
Doorways in the Sand tells the story of Fred Cassidy the &amp;ldquo;Eternal Student&amp;rdquo;, a man who&amp;rsquo;s spent 13 years of his life as an undergrad.
He does everything he can to avoid getting a degree so he can continue benefiting from his uncle&amp;rsquo;s generous will, predicated on him being in school (once he graduates he&amp;rsquo;ll be cut off).</description></item><item><title>The Obelisk Gate</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-29/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-29/</guid><description>spoiler alert This novel suffers from middle book syndrome. It continues the story set up in the first book and, hopefully, sets up the third and final book.
Unlike The Fifth Season, this novel fails to coalesce the different POVs into a cohesive whole which was one of the best aspects of the first book.
The Obelisk Gate feels like two different stories that were spliced into each other and suffers for it.</description></item><item><title>All Systems Red</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-06/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-06/</guid><description>All Systems Red is about a sentient robot-human hybrid, calling themselves Murderbot, a slave to a mega corporation, tasked with protecting the humans it&amp;rsquo;s told to protect.</description></item><item><title>I'm Thinking of Ending Things</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-05/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-05/</guid><description>spoiler alert SPOILER ALERT
It&amp;rsquo;s got a twist.
Yayyyyyyyyyyyyy
I loooooOooOoove twists.
Especially when the foreshadowing of the twist is indistinguishable from terrible writing (absurd internal monologues, nonsensical dialogue between characters) on your first, and probably last, reading of the text.
SPOILER ALERT
SPOILER ALERT
SPOILER ALERT
Canonically, the book you&amp;rsquo;re reading, except for the flashforward interstitials between most chapters, was written by an autistic man who kills himself by the end of the book (a truly inspirational tale, thank you so much for your service Iain).</description></item><item><title>Small Gods</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-03/</guid><description>Terry is dedicated to the bit. More than anything he is committed to creating absurd worlds that feel real. His work has aged beautifully because the world we live in is as absurd as it&amp;rsquo;s ever been and it&amp;rsquo;s only getting more absurd from here on out.
Small Gods is about an autistic savant (pour a drink every time Terry Pratchett includes an autistic character in one of his Discworld books) named Brutha who is a lowly priest/monk in the church of Om.</description></item><item><title>Children of Memory</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-28/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-28/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;They think.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Not thinking like us, though.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Well that&amp;rsquo;s to be expected.&amp;rdquo;
Minor spoilers below about the basic premise of the series/novel
Children of Memory is the third novel in the Children of Time series by Adrian Tchaikovsky. It follows in the footsteps of the first two books by giving us another story about characters (various uplifted species, human/AI constructs and one fungi species) being thrust together onto another planet.</description></item><item><title>A Conjuring of Light</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-18/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-18/</guid><description>spoiler alert It was an enjoyable romp but doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily hit the highs of the previous books in the series. As the third and final(ish) book in the series I was expecting something a little bit more. Or maybe I was expecting a little bit less, a more tightly edited and polished story. Either would have been nice.
Here&amp;rsquo;s some thoughts:
It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to tell a story about an antagonistic character who is basically a god.</description></item><item><title>Brave New World</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-01-08/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-01-08/</guid><description>Brave New World is a dystopian novel from 1932 about dystopian shit and it has a lot to say about the dystopia we&amp;rsquo;re currently living in.</description></item><item><title>Terraform: Watch/Worlds/Burn</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-12-23/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-12-23/</guid><description>A collection of science-fiction short stories that&amp;rsquo;ll make you go &amp;ldquo;huh, interesting&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; and might encourage you to think about how technology affects your life currently and how it might affect it in the not so distant future.</description></item><item><title>Good Omens</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-12-10/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-12-10/</guid><description>A cool guy devil and a flamboyantly effeminate angel living on Earth try to stop the end times from happening because they&amp;rsquo;ve come to enjoy all of Earth&amp;rsquo;s pleasures (mosly driving fast cars and reading, respectively). Also, there&amp;rsquo;s the anti-christ, a descendant of a prophet who&amp;rsquo;s predicted everything, some dude, etc. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot going on here.</description></item><item><title>The Colour of Magic</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-28/</guid><description>An incompetent wizard is tasked with protecting a visitor visiting from a faraway land. A fantasy novel for people who don&amp;rsquo;t like fantasy novels.</description></item><item><title>Truth of the Divine</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-20/</guid><description>Aliens on Earth in the early/mid 2000s and everything that follows from that. Sequel to Axiom&amp;rsquo;s End, continues Cora&amp;rsquo;s story and adds some new fresh characters (alien and otherwise) into the mix.</description></item><item><title>Axiom's End</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-12/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-12/</guid><description>Set in 2007, the novel is about a U.S. government coverup of contact with extraterrestrial life. You follow the story of Cora, daughter of an exiled whistleblower, who finds herself in the middle of the whole &amp;lsquo;alien&amp;rsquo; situation.</description></item><item><title>Living Beyond Borders: Growing up Mexican in America</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-10-04/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-10-04/</guid><description>An anthology of short stories, comics, and poems from Mexican American authors.</description></item><item><title>The Odyssey</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-12-25/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-12-25/</guid><description>The Odyssey is a classic and there&amp;rsquo;s more stories that have been inspired by it than I can count. After reading it, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to see it echoed everywhere you look.</description></item><item><title>Norse Mythology</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-12-15/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-12-15/</guid><description>Neil Gaiman&amp;rsquo;s Norse Mythology is a retelling of a few stories from Norse mythology (which we don&amp;rsquo;t know very much about). I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of Neil Gaiman&amp;rsquo;s work generally but I found this to be quite boring.</description></item><item><title>Sandcastles</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-22/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-22/</guid><description>Sandcastles is the french comic book that the recent M. Night Shyamalan&amp;rsquo;s movie Old was based on. A bunch of different people arrive for a relaxing day at the beach and find themselves aging extremely rapidly, babies become teens and older folk die. Hijinks ensue. I don&amp;rsquo;t get it.</description></item><item><title>Remina</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-15/</guid><description>Junji Ito is cool. Uzumaki is great. A lot of his other work is just OK. I think Remina is also just OK.</description></item><item><title>The Drifting Classroom</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2021-07-01/</guid><description>The Drifting Classroom is a Japanese horror manga series published from 1972 to 1974 that follows a school (and its students) that is mysteriously transported through time to a post-apocalyptic future.</description></item></channel></rss>