<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Strat's Wad Thoughts on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/wads/</link><description>Recent content in Strat's Wad Thoughts on Strat</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/wads/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Eviternity II</title><link>https://strategineer.com/wads/eviternity2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/wads/eviternity2/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I loved the first Eviternity, let&amp;rsquo;s see how this holds up&lt;/li>
&lt;li>nice palette&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map01
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>crazy intro teleporter thing, let&amp;rsquo;s check this in doombuilder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>also revisiting levels from the first megawad but altered due to doomguy&amp;rsquo;s efforts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>jump pads still kind of wild, although a little glitchy&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map02
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>first button you hit, you see exactly what it activates in LOS&lt;/li>
&lt;li>cool rain effect&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>making the pistol fire faster is a classic great way of fixing the pistol feeling awful to use&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Whispers Of Satan</title><link>https://strategineer.com/wads/wos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/wads/wos/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>collab between pcorf and Aro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>fantastic original midi soundtrack, with both pcorf and Aro being talented musicians&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map9: the school, a no russian-esque map, an explicit reference to columbine? That massacre directly led to Doom coming up in the news and being villified and being accused of &amp;ldquo;causing&amp;rdquo; it. Now here&amp;rsquo;s a Doom map that&amp;rsquo;s explicitly about going into a &amp;ldquo;school&amp;rdquo; and blasting through hordes of &amp;ldquo;demons&amp;rdquo;. The music hits here, it&amp;rsquo;s melancholic and it feels like it represents the loss of innocence.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>very tight ammo setup (tightest I&amp;rsquo;ve played recently, every bullet is essential, waste is lethal)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a lot of time spent with the shotgun, smashing your head against bullet sponges. Enemy composition choices are questionable at times, it seems like the mappers were more interested in creating a hopeless vibe instead of purely &amp;ldquo;fun&amp;rdquo; gameplay&lt;/li>
&lt;li>maps get super long past the 1/2 mark&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map25: sneaky cyberdemon teleporting around ominously, very cool&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ubiquitous crosses, inverted, normal, orthodox, but just generally there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of indented decoration in walls. It&amp;rsquo;s used a little too much maybe but it does provide the dozen maps of the wad with a unique look/feel&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map26: organ music at start, great vibes for the evil cathedral setting of the map&lt;/li>
&lt;li>too long, overstays its welcome because the combat isn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;fun&amp;rdquo; enough to hold the rest of it up?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>this has some really iconic set pieces / scenes (map30: hell-levator) but they&amp;rsquo;re spread a little because the maps are so long&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ammo counts a little sus, even when making full use of chainsaw / berserk punching, you just don&amp;rsquo;t have enough. Although I can get a little better at punching demons&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Brigandine</title><link>https://strategineer.com/wads/brigandine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/wads/brigandine/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 super hot fire map&lt;/li>
&lt;li>insane music (doesn&amp;rsquo;t loop properly though)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>cool visuals + combat encounters&lt;/li>
&lt;li>colour palette&lt;/li>
&lt;li>solid AF&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Wads like this are convincing me that if you&amp;rsquo;ve got great music and shift the colour palette slightly combined with good level/combat encounter design, you&amp;rsquo;re golden.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nostalgic Entropy: Neo Retro</title><link>https://strategineer.com/wads/ne/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/wads/ne/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>jaw dropping visuals, custom textures, etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>amazing music&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Atonement</title><link>https://strategineer.com/wads/atone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/wads/atone/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
 
 &lt;p>&lt;p>Unluckily, you&amp;rsquo;ve spawned right in the midst of a trap. The demons have already made it to Earth. It seems like you have just two options of atonement:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Save Earth or die trying.&lt;/p>
&lt;/p>
 
 &lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>a megamad made by one person of 5 years, and it feels like it for better or worse.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>music is a little &amp;ldquo;coffebreak&amp;rdquo; a little elevator music, lacks the propulsive or mystical quality that I&amp;rsquo;m usually looking for.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The first few maps are serviceable and interesting but lack a certain jenesaisquoi. These were created first in the author&amp;rsquo;s DOOM mapping journey, so this makes sense. They&amp;rsquo;ve been touched up after the fact so they&amp;rsquo;re not horrible but they&amp;rsquo;re just OK.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Music gets better after the first 1/3 (map12 track pretty great).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>13: mall center, now we&amp;rsquo;re &amp;ldquo;gaming&amp;rdquo;, solid mapping&lt;/li>
&lt;li>14: the music gets kicking here&lt;/li>
&lt;li>15: back to low fi beat to kill demons to, not my favorite&lt;/li>
&lt;li>16: music kicks in exactly at the halfway point&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Zone 400</title><link>https://strategineer.com/wads/zone400/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/wads/zone400/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
 
 &lt;p>After 12,000 linedefs of action, you have won this battle and have destroyed the source of this demonic civilization. Condemnation is no more and the mystery of this pandemic has finally been solved. As you hop onto the derelict imperial space station Ondor (sic) for the long journey back home you destroy the rest of these beasts with ease blasting them to oblivion.&lt;/p>
 
 &lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>400 line defs each megawad by one mapper (pcorf)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>mostly consistent map length feels good&lt;/li>
&lt;li>economy of design, reusing the same spaces over and over again. A little bit of difficulty in differentiating the levels. There&amp;rsquo;s an intentional use of different textures-sets throughout but it&amp;rsquo;s not enough to really make these maps feel really different.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>gradual expansion of arenas and combination of them as more monster closets are revealed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;hellip; I like this more than I would have expected.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a lot of random TPs used to move enemies around the arenas&amp;hellip; interesting but hard to parse. Makes the maps feel a little random. It feels like a bandaid to solve the problem of wanting to have these maps be tiny but re-use the existing spaces a bunch&amp;hellip; it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fully work.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map11: great example of this idea of opening an arena gradually&lt;/li>
&lt;li>timed buttons keep the pace up but sometimes slow you down when you miss the timing.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>singular/low rocket ammo drops, forces tactical rocket use more than usual&lt;/li>
&lt;li>maps separated into mostly thematic episodes with different map design ethos/pillars in each it feels like&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s good&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2020 pandemic-inspired story line&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Fallen Leaves</title><link>https://strategineer.com/wads/fallenleaves/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/wads/fallenleaves/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>great start, great music, tight combat, awesome color palette&lt;/li>
&lt;li>short and sweet, high polish&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Machete</title><link>https://strategineer.com/wads/machetefinal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/wads/machetefinal/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
 
 &lt;p>Those scum ridden sacks of shit didn&amp;rsquo;t even have the empathy to honorably discharge me. I was just told to shut up and get out. I cleared a tech base of those nightmares and I bet they&amp;rsquo;d still rather see me dead than holding a place in the marines again. I don&amp;rsquo;t need help, I just need to wipe out the rest of these terrors and get rid of that awful noise. Onward to Sunveil Starport.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Lies Beneath</title><link>https://strategineer.com/wads/whatlies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/wads/whatlies/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>gothic horror, moody, starts off entering a spooky mansion and descending into the dungeon&amp;hellip;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>sort of like wad where you go up an elevator in a skyscraper but reversed?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>vibes on point, gameplay not as tight, feels a little random enemy spawn-wise&lt;/li>
&lt;li>great music&lt;/li>
&lt;li>lack of consistency in vision and game mechanics and progression of ideas&amp;hellip;, too many cooks, but each level has a lot of love put into it&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map4 blacksite: sick&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I think I&amp;rsquo;d take a group of less interesting less good maps that are thematically vibewise and gameplay wise cohesive than hodge podge of better maps&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map8: where fools always trespass, elevator sequence&lt;/li>
&lt;li>really too hodge podgy mix and match, lack of cohesion, but the highs are high. not my preference but very cool levels in here&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map11: falling platforms section&lt;/li>
&lt;li>last map might be a little too big&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>