<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reading on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/tags/reading/</link><description>Recent content in Reading on Strat</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 14:00:21 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/blog/tags/reading/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>That moment when you get isekai-ed into a hierarcichal fantasy world and hijinks ensue</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-10-17/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-10-17/</guid><description>This is a really rough draft, read the following at your own peril.
This essay contains spoilers for Gene Wolfe&amp;rsquo;s The Knight.
Able of the High Heart is the POV character in Gene Wolfe&amp;rsquo;s fantasy isekai tryptich The Wizard Knight. I loved the first novel of the set, the Knight, mainly because Able of the High Heart is such an interesting character.
In the following post, I&amp;rsquo;ll describe the premise of the Wizard Knight, then I&amp;rsquo;ll describe a formative encounter that Able has with the knight named Sir Ravd of Redhall early on in his journey and finally I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how this encounter shaped Able into the knight he is now (or wants to be) and why Able being this way is entertaining to read about.</description></item><item><title>On Being Awesome (1)</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-17/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 19:14:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-17/</guid><description>Nick Riggle&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;On Being Awesome: A Unified Theory of How Not to Suck&amp;rdquo; is a philosophy book that discusses awesomeness and suckiness in detail. It defines language to accurately describe and reason about the awesomeness and suckiness that you perceive in yourself and in others.
According to Mr. Riggle, awesomeness and suckiness revolves all around social openings which are moments when we can choose to break out of our norm-governed roles by expressing ourselves.</description></item></channel></rss>