<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reading on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/tags/reading/</link><description>Recent content in Reading on Strat</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 16:40:04 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/blog/tags/reading/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>NOTY List 2024</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2025-01-02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2025-01-02/</guid><description>&lt;p>A list of novels, in randomized order, that I read and enjoyed in 2024.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thoughts on Gene Wolfe's the Wizard Knight (1)</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-10-18/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-10-18/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This post contains spoilers for Gene Wolfe&amp;rsquo;s The Knight.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What do you think is the deal with Abel and his inexplicable random acts of violence?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>At the start of the Knight, but this is made clear(er) only in retrospect, Able is young and naive. He&amp;rsquo;s a boy in a man&amp;rsquo;s body but he doesn&amp;rsquo;t really know who HE is, yet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Knight is a journey of self-actualization for Able. He&amp;rsquo;s discovering who he is by doing what kids do. They model their own beliefs and behaviours based on the beliefs and behaviours of the adults around them. In Able&amp;rsquo;s case, early on in the Knight, before he&amp;rsquo;s physically transformed into an absolute beefcake of a man, he has a brief encounter with a knight, Sir Ravd of Redhall.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why Able in Gene Wolfe's The Wizard Knight is the way he is</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-10-17/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2024-10-17/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is a really rough draft, read the following at your own peril.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This essay contains spoilers for Gene Wolfe&amp;rsquo;s The Knight.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Able of the High Heart is the POV character in Gene Wolfe&amp;rsquo;s fantasy isekai tryptich The Wizard Knight. I loved the first novel of the set, the Knight, mainly because Able of the High Heart is such an interesting character.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the following post, I&amp;rsquo;ll describe the premise of the Wizard Knight, then I&amp;rsquo;ll describe a formative encounter that Able has with the knight named Sir Ravd of Redhall early on in his journey and finally I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how this encounter shaped Able into the knight he is now (or wants to be) and why Able being this way is entertaining to read about.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>On Being Awesome (1)</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-17/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 19:14:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-08-17/</guid><description>&lt;p>Nick Riggle&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;On Being Awesome: A Unified Theory of How Not to Suck&amp;rdquo; is a philosophy book that discusses awesomeness and suckiness in detail. It defines language to accurately describe and reason about the awesomeness and suckiness that you perceive in yourself and in others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>According to Mr. Riggle, awesomeness and suckiness revolves all around &lt;em>social openings&lt;/em> which are moments when we can choose to break out of our norm-governed roles by expressing ourselves.&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>