<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ramble on Strategineer</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/tags/ramble/</link><description>Recent content in ramble on Strategineer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/blog/tags/ramble/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I wrote this on my phone</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-05-23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-05-23/</guid><description>Now that I&amp;rsquo;m using GitHub Actions to deploy my website I&amp;rsquo;m able to write something on my phone, push it to GitHub and Voila!
Freshly squeezed content from my brain to yours.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Myself</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-18/</guid><description>Hi, my name&amp;rsquo;s [NAME]. I&amp;rsquo;ve lived in [CITY], [COUNTRY] my whole life.
I&amp;rsquo;ve worked in the flight simulator space, the video game world, in special effects and, most recently, in financial services.
I&amp;rsquo;m débrouillard meaning that no matter what problem you throw at me, inevitably, I&amp;rsquo;ll figure it out and solve it. I thrive in environments where there&amp;rsquo;s lots of interesting problems to solve. That&amp;rsquo;s what peeked my initial interest in [COMPANY] and I&amp;rsquo;m happy to be here.</description></item><item><title>Twilight</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-17/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-04-17/</guid><description>https://mynoise.net/NoiseMachines/twilightSoundscapeGenerator.php
Twinkling stars blinking in and out of existence.
The thought of the sound of space.
Weightless, floating, breathing in and out forever.
An alien hand reaches out, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s going to be OK&amp;rdquo; they said.
Time stopped, and I looked inward to find myself.
Forgiving yourself for mistakes made and ones you&amp;rsquo;ve yet to make.
The liminal space between your past and your present selves.</description></item><item><title>Bad Poetry #1</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-02-06/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-02-06/</guid><description>Sifting through the filtered photographs
Left and right, left and right
It was love at first swipe.
Balsamic vinegar,
&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s healthy&amp;rdquo;, they said. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s good for you.&amp;rdquo;
But, healthy salad makes me a sad lad.
Choking on a piece of bread,
&amp;ldquo;Chew before you swallow&amp;rdquo;, they said,
I didn&amp;rsquo;t listen and now I&amp;rsquo;m dead.
Flames engulf us,
As I hold on to you, tight.
Are you feeling this?</description></item><item><title>Beetles, bravery and brotherhood</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-02-02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-02-02/</guid><description>Let the beetles beat their drums
Waves reflecting off the sun
Yet, the war has just begun
Previously potted plant, shards everywhere
Uprooted but far from death,
A survivor, stronger than ever
Mint never gave up.
Twelve or more weeks later, disremembered
Gone forever but not forgotten
Brother, who would you have been?</description></item><item><title>Jacob Geller is a god, other people are not</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-18/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-18/</guid><description>Video game Youtube people like Joseph Anderson and Noah Caldwell-Gervais (and many others) have been encouraged by the algorithm (and the way Youtube is monetized) to create longer and longer videos.
It&amp;rsquo;s gotten completely out of hand buuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuut some people seem to be really into it.
I don&amp;rsquo;t see the appeal myself but the numbers don&amp;rsquo;t lie.
Noah Caldwell-Gervais&amp;rsquo; video on the Resident Evil series has a 7h28min long runtime&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>VTOL VR</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-17/</guid><description>Perfect Landing!
I played a few hours of VTOL VR today (streaming the Steam version to my Quest 2 using Virtual Desktop).
I&amp;rsquo;ve never been super excited about planes and doing bombing runs on tiny white dots (collateral damage anyone?) bbuUuUuuuut I had a ton of fun. Maybe I just like roleplaying as a terrible person?
In VTOL VR, you&amp;rsquo;re a pilot of a fully-interactable yet simplified VTOL jet. The cockpit you&amp;rsquo;re in has a ton of fully functioning buttons, levers and joysticks that you use to pilot the jet.</description></item><item><title>Thought Exercise #1</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-01/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2022-01-01/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s a big (but portable) blue button with the word &amp;ldquo;KILL&amp;rdquo; painted on it (called the kill button).
Every time you press the button, a human being on the planet dies and X money is added to your bank account.
How much does X have to be for you to press the button? If you would never press the button no matter how much money you get for doing so, explain why.</description></item><item><title>Diary of a Galaxy Conquering Middle Manager</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-31/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-31/</guid><description>Ahhhhhhhhhhhhhhhh I don&amp;rsquo;t want to bathe in the blood of my enemies againnnnnnnnnnn.
Huh.
But, I do it anyway because it&amp;rsquo;s what my boss, my colleagues and my employees expect of me.
Keeping up appearances is important when you&amp;rsquo;re leading a horde of fanatics across the galaxy in a quest to conquer and kill everyone and everything.
I am but a cog in the machine upholding the status quo in charge of killing any living being that steps out of line.</description></item><item><title>TWRP - The Odyssey - Icarus</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-12-06/</guid><description>Tupper Ware Remix Party ¶ I don&amp;rsquo;t really want to write about Tupper Ware Remix Party.
Writing about music is pain and suffering. Just listen to it, maybe you&amp;rsquo;ll like it.
look at those costumes!
The Odyssey ¶ I just finished reading the Odyssey (translated by Emily Wilson). Odysseus is a mass murderer and a villain&amp;hellip; yet in the story he&amp;rsquo;s presented as a victim and a hero.</description></item><item><title>Building a Discord bot to play Everyone is John</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-24/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-24/</guid><description>I spent all my free time today working on a discord bot to help me GM a tabletop roleplaying session of &amp;ldquo;Everyone is John&amp;rdquo; over Discord.
I hope people have fun!</description></item><item><title>Game of the Year List Draft</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-23/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-23/</guid><description>Supernatural (Oculus Quest 2) Fantastic dance + boxing workouts in VR delivered straight to my headset daily with amazing music and movement. Having one of the many fantastic trainers encouraging you during your workout seems cheesy but it actually helps keep me motivated to keep working out. The game is tricking me into thinking that there&amp;rsquo;s someone out there, other than myself, who&amp;rsquo;s invested in my personal wellbeing. It works.</description></item><item><title>Pilk</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-22/</guid><description>Pilk</description></item><item><title>montager: a script to generate Hunt Showdown montages</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-21/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-21/</guid><description>I want to write some python python code that&amp;rsquo;ll take a folder containing Hunt Showdown video highlights generated through Nvidia Highlights (most of which are exactly 25s long) and automatically generate a &amp;ldquo;montage&amp;rdquo; video containing all the highlights combined.
montager /my_hunt_highlights/ I would like the code to analyze each video, and using one of several different algorithms, and detect which parts of the video are interesting and clip those parts out before combining all the clips together.</description></item><item><title>Footnotes</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-19/</guid><description>This is a test.1
Now I can add footnotes to my essays to make myself seem 100x more intelligent (or obnoxious).
How does this look?
How about this.
This That Potato &amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;</description></item><item><title>Embeds, embeds, embeds</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-18/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-18/</guid><description>I wrote some code to help me embed audio files into my blog posts easily&amp;hellip;
Your browser does not support the audio element. Here&amp;rsquo;s a song I produced about 5 years ago. It&amp;rsquo;s a decent &amp;ldquo;bop&amp;rdquo;?
I wrote some more code to help me embed video files into my blog posts easily&amp;hellip;
Sorry, your browser doesn't support embedded videos. Here&amp;rsquo;s a video of a robot character I modeled and animated myself in Java a long time ago in a university far, far away</description></item><item><title>4 chill beats to work to</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-16/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-16/</guid><description>nervoustestpilot Macross 82-99 Panchiko LukHash &amp;hellip;
I feel like my productivity gets boosted substantially if I&amp;rsquo;m listening to the right kind of music music?
Or maybe listening to good music makes me happy (and more productive)?.
Or maybe I decide to listen to music when I&amp;rsquo;m happy and I&amp;rsquo;m already being more productive than usual because I&amp;rsquo;m happy?
I don&amp;rsquo;t know.</description></item><item><title>Writing #1</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-15/</guid><description>My bars are low, almost completely drained. But here I am, back again for more. Doing exactly what I do everyday. Typing words on my computer.
I&amp;rsquo;m a programmer by day, a writer by night. I&amp;rsquo;m a much better programmer than I am a writer. If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever worked with me, you may or may not disagree. I would love to live in a world where writing was my job and programming was my hobby.</description></item><item><title>ABCs #3</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-11/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-11/</guid><description>Alcohol, being crushed, dull every freedom
Gobble hetero immaturity
Juggle KKK, layman money night
Obsession perverted, quest running stop
Toppling ultimatum vampiress
Win xenon, yodeling, zigzaggedness
Alps, butt cool, dying ebb&amp;rsquo;n flow, guttural
High-minded imagination, jester
Kind laugh, movement, nagging, ovulation
Pressure quacking, rocking silence, taken
Underground venomous, woman, xanthic
Yarovizations, zombifications
All beta cucks, dick egress, fuckers got
Hitting it, jerking kick, losers meeting</description></item><item><title>ABCs #2</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-10/</guid><description>Ale brought chaos, down everywhere fortune
Gaze him into jab, kill love man-of-war
Neither of prison, quarter rocky stone
Tainted undulation vain waifs XoX
Yuppification. Zygophyllaceous.</description></item><item><title>ABCs #1</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-09/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-09/</guid><description>All being cool, do everything flying
Get high, inhale juvenile karmic love
Make naan on pan? question rhetorical
Sink too, under veil waves, xeric you zombie</description></item><item><title>The Odyssey Book 1-7: Two Soy Boy Beta Cucks becoming men (again)</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-08/</guid><description>The story of the Odyssey begins with Telemachus, the son of Odysseus, being a soy boy beta cuck. The men vying for the hand of his mother Penelope treat him like shit. Odysseus&amp;rsquo;s long absence has created a power vacuum in Ithaca and many suitors are now waiting in line to court and wed Penelope.
Telemachus attempts to become less of a soy boy beta cuck by becoming more of a misogynist and treating his exceptionally beautiful and intelligent mother like crap.</description></item><item><title>I made spicy shrimp tacos today</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-07/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-07/</guid><description>I made this today.
It was good.</description></item><item><title>Inline images with captions</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-06/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-06/</guid><description>I took me years of writing about video games (a visual medium) on here before I finally decided it was about time to make it easy for me to insert images with optional captions into my blog posts&amp;hellip;
Well, here you go.
This is some text before the image.
testing the caption
This is some text after the image.
It took me about 30min to get this to work.</description></item><item><title>Cocktails #1</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-04/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-04/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s an ordered list of all the cocktails I&amp;rsquo;ve tried since I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten into mixology from my most favorite to least favorite:
Dark and Stormy Ginger beer combined with rum, garnished with lime. The &amp;ldquo;dark&amp;rdquo; part of the Dark and Stormy refers to the color but the &amp;ldquo;stormy&amp;rdquo; part refers to the storm of flavors this cocktail creates in your mouth. I&amp;rsquo;ve been told that the key is to buy (or make) high quality ginger beer.</description></item><item><title>Sleep</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-03/</guid><description>I forgot to set my alarm last night, so I woke up 2h after I was expecting to and that&amp;rsquo;s thrown off my entire day. I can&amp;rsquo;t fix this by going to sleep 2h later than usual because I want to get a good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep and I want to wake up at my usual time (6:30am).
So here I am, living through a day that&amp;rsquo;s shorter than it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be.</description></item><item><title>Cutting my own hair</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-02/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been cutting my own hair for the past few years.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned:
A decent hair trimmer costs as much as a single haircut. If you can learn how to cut your own hair with one then you can save a little time and money. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking to give yourself a buzzcut then buy yourself a hair trimmer and enjoy saving yourself time and money by cutting your own hair.</description></item><item><title>A (work)day in the life</title><link>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/blog/2021-11-01/</guid><description>6:30am.
I wake up. It&amp;rsquo;s still dark outside. I sit on the toilet bowl and piss. I get up and walk over to my closet. I pull out some socks, pajama pants or shorts depending on the weather and a polo shirt.
I get dressed.
I walk over to my living room. I take my phone off its wireless charger and check to see if I received any messages in the middle of the night (probably not).</description></item></channel></rss>