<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dragonfly on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/mappers/dragonfly/</link><description>Recent content in Dragonfly on Strat</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 22:35:09 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/mappers/dragonfly/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Eviternity II</title><link>https://strategineer.com/wads/eviternity2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/wads/eviternity2/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I loved the first Eviternity, let&amp;rsquo;s see how this holds up&lt;/li>
&lt;li>nice palette&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map01
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>crazy intro teleporter thing, let&amp;rsquo;s check this in doombuilder&lt;/li>
&lt;li>also revisiting levels from the first megawad but altered due to doomguy&amp;rsquo;s efforts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>jump pads still kind of wild, although a little glitchy&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map02
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>first button you hit, you see exactly what it activates in LOS&lt;/li>
&lt;li>cool rain effect&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map03
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>leaves falling effect, cool&amp;hellip;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>making the pistol fire faster is a classic great way of fixing the pistol feeling awful to use&lt;/li>
&lt;li>each map&amp;rsquo;s exit allow you to see the start of the next map is brilliant
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>a lot of &amp;ldquo;high budget&amp;rdquo; choices like this bring this wad above and beyond others&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the detailing in every room is just insane&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>having a switch bring up some stairs with a switch on them allowing the player to &amp;ldquo;unlock&amp;rdquo; being able to activate these stairs up and down to access new areas seems key (not something new but something I was having trouble coming up with on my own during my most recent mapping session)
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>also, having really big stairs have a dedicated button next to them instead of on them&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map05 track is cool but doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit&amp;hellip;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>breadcrumb rocket ammo, encourages keeping your eyes peeled and makes the movement funner than it would be otherwise (like coins in Mario)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map07: big open space with monsters all around, open this one up in UDB and take a look at how this works.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>two SSG spawns on both ends of the map to increases the chances of the player picking it up sooner rather than later. Especially once the pinkies are start showing up.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>every enemy set to ambush probably. Ample use of cacos that can fly over obstacles and threaten the player. A lot of weak monsters out of reach that the player can ping with the chaingun, big bads are very rarely out of reach. Arachnotron used as a turret though&lt;/li>
&lt;li>hit a switch and different monster comps teleported into the arena you just fought in&lt;/li>
&lt;li>switches / combined with walk over linedef actions to force player to walk back and forth while fighting enemies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>masterful use of colours to guide the player towards buttons they can press or should press based on the keys they have (map06 does this too)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>grey arachnos are deadly but their shots can be avoided with movement so they encourage you to keep moving&lt;/li>
&lt;li>giving an extra rocket launcher as well, just in case&amp;hellip;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>a lot of sector manipulation to create arenas where fights happen then eventually the arena opens back up again. Check how this is done in UDB&amp;hellip;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map09: nice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map11: constantly expanding arena with new monsters&lt;/li>
&lt;li>map12: another map with an expanding arena, a bunch of imps teleporting in, seems like the imp is the go to spammable enemy&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>