<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fantasy on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/tags/fantasy/</link><description>Recent content in fantasy on Strat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/books/tags/fantasy/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Obelisk Gate</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-29/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-29/</guid><description>spoiler alert This novel suffers from middle book syndrome. It continues the story set up in the first book and, hopefully, sets up the third and final book.
Unlike The Fifth Season, this novel fails to coalesce the different POVs into a cohesive whole which was one of the best aspects of the first book.
The Obelisk Gate feels like two different stories that were spliced into each other and suffers for it.</description></item><item><title>Small Gods</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-03/</guid><description>Terry is dedicated to the bit. More than anything he is committed to creating absurd worlds that feel real. His work has aged beautifully because the world we live in is as absurd as it&amp;rsquo;s ever been and it&amp;rsquo;s only getting more absurd from here on out.
Small Gods is about an autistic savant (pour a drink every time Terry Pratchett includes an autistic character in one of his Discworld books) named Brutha who is a lowly priest/monk in the church of Om.</description></item><item><title>A Conjuring of Light</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-18/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-18/</guid><description>spoiler alert It was an enjoyable romp but doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily hit the highs of the previous books in the series. As the third and final(ish) book in the series I was expecting something a little bit more. Or maybe I was expecting a little bit less, a more tightly edited and polished story. Either would have been nice.
Here&amp;rsquo;s some thoughts:
It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to tell a story about an antagonistic character who is basically a god.</description></item><item><title>The Colour of Magic</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-28/</guid><description>An incompetent wizard is tasked with protecting a visitor visiting from a faraway land. A fantasy novel for people who don&amp;rsquo;t like fantasy novels.</description></item></channel></rss>