<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fantasy on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/tags/fantasy/</link><description>Recent content in Fantasy on Strat</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 20:34:47 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/books/tags/fantasy/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Grunts</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780451454539/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780451454539/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote cite="p. 5">
 &lt;p>&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;You can&amp;rsquo;t beat no orc marines&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When we fire our M16s!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/p>
 
 &lt;p class="page-number">p. 151&lt;/p>
 
 &lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Mary Gentle&amp;rsquo;s Grunts in a nutshell. Grunts is a satire of the schlocky high fantasy Tolkien ripoffs of the 70s and 80s. It pokes fun at the aesthetic of the American military as portrayed in film and literature. It combines Grand Guignol (think slapstick but extra gory and violent) dark comedy with satire on bad fantasy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The story begins with a group of orcs, the Agaku led by the orc Ashnak, tasked with stealing powerful yet non-magical weapons from a dragon&amp;rsquo;s hoard by the nameless necromancer. The pretense for this quest is that these weapons will be useful for the Final Battle between the forces of Light and Dark that&amp;rsquo;s about to happen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These weapons turn out to be an impressive assortment of modern military equipment: assault rifles, machine guns, rocket launchers, tanks, helicopters, surface to air missile launchers&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You name it, they&amp;rsquo;ve got it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Agaku are your stereotypical generic fantasy orcs: a little stupid, violent, strong. The dragon&amp;rsquo;s hoard of modern military weaponry was cursed with a geas which changes the mindset of the orcs into the stereotypical Vietnam War United States Marine Corps soldier mindset: huuuuuurrah-ing, tabbaco chewing, cigar smoking, a belief that might makes right, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hijinks ensue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Minor Spoilers Ahead&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It turns out that the modern military equipment the orc marines have access to isn&amp;rsquo;t enough to turn the tide of the Final Battle. The forces of Light win but many of the forces of Dark, including Ashnak and his orc marines, manage to escape. The orc marines return to their fort in Nin-Edin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the following weeks, the forces of Light chase down and ethnically cleanse (we&amp;rsquo;ll get into it) the remaining forces of Dark. This leads to a siege (take a shot every time Mary Gentle depicts a siege in her work) where Ashnak and his orc marines have dug into their fort at Nin-Edin and are preparing to fend off the forces of Light.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note that all this happens in the first third of the novel, subverting the trope of the not so final Final Battle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the forces of Light. Epic fantasy has always had a problematic relationship with presenting good/bad in black and white terms with little room in between. My understanding is that this simplicity appeals to the human desire to constantly simplify the eternally complex real world in order to live within it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s fine. But by presenting good/bad like this, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to fall into the trap (intentionally or not) of depicting certain beings as inherently evil.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dehumanizing the human.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mary Gentle portrays the forces of Light and Dark&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>posits that the weapons we have access to change us (power corrupts), she posits that power is power and war is war,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip; fantasy satire with grit. Think Terry Pratchett but more mature and with a lot more gore and violence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>themes to explore: ethnic cleansing, rnd orc with gold eyes (1/8th elven)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ash - A Secret History</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780575069015/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780575069015/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ash - A Secret History is by far the longest novel I&amp;rsquo;ve read. When I saw the thickness of the book, the number of lines on each page and the miniscule size of the font, I was scared that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to read through the whole thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All it took for me to get over that fear was reading the first few pages. Mary Gentle hooked me with her commitment to telling Ash&amp;rsquo;s story in a way that only she could and she refused to let go of me until the very end.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Books of Earthsea: The Complete Illustrated Edition</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781481465588/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781481465588/</guid><description>&lt;p>These illustrations are kind of whack. All the characters look like little goblins.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
 &lt;img
 loading="lazy"
 class="img-fluid rounded mx-auto d-block"
 width="300" src="https://strategineer.com/img/react/sad.gif"/>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But Le Guin&amp;rsquo;s Earthsea series is fantastic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
 &lt;img
 loading="lazy"
 class="img-fluid rounded mx-auto d-block"
 width="300" src="https://strategineer.com/img/react/pumped.gif"/>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Other Wind</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780547773728/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780547773728/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ursula K. Le Guin&amp;rsquo;s conclusion to her fantastic Earthsea series. Once again, she manages to create a fantasy world where violence doesn&amp;rsquo;t solve everything. Her characters engage in the mundane activities that real people do most of the time: chat, make friends, think about their loved ones, cuddle with their pets, etc. The way she writes these mundane scenes makes them feel just as important and interesting as they really are.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lonely Castle In The Mirror</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781645660408/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781645660408/</guid><description>&lt;p>Childhood trauma. Check.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Split timeline. Check.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Transported to another world. Check.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Children competing for a prize (to the death?). Check.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is Japan.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tales From Earthsea</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780547722047/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780547722047/</guid><description>&lt;p>A collection of short stories and novellas set in the Earthsea setting that Ursula wrote to help her find out how to continue the story when prompted to do so by her publisher.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s some great stories here but I prefer the Earthsea novels to this generally (don&amp;rsquo;t get me started on The Farthest Shore).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tehanu</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781473223592/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781473223592/</guid><description>&lt;p>A sequel to both The Tombs of Atuan and The Farthest Shore.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Considering how uninteresting The Farthest Shore is, I&amp;rsquo;m confident saying that you can skip that book and go straight to Tehanu.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Child Thief - A Novel</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780061671340/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780061671340/</guid><description>&lt;p>An edgy retelling of Peter Pan by Brom, the illustrator who&amp;rsquo;s work you&amp;rsquo;ve definitely seen before (Doom II, Diablo II).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nettle &amp; Bone</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781250244048/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781250244048/</guid><description>&lt;p>Feels like an Arthurian legend, a mix of fairy tales but grounded in a reality somewhat like our own with some fantastical twists layered into it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Short and sweet, deserving of all the praise it has received.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guards! Guards!</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780552134620/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780552134620/</guid><description>&lt;p>The first novel in Terry Pratchett&amp;rsquo;s City/Night Watch series featuring the drunk and depressed Captain Vimes, the human who thinks he&amp;rsquo;s a dwarf Carrot, the everyman Nobby and the boomer Sergeant Colon. They act like a tight knit four man improv group, bouncing off each other really well and provide a great foundation for the humor, action and hijinks in the novel.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Farthest Shore</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781442459922/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781442459922/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hasn&amp;rsquo;t aged as well as the first two books in the series IMO.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s kind of a retread of the first book with a little bit of the 80s crack epidemic and reganomics commentary spliced into it. It&amp;rsquo;s not as evergreen as the other books.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Raven Tower</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780316388696/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780316388696/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The Raven Tower&amp;rdquo; is one of the worst books I have ever read. I&amp;rsquo;ve only covered the tip of the iceberg in this review because reading through this book has left me completely drained of energy. Please don&amp;rsquo;t read this book, it is beyond trash. If you really want to, I can&amp;rsquo;t stop you but I really wish I could.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zachary Ying And The Dragon Emperor</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781665900706/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781665900706/</guid><description>&lt;p>Xiran Jay Zhao strikes again. I was blown away by her YA novel Iron Window a few months ago so when I saw her next novel Zachary Ying and the Dragon Emperor on sale, I snatched it up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once again, Xiran has interwoven ancient Chinese history and mythology seamlessly with an anime inspired aesthetic (Yugioh in this case whereas Iron Window was very Darling in the Franxx) serving it all through a genre appropriate lens.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gregor The Overlander</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781407172583/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781407172583/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s heartbreaking. I&amp;rsquo;m tearing up by page 4. This series is advertised as a story for kids but it&amp;rsquo;s written in such a way that it&amp;rsquo;s just as interesting reading through it as an adult. A younger reader wouldn&amp;rsquo;t catch all the subtext (and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of it).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Gathering Of Shadows</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780765376480/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780765376480/</guid><description>&lt;p>An absolute page turner if I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read one (I couldn&amp;rsquo;t put this book down). Each time I sat down to read, it only took a few sentences to transport me completely into this world that V.E. Schwab has so carefully built.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Gathering of Shadows develops the characters introduced in the previous book (along with some fresh faces), portrays the evolution of their relationships with one another and sets everything up for what I&amp;rsquo;m confident is going to be a riveting conclusion to the trilogy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Tombs Of Atuan</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781442459908/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781442459908/</guid><description>&lt;p>Le Guin mostly successful attempt to write a story in the world of a Wizard of Earthsea told from the perspective of a girl and, eventually, woman.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ged shows up and steals the show a little bit from Tenar which Le Guin will rectify in the subsequent novels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Wizard Of Earthsea</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780547722023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780547722023/</guid><description>&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s a, soon-to-be wizard, on a archipelago world. He goes to wizard school and becomes xXx#1_Mage_NAxXx.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A classic fantasy story elevated by Le Guin&amp;rsquo;s poetic use of words. Struggles to give women in the story the story they deserve, an issue dealt with in the subsequent novels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Witches Abroad</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780552134651/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780552134651/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Thud!</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780552152679/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780552152679/</guid><description>&lt;p>Thud! by Terry Pratchett tells the story of Sam Vimes, head of the Ankh-Morpork City Watch, and his fellow coppers trying to solve a dwarf&amp;rsquo;s murder. The upcoming anniversary of the thousands years old Battle of Koom Valley is keeping tension high between the dwarves and the trolls; making it harder for the constables of the Watch to keep the peace and solve the crime.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thud! is a Terry Pratchett novel through and through. There&amp;rsquo;s ample comedy interlaced with impactful action scenes with just a little bit of drama sprinkled in. This time around, it&amp;rsquo;s a little grittier and darker than usual.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Small Gods</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780552138901/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780552138901/</guid><description>&lt;p>Terry is dedicated to the bit. More than anything he is committed to creating absurd worlds that feel real. His work has aged beautifully because the world we live in is as absurd as it&amp;rsquo;s ever been and it&amp;rsquo;s only getting more absurd from here on out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Small Gods is about an autistic savant (pour a drink every time Terry Pratchett includes an autistic character in one of his Discworld books) named Brutha who is a lowly priest/monk in the church of Om. Hijinks ensue.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thief Of Time</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780552148405/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780552148405/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few different cooky POV characters doing their own thing, eventually meet up to save big T Time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second Terry Pratchett book I read, I preferred Going Postal but this one is no slouch.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Going Postal</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780552149433/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780552149433/</guid><description>&lt;p>Going Postal is my favorite Terry Pratchett novel. I&amp;rsquo;m facepalming right now for not writing my thoughts down about this book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Conjuring Of Light</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780765387462/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780765387462/</guid><description>&lt;p>It was an enjoyable romp but doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily hit the highs of the previous books in the series. As the third and final(ish) book in the series I was expecting something a little bit more. Or maybe I was expecting a little bit less, a more tightly edited and polished story. Either would have been nice.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Darker Shade Of Magic</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780765376466/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780765376466/</guid><description>&lt;p>I really loved it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was skeptical at first (I&amp;rsquo;ve been burned too many times by boring and tropey fantasy novels that so many people love) but V. E. Schwab reeled me in with some gritty and edgy fantasy that felt really &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; to me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was so immersed in the world that I was tearing up by the end of the book which doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen to me very often (one character&amp;rsquo;s arc really spoke to me)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Colour Of Magic</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781804990315/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781804990315/</guid><description>&lt;p>An incompetent wizard is tasked with protecting a visitor visiting from a faraway land. A fantasy novel for people who don&amp;rsquo;t like fantasy novels.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>