<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fantasy on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/tags/fantasy/</link><description>Recent content in fantasy on Strat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/books/tags/fantasy/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tales from Earthsea</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-31/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-31/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve read through the two first stories so far and I&amp;rsquo;m beginning to wonder why Ursula is so fascinated by mages retaining their semen. It&amp;rsquo;s a little wacky.</description></item><item><title>Tehanu</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-27/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-27/</guid><description>Way better than The Farthest Shore, which might be Ursula&amp;rsquo;s worst work I&amp;rsquo;ve read so far. It&amp;rsquo;s a sequel to both Tehanu and the Farthest Shore but I think you could probably skip The Farthest Shore and be OK with reading the rest of the series.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading the series alongside Ranged Touch Shelved by Genre podcast and it&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of fun!
I have an insatiable desire to read, write, think and talk about the books I&amp;rsquo;ve read so a book club-like podcast is a perfect fit for me.</description></item><item><title>The Child Thief</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-02-29/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-02-29/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sword &amp; Citadel: The Second Half of The Book of the New Sun</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-02-19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-02-19/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Shadow &amp; Claw: The First Half of The Book of the New Sun</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-02-11/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-02-11/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;What will you be, Severian? A torturer? You may leave the guild, you know, if you prefer.&amp;rdquo;
I told him firmly - and as though I were slightly shocked by the suggestion - that I had never considered it. It was a lie. I had known, as all the apprentices knew, that one was not firmly and finally a member of the guild until one consented as an adult to the connection.</description></item><item><title>Nettle &amp; Bone</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-14/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-14/</guid><description>Feels like an Arthurian legend, a mix of fairy tales but grounded in a reality somewhat like our own with some fantastical twists layered into it.
Christ is implied to have existed in this universe so that&amp;rsquo;s a little confusing. Where and when are we then? But it feels like an alternate fantastical reality.
Inverting tropes: instead of a prince saving a princess, the princess wants to kill the prince and save her sister.</description></item><item><title>Guards! Guards!</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-13/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s a Terry Pratchett novel so that implies that it&amp;rsquo;s pretty good. I liked this one quite a bit. After reading Thud! and enjoying that, I decided to start reading the entire Discworld City/Night Watch series. Captain Vimes, Carrot, Sergeant Colon and Nobby are great characters.
Sam Vimes suffers from a combination of alcoholism and depression leading to his skewed perspective of the world.
Lessee . . . he’d gone off after the funeral and got drunk.</description></item><item><title>The Farthest Shore</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-21/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-21/</guid><description>Hasn&amp;rsquo;t aged as well as the first two books in the series IMO.
It&amp;rsquo;s kind of a retread of the first book with a little bit of the 80s crack epidemic and reganomics commentary spliced into it. It&amp;rsquo;s not as evergreen as the other books.</description></item><item><title>The Raven Tower</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-25/</guid><description>NB: &amp;ldquo;The Raven Tower&amp;rdquo; is one of the worst books I have ever read. I&amp;rsquo;ve only covered the tip of the iceberg in this review because reading through this book has left me completely drained of energy. Please don&amp;rsquo;t read this book, it is beyond trash. If you really want to, I can&amp;rsquo;t stop you but I really wish I could.
I have an important question for y&amp;rsquo;all.
Is this how people speak?</description></item><item><title>Zachary Ying and the Dragon Emperor</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-24/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-24/</guid><description>Xiran Jay Zhao strikes again. I was blown away by her YA novel Iron Window a few months ago so when I saw her next novel Zachary Ying and the Dragon Emperor on sale, I snatched it up.
Once again, Xiran has interwoven ancient Chinese history and mythology seamlessly with an anime inspired aesthetic (Yugioh in this case whereas Iron Window was very Darling in the Franxx) serving it all through a genre appropriate lens.</description></item><item><title>Gregor The Overlander</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-21/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-21/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s heartbreaking. I&amp;rsquo;m tearing up by page four. This series is advertised as a story for kids but it&amp;rsquo;s written in such a way that it&amp;rsquo;s just as interesting reading through it as an adult. A younger reader wouldn&amp;rsquo;t catch all the subtext (and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of it) consciously.
As the oldest kid (11 years old) in his family, Gregor is tasked with taking care of his 2 year old baby sister over the summer while his single mother (Gregor&amp;rsquo;s father &amp;ldquo;disappeared&amp;rdquo; one night) works to put food on the table.</description></item><item><title>A Gathering of Shadows</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-18/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-18/</guid><description>An absolute page turner if I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read one (I couldn&amp;rsquo;t put this book down). Each time I sat down to read, it only took a few sentences to transport me completely into this world that V.E. Schwab has so carefully built.
A Gathering of Shadows develops the characters introduced in the previous book (along with some fresh faces), portrays the evolution of their relationships with one another and sets everything up for what I&amp;rsquo;m confident is going to be a riveting conclusion to the trilogy.</description></item><item><title>Tombs of Atuan</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-02/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Wizard of Earthsea</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-30/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-30/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Obelisk Gate</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-29/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-29/</guid><description>spoiler alert This novel suffers from middle book syndrome. It continues the story set up in the first book and, hopefully, sets up the third and final book.
Unlike The Fifth Season, this novel fails to coalesce the different POVs into a cohesive whole which was one of the best aspects of the first book.
The Obelisk Gate feels like two different stories that were spliced into each other and suffers for it.</description></item><item><title>Thud!</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-12/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-12/</guid><description>It would be a lot simpler [&amp;hellip;] if this was a story. A sword is pulled out of a stone or a magic ring is flung into the depths of the sea, and with general rejoicing the world turns.
But this was real life. The world didn&amp;rsquo;t turn, it just went into a spin.
Thud! by Terry Pratchett tells the story of Sam Vimes, head of the Ankh-Morpork City Watch, and his fellow coppers trying to solve a dwarf&amp;rsquo;s murder.</description></item><item><title>Small Gods</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-03/</guid><description>Terry is dedicated to the bit. More than anything he is committed to creating absurd worlds that feel real. His work has aged beautifully because the world we live in is as absurd as it&amp;rsquo;s ever been and it&amp;rsquo;s only getting more absurd from here on out.
Small Gods is about an autistic savant (pour a drink every time Terry Pratchett includes an autistic character in one of his Discworld books) named Brutha who is a lowly priest/monk in the church of Om.</description></item><item><title>A Conjuring of Light</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-18/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-18/</guid><description>spoiler alert It was an enjoyable romp but doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily hit the highs of the previous books in the series. As the third and final(ish) book in the series I was expecting something a little bit more. Or maybe I was expecting a little bit less, a more tightly edited and polished story. Either would have been nice.
Here&amp;rsquo;s some thoughts:
It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to tell a story about an antagonistic character who is basically a god.</description></item><item><title>A Darker Shade of Magic</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-12/</guid><description>I really loved it&amp;hellip;
I was skeptical at first (I&amp;rsquo;ve been burned too many times by boring and tropey fantasy novels that so many people love) but V. E. Schwab reeled me in with some gritty and edgy fantasy that felt really &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; to me.
I was so immersed in the world that I was tearing up by the end of the book which doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen to me very often (one character&amp;rsquo;s arc really spoke to me)</description></item><item><title>The Colour of Magic</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-28/</guid><description>An incompetent wizard is tasked with protecting a visitor visiting from a faraway land. A fantasy novel for people who don&amp;rsquo;t like fantasy novels.</description></item></channel></rss>