<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fantasy on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/tags/fantasy/</link><description>Recent content in Fantasy on Strat</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 13:43:48 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/books/tags/fantasy/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tales from Earthsea</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-06/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-04-06/</guid><description>&lt;p>A collection of short stories and novellas set in the Earthsea setting that Ursula wrote to help her find out how to continue the story when prompted to do so by her publisher.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s some great stories here but I prefer the Earthsea novels to this generally (don&amp;rsquo;t get me started on The Farthest Shore).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tehanu</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-27/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-03-27/</guid><description>Way better than The Farthest Shore, which might be Ursula&amp;rsquo;s worst work I&amp;rsquo;ve read so far. It&amp;rsquo;s a sequel to both Tehanu and the Farthest Shore but I think you could probably skip The Farthest Shore and be OK with reading the rest of the series.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading the series alongside Ranged Touch Shelved by Genre podcast and it&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of fun!
I have an insatiable desire to read, write, think and talk about the books I&amp;rsquo;ve read so a book club-like podcast is a perfect fit for me.</description></item><item><title>The Child Thief</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-02-29/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2024-02-29/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Nettle &amp; Bone</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-14/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-14/</guid><description>Feels like an Arthurian legend, a mix of fairy tales but grounded in a reality somewhat like our own with some fantastical twists layered into it.
Christ is implied to have existed in this universe so that&amp;rsquo;s a little confusing. Where and when are we then? But it feels like an alternate fantastical reality.
Inverting tropes: instead of a prince saving a princess, the princess wants to kill the prince and save her sister.</description></item><item><title>Guards! Guards!</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-11-13/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s a Terry Pratchett novel so that implies that it&amp;rsquo;s pretty good. I liked this one quite a bit. After reading Thud! and enjoying that, I decided to start reading the entire Discworld City/Night Watch series. Captain Vimes, Carrot, Sergeant Colon and Nobby are great characters.
Sam Vimes suffers from a combination of alcoholism and depression leading to his skewed perspective of the world.
Lessee . . . he’d gone off after the funeral and got drunk.</description></item><item><title>The Farthest Shore</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-21/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-10-21/</guid><description>Hasn&amp;rsquo;t aged as well as the first two books in the series IMO.
It&amp;rsquo;s kind of a retread of the first book with a little bit of the 80s crack epidemic and reganomics commentary spliced into it. It&amp;rsquo;s not as evergreen as the other books.</description></item><item><title>The Raven Tower</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-25/</guid><description>NB: &amp;ldquo;The Raven Tower&amp;rdquo; is one of the worst books I have ever read. I&amp;rsquo;ve only covered the tip of the iceberg in this review because reading through this book has left me completely drained of energy. Please don&amp;rsquo;t read this book, it is beyond trash. If you really want to, I can&amp;rsquo;t stop you but I really wish I could.
I have an important question for y&amp;rsquo;all.
Is this how people speak?</description></item><item><title>Zachary Ying and the Dragon Emperor</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-24/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-24/</guid><description>Xiran Jay Zhao strikes again. I was blown away by her YA novel Iron Window a few months ago so when I saw her next novel Zachary Ying and the Dragon Emperor on sale, I snatched it up.
Once again, Xiran has interwoven ancient Chinese history and mythology seamlessly with an anime inspired aesthetic (Yugioh in this case whereas Iron Window was very Darling in the Franxx) serving it all through a genre appropriate lens.</description></item><item><title>Gregor The Overlander</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-21/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-09-21/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s heartbreaking. I&amp;rsquo;m tearing up by page four. This series is advertised as a story for kids but it&amp;rsquo;s written in such a way that it&amp;rsquo;s just as interesting reading through it as an adult. A younger reader wouldn&amp;rsquo;t catch all the subtext (and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of it) consciously.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the oldest kid (11 years old) in his family, Gregor is tasked with taking care of his 2 year old baby sister over the summer while his single mother (Gregor&amp;rsquo;s father &amp;ldquo;disappeared&amp;rdquo; one night) works to put food on the table.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>His grandmother lives with them and has Dementia (although Gregor doesn&amp;rsquo;t know that&amp;rsquo;s what it is).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>For the last year his grandma had been slipping in and out of reality. One minute she was clear as a bell and the next she was calling him Simon. Who was Simon? He had no idea.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gregor doesn&amp;rsquo;t speak like a child, in a lot of ways he&amp;rsquo;s a grown ass man in a boy&amp;rsquo;s body. Children don&amp;rsquo;t speak like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;Great, Day One and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to a trip to the laundry room,&amp;rdquo; Gregor thought. &amp;ldquo;By September, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably be ecstatic when we get the phone bill.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is fine because:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>It makes it easier for me to step into Gregor&amp;rsquo;s shoes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It makes him more interesting.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Trauma forces you to grow up quicker than normal.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Gregor is old at heart and he&amp;rsquo;s been through some shit. He&amp;rsquo;s depressed as hell because he misses his dad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Gregor tried to remember the last time he&amp;rsquo;d felt as happy as Boots did with her ball. He had had some decent times over the past couple of years. [&amp;hellip;] But if he was honest with himself, Gregor knew it had been years since he&amp;rsquo;d felt real happiness.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>THIS IS A BOOK FOR CHILDREN, PLEASE SEND HELP!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not only has Gregor been through &amp;ldquo;some&amp;rdquo; shit, he&amp;rsquo;s about to go through &amp;ldquo;the&amp;rdquo; shit because each book involves Gregor going on a military/diplomatic mission in a world at war, or about to be at war.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Gathering of Shadows</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-18/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-18/</guid><description>An absolute page turner if I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read one (I couldn&amp;rsquo;t put this book down). Each time I sat down to read, it only took a few sentences to transport me completely into this world that V.E. Schwab has so carefully built.
A Gathering of Shadows develops the characters introduced in the previous book (along with some fresh faces), portrays the evolution of their relationships with one another and sets everything up for what I&amp;rsquo;m confident is going to be a riveting conclusion to the trilogy.</description></item><item><title>Tombs of Atuan</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-02/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-08-02/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Wizard of Earthsea</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-30/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-30/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Witches Abroad</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-20/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-20/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Thud!</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-12/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-12/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>It would be a lot simpler [&amp;hellip;] if this was a story. A sword is pulled out of a stone or a magic ring is flung into the depths of the sea, and with general rejoicing the world turns.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>But this was real life. The world didn&amp;rsquo;t turn, it just went into a spin.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thud! by Terry Pratchett tells the story of Sam Vimes, head of the Ankh-Morpork City Watch, and his fellow coppers trying to solve a dwarf&amp;rsquo;s murder. The upcoming anniversary of the thousands years old Battle of Koom Valley is keeping tension high between the dwarves and the trolls; making it harder for the constables of the Watch to keep the peace and solve the crime.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thud! is a Terry Pratchett novel through and through. There&amp;rsquo;s ample comedy interlaced with impactful action scenes with just a little bit of drama sprinkled in. This time around, it&amp;rsquo;s a little grittier and darker than usual.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thud! is about prejudice. The main plot as well as every sub plot has something to say about prejudice, how it can cloud our judgement and prevent us from doing the right thing and treating everyone with the respect they deserve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The choice to have the protagonist be a prototypical white man in a position of power is great because I would have had a hard time taking the novel seriously if Terry Pratchett, a very white man, had chosen to tell this story from the perspective of a minority.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sam Vimes is an honest man doing the best he can but sometimes that&amp;rsquo;s just not good enough. So, for me, throughout the novel, he flip-flopped between being the hero I was rooting for and the antihero I loved to hate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Small Gods</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-07-03/</guid><description>Terry is dedicated to the bit. More than anything he is committed to creating absurd worlds that feel real. His work has aged beautifully because the world we live in is as absurd as it&amp;rsquo;s ever been and it&amp;rsquo;s only getting more absurd from here on out.
Small Gods is about an autistic savant (pour a drink every time Terry Pratchett includes an autistic character in one of his Discworld books) named Brutha who is a lowly priest/monk in the church of Om.</description></item><item><title>Thief of Time</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-24/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-24/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Going Postal</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-23/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-23/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Conjuring of Light</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-18/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-18/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>spoiler alert&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Darker Shade of Magic</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2023-06-12/</guid><description>I really loved it&amp;hellip;
I was skeptical at first (I&amp;rsquo;ve been burned too many times by boring and tropey fantasy novels that so many people love) but V. E. Schwab reeled me in with some gritty and edgy fantasy that felt really &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; to me.
I was so immersed in the world that I was tearing up by the end of the book which doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen to me very often (one character&amp;rsquo;s arc really spoke to me)</description></item><item><title>The Colour of Magic</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/2022-11-28/</guid><description>An incompetent wizard is tasked with protecting a visitor visiting from a faraway land. A fantasy novel for people who don&amp;rsquo;t like fantasy novels.</description></item></channel></rss>