<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Currently-Reading on Strat</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/tags/currently-reading/</link><description>Recent content in Currently-Reading on Strat</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:04:10 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://strategineer.com/books/tags/currently-reading/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Astro City</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781401232627/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781401232627/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Calvin And Hobbes</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780836220889/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780836220889/</guid><description>&lt;p>Calvin is a kid and Hobbes is his imaginary tiger buddy. They get up to hijinks together, usually while torturing Calvin&amp;rsquo;s parents intentionally or not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The jokes still land decades later but given that this comic strip appeared piece meal in your daily newspaper, they&amp;rsquo;re not meant to be read all in a row.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Doom Patrol</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781401263126/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781401263126/</guid><description>&lt;p>Grant Morrison&amp;rsquo;s run of Doom Patrol focuses on the misfits, the weird and the broken and how they are fit to fight evils that other more conventional and sane heroes aren&amp;rsquo;t equipped to deal with.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Robotman has a fully mechanical body with his very human brain controlling new body. He can&amp;rsquo;t feel anything. What makes a human a human if not for their ability to sense the world around them?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Crazy Jane is a woman with 64 different personalities, so far at least, each possessing a different power. She&amp;rsquo;s unpredictable but it seems like her powers will come in handy time and time again. Who exactly is Crazy Jane? Who are they and what makes they, her?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rebis is formed from the fusion of a man and a woman with the mind and bodies of both becoming one. Their memories are the memories of the two who became one but altered and corrupted in the process. When we change how does that effect us and does that effect others around us?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Incal</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781643377803/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781643377803/</guid><description>&lt;p>Drawn by French artist Moebius and written by Jodorowsky himself, every page of the Incal is an opportunity for the pair to blow you away with the prettiest art you&amp;rsquo;ll ever see and a humongous story told at a pace that&amp;rsquo;s unbelievably fast considering its scope.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Metabarons</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781594651069/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781594651069/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Fables</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9781563899423/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9781563899423/</guid><description>&lt;p>Comic book with characters from fairy tales like the Big Bad Wolf, Snow White and Prince Charming who&amp;rsquo;ve been expulsed from their lands straight into modern day New York by an evil force, called the Adversary, where they have to survive and hide their unique fairy taleness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This comic book was first published in 2002 by a Pro-Israel author. Fables is explicitly an allegory for the Isreal-Palestenian conflict. So I&amp;rsquo;m expecting more than a little yikes with a dash of Islamophobia in this comic book so let&amp;rsquo;s see how far we get.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Word For World Is Forest</title><link>https://strategineer.com/books/9780765324641/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://strategineer.com/books/9780765324641/</guid><description>&lt;p>Seems like Ursula K. Le Guin is subverting the old school military science fiction trope of humans going around killing &amp;ldquo;aliens&amp;rdquo; with the humans doing the killing framed as the good guys who we&amp;rsquo;re supposed to be rooting for. Maybe colonialism is bad?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s see how this goes.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>